{
	"description": "Kanji readings for JLPT N1-5",
	"deck": [
	{"question":"お互い","answers":["おたがい"],"comment":"(n) mutual/reciprocal/each other"},
	{"question":"お代わり","answers":["おかわり"],"comment":"(n) second helping/another cup"},
	{"question":"お使い","answers":["おつかい"],"comment":"errand"},
	{"question":"お供","answers":["おとも"],"comment":"(n,vs) attendant/companion"},
	{"question":"お兄さん","answers":["おにいさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) older brother/(vocative) 'Mister?'"},
	{"question":"お参り","answers":["おまいり"],"comment":"(n,vs) worship/shrine visit"},
	{"question":"お土産","answers":["おみやげ"],"comment":"(n) present/souvenir"},
	{"question":"お姉さん","answers":["おねえさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) older sister/(vocative) 'Miss?'"},
	{"question":"お嬢さん","answers":["おじょうさん"],"comment":"(n) (1) (hon) daughter/(2) young lady"},
	{"question":"お子さん","answers":["おこさん"],"comment":"(n) (someone else's) child"},
	{"question":"お宅","answers":["おたく"],"comment":"(n) (pol) your house/your home/you"},
	{"question":"お宮","answers":["おみや"],"comment":"(n) Shinto shrine"},
	{"question":"お弁当","answers":["おべんとう"],"comment":"(n) boxed lunch"},
	{"question":"お手上げ","answers":["おてあげ"],"comment":"(n) all over/given in/given up hope/bring to knees"},
	{"question":"お手伝いさん","answers":["おてつだいさん"],"comment":"(n) maid"},
	{"question":"お手洗い","answers":["おてあらい"],"comment":"toilet/restroom/lavatory/bathroom (US)"},
	{"question":"お昼","answers":["おひる"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) lunch/noon"},
	{"question":"お母さん","answers":["おかあさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) mother"},
	{"question":"お父さん","answers":["おとうさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) father"},
	{"question":"お産","answers":["おさん"],"comment":"(n) (giving) birth"},
	{"question":"お皿","answers":["おさら"],"comment":"(n) plate/dish"},
	{"question":"お礼","answers":["おれい"],"comment":"(n) thanking/expression of gratitude"},
	{"question":"お祝い","answers":["おいわい"],"comment":"(n) congratulation/celebration"},
	{"question":"お茶","answers":["おちゃ"],"comment":"(n) tea (green)"},
	{"question":"お菓子","answers":["おかし"],"comment":"(n) confections/sweets/candy"},
	{"question":"お見舞い","answers":["おみまい"],"comment":"(n) calling on someone who is ill/enquiry"},
	{"question":"お酒","answers":["おさけ"],"comment":"(n) alcohol/sake (rice wine)"},
	{"question":"お金","answers":["おかね"],"comment":"(n) money"},
	{"question":"ご存じ","answers":["ごぞんじ"],"comment":"(n) knowing/acquaintance"},
	{"question":"ジェット機","answers":["ジェットき"],"comment":"(n) jet aeroplane"},
	{"question":"一","answers":["いち"],"comment":"(num) one"},
	{"question":"一つ","answers":["ひとつ"],"comment":"(n) one"},
	{"question":"一人","answers":["ひとり"],"comment":"(n) one person"},
	{"question":"一人一人","answers":["ひとりひとり"],"comment":"(n-t) one by one/each/one at a time"},
	{"question":"一休み","answers":["ひとやすみ"],"comment":"(n) a rest"},
	{"question":"一体","answers":["いったい"],"comment":"(adv,n) (1) one object/one body/(2) what on earth?/really?/(3) generally"},
	{"question":"一切","answers":["いっさい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) all/everything/without exception/the whole/entirely/absolutely"},
	{"question":"一別","answers":["いちべつ"],"comment":"(n) parting"},
	{"question":"一同","answers":["いちどう"],"comment":"(n) all present/all concerned/all of us"},
	{"question":"一変","answers":["いっぺん"],"comment":"(n,vs) complete change/about-face"},
	{"question":"一定","answers":["いってい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) fixed/settled/definite/uniform/regularized/defined/standardized/certain/prescribed"},
	{"question":"一家","answers":["いっか"],"comment":"(n) a house/a home/a family/a household/one's family/one's folks/a style"},
	{"question":"一層","answers":["いっそう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) much more/still more/all the more"},
	{"question":"一帯","answers":["いったい"],"comment":"(n) a region/a zone/the whole place"},
	{"question":"一度","answers":["いちど"],"comment":"(n-adv) once/one time/on one occasion"},
	{"question":"一度に","answers":["いちどに"],"comment":"(adv) all at once"},
	{"question":"一律","answers":["いちりつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n) evenness/uniformity/monotony/equality"},
	{"question":"一心","answers":["いっしん"],"comment":"(adv,n) one mind/wholeheartedness/the whole heart"},
	{"question":"一応","answers":["いちおう"],"comment":"(adv) once/tentatively/in outline/for the time being"},
	{"question":"一息","answers":["ひといき"],"comment":"(n) puffy/a breath/a pause/an effort"},
	{"question":"一括","answers":["いっかつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) all together/batch/one lump/one bundle/summing up"},
	{"question":"一挙に","answers":["いっきょに"],"comment":"(adv) at a stroke/with a single swoop"},
	{"question":"一斉","answers":["いっせい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) simultaneous/all at once"},
	{"question":"一方","answers":["いっぽう"],"comment":"(conj,n-adv,n) (1) on the other hand/one side/one way/one direction/one party/the other party/(2) meanwhile/(3) only/simple/in turn"},
	{"question":"一日","answers":["いちにち","ついたち"],"comment":"(n) (1) first of month"},
	{"question":"一旦","answers":["いったん"],"comment":"(adv) once/for a moment/one morning/temporarily"},
	{"question":"一昨年","answers":["いっさくねん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) year before last"},
	{"question":"一昨日","answers":["いっさくじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) day before yesterday"},
	{"question":"一時","answers":["いちじ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) moment/time"},
	{"question":"一月","answers":["ひとつき"],"comment":"one month"},
	{"question":"一概に","answers":["いちがいに"],"comment":"(adv) unconditionally/as a rule"},
	{"question":"一様","answers":["いちよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) uniformity/evenness/similarity/equality/impartiality"},
	{"question":"一段と","answers":["いちだんと"],"comment":"(adv) greater/more/further/still more"},
	{"question":"一気","answers":["いっき"],"comment":"(n) (abbr) drink!(said repeatedly as a party cheer)"},
	{"question":"一流","answers":["いちりゅう"],"comment":"(n) first class/top grade/school (of art)/foremost/top-notch/unique"},
	{"question":"一生","answers":["いっしょう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) whole life/a lifetime/all through life/one existence/a generation/an age/the whole world/the era"},
	{"question":"一生懸命","answers":["いっしょうけんめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n) very hard/with utmost effort/with all one's might"},
	{"question":"一目","answers":["いちもく"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) a glance/a look/a glimpse"},
	{"question":"一瞬","answers":["いっしゅん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) a moment/an instant"},
	{"question":"一種","answers":["いっしゅ"],"comment":"(adv,n) a species/a kind/a variety"},
	{"question":"一筋","answers":["ひとすじ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) a line/earnestly/blindly/straightforwardly"},
	{"question":"一緒","answers":["いっしょ"],"comment":"(adv,n) together/meeting/company"},
	{"question":"一致","answers":["いっち"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) coincidence/agreement/union/match/(2) conformity/consistency/(3) co-operation"},
	{"question":"一般","answers":["いっぱん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) general/liberal/universal/ordinary/average"},
	{"question":"一見","answers":["いっけん"],"comment":"(adv,n,vs) (1) a look/a glimpse/glance/(2) first meeting"},
	{"question":"一言","answers":["ひとこと"],"comment":"(n) single word"},
	{"question":"一通り","answers":["ひととおり"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) ordinary/usual/in general/briefly"},
	{"question":"一連","answers":["いちれん"],"comment":"(n) a series/a chain/a ream (of paper)"},
	{"question":"一部分","answers":["いちぶぶん"],"comment":"(n) a part/a portion/a section"},
	{"question":"一面","answers":["いちめん"],"comment":"(adv,n) one side/one phase/front page/the other hand/the whole surface"},
	{"question":"一頃","answers":["ひところ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) once/some time ago"},
	{"question":"丁寧","answers":["ていねい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) polite/courteous/careful/care/kind/close/thorough/conscientious"},
	{"question":"七","answers":["しち","なな"],"comment":"(num) seven"},
	{"question":"七つ","answers":["ななつ"],"comment":"(n) seven"},
	{"question":"七日","answers":["なのか"],"comment":"(n-adv) seven days/the seventh day (of the month)"},
	{"question":"万","answers":["まん"],"comment":"(adv,num) 10,000/ten thousand/myriads/all/everything"},
	{"question":"万一","answers":["まんいち"],"comment":"(adv,n) by some chance/by some possibility/if by any chance/10E4:1 odds"},
	{"question":"万人","answers":["ばんにん"],"comment":"(n) all people/everybody/10000 people"},
	{"question":"万年筆","answers":["まんねんひつ"],"comment":"(n) fountain pen"},
	{"question":"万歳","answers":["ばんざい"],"comment":"strolling comic dancer"},
	{"question":"万能","answers":["ばんのう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) all-purpose/almighty/omnipotent"},
	{"question":"丈","answers":["たけ"],"comment":"(prt) (uk) only/just/as"},
	{"question":"丈夫","answers":["じょうぶ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) hero/gentleman/warrior/manly person/(2) good health/robustness/strong/solid/durable"},
	{"question":"三","answers":["さん"],"comment":"(num) three"},
	{"question":"三つ","answers":["みっつ"],"comment":"(n) three"},
	{"question":"三味線","answers":["しゃみせん"],"comment":"(n) three-stringed Japanese guitar/shamisen"},
	{"question":"三日","answers":["みっか"],"comment":"(n) three days/the third day (of the month)"},
	{"question":"三日月","answers":["みかづき"],"comment":"(n) new moon/crescent moon"},
	{"question":"三角","answers":["さんかく"],"comment":"(n) triangle/triangular"},
	{"question":"上","answers":["うえ","うわ","かみ","じょう"],"comment":"(n,pref,suf) (1) first volume/(2) superior quality/(3) governmental/imperial/top/best/high class/going up/presenting/showing/aboard a ship or vehicle/from the standpoint of/as a matter of (fact)"},
	{"question":"上がり","answers":["あがり"],"comment":"(n,suf) (1) ascent/rise/slope/(2) freshly-drawn green tea (esp. in sushi shops)/(3) advance income/crop yield/(4) death/spinning/completion/stop/finish/(5) after (rain)/ex (official, etc.)"},
	{"question":"上げる","answers":["あげる"],"comment":"(v1) to give/to raise/to elevate/to fly (kites)/to praise/to increase/to advance/to promote/to vomit/to usher in/to admit/to send (to school)/to offer/to present/to leave with/to finish/to arrange (expenses)/to observe/to perform/to quote/to mention/to bear (a child)/to improve (talents)/to do up (the hair)/to arrest/to engage/to fry/(rains) to stop"},
	{"question":"上り","answers":["のぼり"],"comment":"(n) up-train (going to Tokyo)/ascent"},
	{"question":"上る","answers":["あがる","のぼる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rise/to ascend/to be promoted/to go up/to climb/to go to (the capital)/to add up to/to advance (in price)/to sail up/to come up (on the agenda)"},
	{"question":"上下","answers":["じょうげ"],"comment":"(n,vs) high and low/up and down/unloading and loading/praising and blaming"},
	{"question":"上京","answers":["じょうきょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) proceeding to the capital (Tokyo)"},
	{"question":"上位","answers":["じょうい"],"comment":"(n) superior (rank not class)/higher order (e.g. byte)/host computer (of connected device)"},
	{"question":"上司","answers":["じょうし"],"comment":"(n) superior authorities/boss"},
	{"question":"上品","answers":["じょうひん"],"comment":"(n) Buddhism's highest paradise"},
	{"question":"上回る","answers":["うわまわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to exceed"},
	{"question":"上手","answers":["じょうず"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) skill/skillful/dexterity"},
	{"question":"上旬","answers":["じょうじゅん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) first 10 days of month"},
	{"question":"上昇","answers":["じょうしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) rising/ascending/climbing"},
	{"question":"上演","answers":["じょうえん"],"comment":"(n,vs) performance (e.g. music)"},
	{"question":"上着","answers":["うわぎ"],"comment":"(n) coat/tunic/jacket/outer garment"},
	{"question":"上空","answers":["じょうくう"],"comment":"(n) sky/the skies/high-altitude sky/upper air"},
	{"question":"上等","answers":["じょうとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) superiority/first class/very good"},
	{"question":"上級","answers":["じょうきゅう"],"comment":"(n) advanced level/high grade/senior"},
	{"question":"上達","answers":["じょうたつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) improvement/advance/progress"},
	{"question":"上陸","answers":["じょうりく"],"comment":"(n,vs) landing/disembarkation"},
	{"question":"下","answers":["げ","した","しも"],"comment":"(n) under/below/beneath"},
	{"question":"下げる","answers":["さげる"],"comment":"(v1) to hang/to lower/to move back/to wear/to dismiss/to grant"},
	{"question":"下さる","answers":["くださる"],"comment":"(v5aru) (hon) to give/to confer"},
	{"question":"下す","answers":["おろす"],"comment":"(v5s) to lower/to let go down"},
	{"question":"下り","answers":["くだり"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) down-train (going away from Tokyo)"},
	{"question":"下りる","answers":["おりる"],"comment":"(v1) to alight (e.g. from bus)/to get off/to descend (e.g. a mountain)"},
	{"question":"下る","answers":["くだる","さがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to get down/to descend"},
	{"question":"下取り","answers":["したどり"],"comment":"(n) trade in/part exchange"},
	{"question":"下品","answers":["げひん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) vulgarity/meanness/indecency/coarseness"},
	{"question":"下地","answers":["したじ"],"comment":"(n) groundwork/foundation/inclination/aptitude/elementary knowledge of/grounding in/prearrangement/spadework/signs/symptoms/first coat of plastering/soy"},
	{"question":"下宿","answers":["げしゅく"],"comment":"(n,vs) boarding/lodging/boarding house"},
	{"question":"下心","answers":["したごころ"],"comment":"(n) secret intention/motive"},
	{"question":"下手","answers":["へた"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unskillful/poor/awkward"},
	{"question":"下旬","answers":["げじゅん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) month (last third of)"},
	{"question":"下書き","answers":["したがき"],"comment":"(n) rough copy/draft"},
	{"question":"下水","answers":["げすい"],"comment":"(n) drainage/sewage/ditch/gutter/sewerage"},
	{"question":"下火","answers":["したび"],"comment":"(n) burning low/waning/declining"},
	{"question":"下町","answers":["したまち"],"comment":"(n) Shitamachi/lower parts of town"},
	{"question":"下痢","answers":["げり"],"comment":"(n) diarrhoea"},
	{"question":"下着","answers":["したぎ"],"comment":"(n) underwear"},
	{"question":"下線","answers":["かせん"],"comment":"(n) underline/underscore"},
	{"question":"下調べ","answers":["したしらべ"],"comment":"(n) preliminary investigation/preparation"},
	{"question":"下車","answers":["げしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) alighting/getting off"},
	{"question":"下降","answers":["かこう"],"comment":"(n) downward/descent/fall/drop/subsidence"},
	{"question":"下駄","answers":["げた"],"comment":"(n) geta (Japanese footwear)/wooden clogs"},
	{"question":"不","answers":["ふ","ぶ"],"comment":"un/non/negative prefix"},
	{"question":"不便","answers":["ふべん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) inconvenience/inexpediency/unhandiness"},
	{"question":"不利","answers":["ふり"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) disadvantage/handicap/unfavorable/drawback"},
	{"question":"不動産","answers":["ふどうさん"],"comment":"(n) real estate"},
	{"question":"不可","answers":["ふか"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) wrong/bad/improper/unjustifiable/inadvisable"},
	{"question":"不可欠","answers":["ふかけつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) indispensable/essential"},
	{"question":"不吉","answers":["ふきつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) ominous/sinister/bad luck/ill omen/inauspiciousness"},
	{"question":"不在","answers":["ふざい"],"comment":"(n) absence"},
	{"question":"不安","answers":["ふあん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) anxiety/uneasiness/insecurity/suspense"},
	{"question":"不審","answers":["ふしん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) incomplete understanding/doubt/question/distrust/suspicion/strangeness/infidelity"},
	{"question":"不平","answers":["ふへい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) complaint/discontent/dissatisfaction"},
	{"question":"不幸","answers":["ふこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unhappiness/sorrow/misfortune/disaster/accident/death"},
	{"question":"不当","answers":["ふとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) injustice/impropriety/unreasonableness/undeservedness/unfair/invalid"},
	{"question":"不思議","answers":["ふしぎ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) wonder/miracle/strange/mystery/marvel/curiosity"},
	{"question":"不意","answers":["ふい"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) sudden/abrupt/unexpected/unforeseen"},
	{"question":"不振","answers":["ふしん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dullness/depression/slump/stagnation"},
	{"question":"不明","answers":["ふめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unknown/obscure/indistinct/uncertain/ambiguous/ignorant/lack of wisdom/anonymous/unidentified"},
	{"question":"不景気","answers":["ふけいき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) business recession/hard times/depression/gloom/sullenness/cheerlessness"},
	{"question":"不服","answers":["ふふく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dissatisfaction/discontent/disapproval/objection/complaint/protest/disagreement"},
	{"question":"不正","answers":["ふせい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) injustice/unfairness/iniquity/impropriety/irregularity/dishonesty/illegality"},
	{"question":"不況","answers":["ふきょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) recession/depression/slump"},
	{"question":"不満","answers":["ふまん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dissatisfaction/displeasure/discontent/complaints/unhappiness"},
	{"question":"不潔","answers":["ふけつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unclean/dirty/filthy/impure"},
	{"question":"不自由","answers":["ふじゆう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) discomfort/disability/inconvenience/destitution"},
	{"question":"不良","answers":["ふりょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) badness/delinquent/inferiority/failure"},
	{"question":"不規則","answers":["ふきそく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) irregularity/unsteadiness/disorderly"},
	{"question":"不評","answers":["ふひょう"],"comment":"(n) bad reputation/disgrace/unpopularity"},
	{"question":"不調","answers":["ふちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) bad condition/not to work out (ie a deal)/disagreement/break-off/disorder/slump/out of form"},
	{"question":"不足","answers":["ふそく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) insufficiency/shortage/deficiency/lack/dearth"},
	{"question":"不通","answers":["ふつう"],"comment":"(n) suspension/interruption/stoppage/tie-up/cessation"},
	{"question":"不運","answers":["ふうん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unlucky/misfortune/bad luck/fate"},
	{"question":"不順","answers":["ふじゅん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) irregularity/unseasonableness"},
	{"question":"与える","answers":["あたえる"],"comment":"(v1) to give/to present/to award"},
	{"question":"与党","answers":["よとう"],"comment":"(n) government party/(ruling) party in power/government"},
	{"question":"且つ","answers":["かつ"],"comment":"(adv,conj) yet/and"},
	{"question":"世","answers":["よ"],"comment":"(n) world/society/age/generation"},
	{"question":"世の中","answers":["よのなか"],"comment":"(n) society/the world/the times"},
	{"question":"世代","answers":["せだい"],"comment":"(n) generation/the world/the age"},
	{"question":"世帯","answers":["せたい"],"comment":"(n) household"},
	{"question":"世界","answers":["せかい"],"comment":"(n) the world/society/the universe"},
	{"question":"世紀","answers":["せいき"],"comment":"(n) century/era"},
	{"question":"世話","answers":["せわ"],"comment":"(n,vs) looking after/help/aid/assistance"},
	{"question":"世論","answers":["せろん","よろん"],"comment":"(n) public opinion"},
	{"question":"世辞","answers":["せじ"],"comment":"(n) flattery/compliment"},
	{"question":"世間","answers":["せけん"],"comment":"(n) world/society"},
	{"question":"丘","answers":["おか"],"comment":"(n) hill/height/knoll/rising ground"},
	{"question":"丘陵","answers":["きゅうりょう"],"comment":"(n) hill"},
	{"question":"両側","answers":["りょうがわ"],"comment":"(n) both sides"},
	{"question":"両方","answers":["りょうほう"],"comment":"(n) both sides/both parties"},
	{"question":"両替","answers":["りょうがえ"],"comment":"(n,vs) change/money exchange"},
	{"question":"両極","answers":["りょうきょく"],"comment":"(n) both extremities/north and south poles/positive and negative poles"},
	{"question":"両立","answers":["りょうりつ"],"comment":"(n) compatibility/coexistence/standing together"},
	{"question":"両親","answers":["りょうしん"],"comment":"(n) parents/both parents"},
	{"question":"並","answers":["なみ"],"comment":"line up/be in a row/rank with/rival/equal"},
	{"question":"並びに","answers":["ならびに"],"comment":"(conj) and"},
	{"question":"並ぶ","answers":["ならぶ"],"comment":"(v5b,vi) to line up/to stand in a line"},
	{"question":"並べる","answers":["ならべる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to line up/to set up"},
	{"question":"並列","answers":["へいれつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) arrangement/parallel/abreast"},
	{"question":"並木","answers":["なみき"],"comment":"(n) roadside tree/row of trees"},
	{"question":"並行","answers":["へいこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) (going) side by side/concurrent/abreast/at the same time/occurring together/parallel/parallelism"},
	{"question":"中","answers":["ちゅう","なか"],"comment":"(n) inside/middle/among"},
	{"question":"中世","answers":["ちゅうせい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) Middle Ages/mediaeval times"},
	{"question":"中傷","answers":["ちゅうしょう"],"comment":"(n) slander/libel/defamation"},
	{"question":"中古","answers":["ちゅうこ"],"comment":"(n-t) (1) used/second-hand/old"},
	{"question":"中味","answers":["なかみ"],"comment":"(n) contents/interior/substance/filling/(sword) blade"},
	{"question":"中和","answers":["ちゅうわ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) neutralize/counteract"},
	{"question":"中央","answers":["ちゅうおう"],"comment":"(n) centre/central/center/middle"},
	{"question":"中学","answers":["ちゅうがく"],"comment":"(n) middle school/junior high school"},
	{"question":"中学校","answers":["ちゅうがっこう"],"comment":"(n) junior high school/middle school pupil"},
	{"question":"中年","answers":["ちゅうねん"],"comment":"(n) middle-aged"},
	{"question":"中心","answers":["ちゅうしん"],"comment":"(n) center/core/heart/pivot/emphasis/balance"},
	{"question":"中性","answers":["ちゅうせい"],"comment":"(n) neuter gender/neutral (chem.)/indifference/sterility"},
	{"question":"中指","answers":["なかゆび"],"comment":"(n) middle finger"},
	{"question":"中断","answers":["ちゅうだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) interruption/suspension/break"},
	{"question":"中旬","answers":["ちゅうじゅん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) second third of a month"},
	{"question":"中枢","answers":["ちゅうすう"],"comment":"(n) centre/pivot/mainstay/nucleus/backbone/central figure/pillar/key man"},
	{"question":"中止","answers":["ちゅうし"],"comment":"(n,vs) suspension/stoppage/discontinuance/interruption"},
	{"question":"中毒","answers":["ちゅうどく"],"comment":"(n) poisoning"},
	{"question":"中程","answers":["なかほど"],"comment":"(n) middle/midway"},
	{"question":"中立","answers":["ちゅうりつ"],"comment":"(n) neutrality"},
	{"question":"中継","answers":["ちゅうけい"],"comment":"(n) relay/hook-up"},
	{"question":"中腹","answers":["ちゅうふく"],"comment":"(n) mountain side/halfway up"},
	{"question":"中身","answers":["なかみ"],"comment":"(n) contents/interior/substance/filling/(sword) blade"},
	{"question":"中途","answers":["ちゅうと"],"comment":"(n) in the middle/half-way"},
	{"question":"中間","answers":["ちゅうかん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) middle/midway/interim"},
	{"question":"丸","answers":["まる"],"comment":"(n) circle/full (month)/perfection/purity/suffix for ship names"},
	{"question":"丸々","answers":["まるまる"],"comment":"(adv,n) completely"},
	{"question":"丸い","answers":["まるい"],"comment":"(adj) round/circular/spherical"},
	{"question":"丸ごと","answers":["まるごと"],"comment":"(adv) in its entirety/whole/wholly"},
	{"question":"丸める","answers":["まるめる"],"comment":"(v1) to make round/to round off/to roll up/to curl up/to seduce/to cajole/to explain away"},
	{"question":"主","answers":["しゅ","ぬし"],"comment":"(n) owner/master/lover/god"},
	{"question":"主に","answers":["おもに"],"comment":"(adv) mainly/primarily"},
	{"question":"主人","answers":["しゅじん"],"comment":"(n) master/head (of a household)/landlord/one's husband/employer/host"},
	{"question":"主人公","answers":["しゅじんこう"],"comment":"(n) (1) protagonist/main character/hero(ine) (of a story)/(2) head of household"},
	{"question":"主任","answers":["しゅにん"],"comment":"(n) person in charge/responsible official"},
	{"question":"主体","answers":["しゅたい"],"comment":"(n) subject/main constituent"},
	{"question":"主催","answers":["しゅさい"],"comment":"(n,vs) organization/sponsorship"},
	{"question":"主婦","answers":["しゅふ"],"comment":"(n) housewife/mistress"},
	{"question":"主導","answers":["しゅどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) main leadership"},
	{"question":"主張","answers":["しゅちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) claim/request/insistence/assertion/advocacy/emphasis/contention/opinion/tenet"},
	{"question":"主役","answers":["しゅやく"],"comment":"(n) leading part/leading actor (actress)"},
	{"question":"主権","answers":["しゅけん"],"comment":"(n) sovereignty/supremacy/dominion"},
	{"question":"主演","answers":["しゅえん"],"comment":"(n) starring/playing the leading part"},
	{"question":"主義","answers":["しゅぎ"],"comment":"(n) doctrine/rule/principle"},
	{"question":"主要","answers":["しゅよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) chief/main/principal/major"},
	{"question":"主観","answers":["しゅかん"],"comment":"(n) subjectivity/subject/ego"},
	{"question":"主語","answers":["しゅご"],"comment":"(n) (gram) subject"},
	{"question":"主題","answers":["しゅだい"],"comment":"(n) subject/theme/motif"},
	{"question":"主食","answers":["しゅしょく"],"comment":"(n) staple food"},
	{"question":"丼","answers":["どんぶり"],"comment":"(n) porcelain bowl/bowl of rice with food on top"},
	{"question":"乃至","answers":["ないし"],"comment":"(conj) from...to/between...and/or"},
	{"question":"久しい","answers":["ひさしい"],"comment":"(adj) long/long-continued/old (story)"},
	{"question":"久しぶり","answers":["ひさしぶり"],"comment":"(exp) after a long time"},
	{"question":"乏しい","answers":["とぼしい"],"comment":"(adj) meagre/scarce/limited/destitute/hard up/scanty/poor"},
	{"question":"乗せる","answers":["のせる"],"comment":"(v1) to place on (something)/to take on board/to give a ride/to let (one) take part/to impose on/to record/to mention/to load (luggage)/to publish/to run (an ad)"},
	{"question":"乗っ取る","answers":["のっとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to capture/to occupy/to usurp"},
	{"question":"乗り換える","answers":["のりかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to transfer (trains)/to change (bus, train)"},
	{"question":"乗り物","answers":["のりもの"],"comment":"(n) vehicle"},
	{"question":"乗り越し","answers":["のりこし"],"comment":"(n) riding past (one's station)"},
	{"question":"乗り込む","answers":["のりこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) (1) to board/to embark on/to get into (a car)/to ship (passengers)/to man (a ship)/to help (someone) into/(2) to march into/to enter"},
	{"question":"乗る","answers":["のる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to get on/to ride in/to board/to mount/to get up on/to spread (paints)/to be taken in/(2) to share in/to join/to be found in (a dictionary)/to feel like doing/to be mentioned in/to be in harmony with"},
	{"question":"乗客","answers":["じょうきゃく"],"comment":"(n) passenger"},
	{"question":"乗換","answers":["のりかえ"],"comment":"(io) (n) transfer (trains, buses, etc.)"},
	{"question":"乗車","answers":["じょうしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) taking a train/entraining"},
	{"question":"乙","answers":["おつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) 2nd in rank/second sign of the Chinese calendar"},
	{"question":"九","answers":["きゅう","く"],"comment":"(num) nine"},
	{"question":"九つ","answers":["ここのつ"],"comment":"(n) nine"},
	{"question":"九日","answers":["ここのか"],"comment":"nine days/the ninth day (of the month)"},
	{"question":"乱す","answers":["みだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to throw out of order/to disarrange/to disturb"},
	{"question":"乱れる","answers":["みだれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get confused/to be disordered/to be disturbed"},
	{"question":"乱暴","answers":["らんぼう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) rude/violent/rough/lawless/unreasonable/reckless"},
	{"question":"乳","answers":["ちち"],"comment":"(n) milk/breast/loop"},
	{"question":"乾かす","answers":["かわかす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to dry (clothes, etc.)/to desiccate"},
	{"question":"乾く","answers":["かわく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) to get dry"},
	{"question":"乾杯","answers":["かんぱい"],"comment":"(n,vs) toast (drink)"},
	{"question":"乾燥","answers":["かんそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) dry/arid/insipid/dehydrated"},
	{"question":"乾電池","answers":["かんでんち"],"comment":"(n) dry cell/battery"},
	{"question":"了承","answers":["りょうしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) acknowledgement/understanding (e.g. 'please be understanding of the mess during our renovation')"},
	{"question":"了解","answers":["りょうかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) comprehension/consent/understanding/roger (on the radio)"},
	{"question":"予て","answers":["かねて"],"comment":"(adv) previously/already/lately"},
	{"question":"予め","answers":["あらかじめ"],"comment":"(adv) beforehand/in advance/previously"},
	{"question":"予備","answers":["よび"],"comment":"(n) preparation/preliminaries/reserve/spare"},
	{"question":"予報","answers":["よほう"],"comment":"(n,vs) forecast/prediction"},
	{"question":"予定","answers":["よてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) plans/arrangement/schedule/program/expectation/estimate"},
	{"question":"予想","answers":["よそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) expectation/anticipation/prediction/forecast"},
	{"question":"予感","answers":["よかん"],"comment":"(n) presentiment/premonition"},
	{"question":"予期","answers":["よき"],"comment":"(n,vs) expectation/assume will happen/forecast"},
	{"question":"予測","answers":["よそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) prediction/estimation"},
	{"question":"予算","answers":["よさん"],"comment":"(n) estimate/budget"},
	{"question":"予約","answers":["よやく"],"comment":"(n,vs) reservation/contract/subscription/booking/pledge/advance order"},
	{"question":"予習","answers":["よしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) preparation for a lesson"},
	{"question":"予言","answers":["よげん"],"comment":"(n) prediction/promise/prognostication"},
	{"question":"予防","answers":["よぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) prevention/precaution/protection against"},
	{"question":"争い","answers":["あらそい"],"comment":"(n) dispute/strife/quarrel/dissension/conflict/rivalry/contest"},
	{"question":"争う","answers":["あらそう"],"comment":"(v5u) to dispute/to argue/to be at variance/to compete"},
	{"question":"事","answers":["こと"],"comment":"(n) thing/matter/fact/circumstances/business/reason/experience"},
	{"question":"事件","answers":["じけん"],"comment":"(n) event/affair/incident/case/plot/trouble/scandal"},
	{"question":"事前","answers":["じぜん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) prior/beforehand/in advance"},
	{"question":"事務","answers":["じむ"],"comment":"(n) business/office work"},
	{"question":"事務所","answers":["じむしょ"],"comment":"(n) office"},
	{"question":"事実","answers":["じじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) fact/truth/reality"},
	{"question":"事情","answers":["じじょう"],"comment":"(n) circumstances/consideration/conditions/situation/reasons"},
	{"question":"事態","answers":["じたい"],"comment":"(n) situation/present state of affairs/circumstances"},
	{"question":"事故","answers":["じこ"],"comment":"(n) accident/incident/trouble/circumstances/reasons"},
	{"question":"事柄","answers":["ことがら"],"comment":"(n) matter/thing/affair/circumstance"},
	{"question":"事業","answers":["じぎょう"],"comment":"(n) project/enterprise/business/industry/operations"},
	{"question":"事項","answers":["じこう"],"comment":"(n) matter/item/facts"},
	{"question":"二","answers":["に"],"comment":"(num) two"},
	{"question":"二つ","answers":["ふたつ"],"comment":"(n) two"},
	{"question":"二人","answers":["ふたり"],"comment":"(n) two persons/two people/pair/couple"},
	{"question":"二十","answers":["はたち"],"comment":"(n) 20 years old/20th year"},
	{"question":"二十日","answers":["はつか"],"comment":"(n) twenty days/twentieth (day of the month)"},
	{"question":"二十歳","answers":["はたち"],"comment":"(n) 20 years old/20th year"},
	{"question":"二日","answers":["ふつか"],"comment":"(n) second day of the month/two days"},
	{"question":"云々","answers":["うんぬん"],"comment":"(n,vs) and so on/and so forth/comment"},
	{"question":"互い","answers":["たがい"],"comment":"(n) mutual/reciprocal"},
	{"question":"五","answers":["ご"],"comment":"(num) five"},
	{"question":"五つ","answers":["いつつ"],"comment":"(n) five"},
	{"question":"五十音","answers":["ごじゅうおん"],"comment":"(n) the Japanese syllabary"},
	{"question":"五日","answers":["いつか"],"comment":"(n) five days/the fifth day (of the month)"},
	{"question":"井戸","answers":["いど"],"comment":"(n) water well"},
	{"question":"亜","answers":["あ"],"comment":"(pref) ① sub-. ② -ous (indicating a low oxidation state); -ite."},
	{"question":"亡くす","answers":["なくす"],"comment":"(v5s) to lose someone, wife, child, etc"},
	{"question":"亡くなる","answers":["なくなる"],"comment":"(v5r) to die"},
	{"question":"交える","answers":["まじえる"],"comment":"(v1) to mix/to converse with/to cross (swords)"},
	{"question":"交ざる","answers":["まざる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to join"},
	{"question":"交じる","answers":["まじる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to interest/to join"},
	{"question":"交す","answers":["かわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to exchange (messages)/to dodge/to parry/to avoid/to turn aside"},
	{"question":"交ぜる","answers":["まぜる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with"},
	{"question":"交わる","answers":["まじわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to cross/to intersect/to associate with/to mingle with/to interest/to join"},
	{"question":"交互","answers":["こうご"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) mutual/reciprocal/alternate"},
	{"question":"交付","answers":["こうふ"],"comment":"(n,vs) delivering/furnishing (with copies)"},
	{"question":"交差","answers":["こうさ"],"comment":"(n,vs) cross"},
	{"question":"交差点","answers":["こうさてん"],"comment":"(n) crossing/intersection"},
	{"question":"交換","answers":["こうかん"],"comment":"(n,vs) exchange/interchange/reciprocity/barter/substitution/clearing (of checks)"},
	{"question":"交替","answers":["こうたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) alternation/change/relief/relay/shift"},
	{"question":"交流","answers":["こうりゅう"],"comment":"(n) alternating current/intercourse/(cultural) exchange/intermingling"},
	{"question":"交渉","answers":["こうしょう"],"comment":"(n) negotiations/discussions/connection"},
	{"question":"交番","answers":["こうばん"],"comment":"(n) police box"},
	{"question":"交通","answers":["こうつう"],"comment":"(n) communication/transportation/traffic/intercourse"},
	{"question":"交通機関","answers":["こうつうきかん"],"comment":"(n) transportation facilities"},
	{"question":"交際","answers":["こうさい"],"comment":"(n,vs) company/friendship/association/society/acquaintance"},
	{"question":"享受","answers":["きょうじゅ"],"comment":"(n,vs) reception/acceptance/enjoyment/being given"},
	{"question":"人","answers":["ひと"],"comment":"(n) man/person/human being/mankind/people/character/personality/true man/man of talent/adult/other people/messenger/visitor"},
	{"question":"人事","answers":["じんじ"],"comment":"(n) other's affairs"},
	{"question":"人体","answers":["じんたい"],"comment":"(n) personal appearance/looks"},
	{"question":"人口","answers":["じんこう"],"comment":"(n) (1) population/(2) common talk"},
	{"question":"人命","answers":["じんめい"],"comment":"(n) (human) life"},
	{"question":"人工","answers":["じんこう"],"comment":"(n) artificial/manmade/human work/human skill/artificiality"},
	{"question":"人差指","answers":["ひとさしゆび"],"comment":"(n) index finger"},
	{"question":"人形","answers":["にんぎょう"],"comment":"(n) doll/puppet/figure"},
	{"question":"人影","answers":["ひとかげ"],"comment":"(n) man's shadow/soul"},
	{"question":"人文科学","answers":["じんぶんかがく"],"comment":"social sciences/humanities"},
	{"question":"人材","answers":["じんざい"],"comment":"(n) man of talent"},
	{"question":"人柄","answers":["ひとがら"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) personality/character/personal appearance/gentility"},
	{"question":"人格","answers":["じんかく"],"comment":"(n) personality/character/individuality"},
	{"question":"人民","answers":["じんみん"],"comment":"(n) people/public"},
	{"question":"人気","answers":["にんき","ひとけ"],"comment":"(n) sign of life"},
	{"question":"人物","answers":["じんぶつ"],"comment":"(n) character/personality/person/man/personage/talented man"},
	{"question":"人生","answers":["じんせい"],"comment":"(n) (human) life (i.e. conception to death)"},
	{"question":"人目","answers":["ひとめ"],"comment":"(n) glimpse/public gaze"},
	{"question":"人種","answers":["じんしゅ"],"comment":"(n) race (of people)"},
	{"question":"人質","answers":["ひとじち"],"comment":"(n) hostage/prisoner"},
	{"question":"人込み","answers":["ひとごみ"],"comment":"(n) crowd of people"},
	{"question":"人通り","answers":["ひとどおり"],"comment":"(n) pedestrian traffic"},
	{"question":"人造","answers":["じんぞう"],"comment":"(n) man-made/synthetic/artificial"},
	{"question":"人間","answers":["にんげん"],"comment":"(n) human being/man/person"},
	{"question":"人類","answers":["じんるい"],"comment":"(n) mankind/humanity"},
	{"question":"今","answers":["いま"],"comment":"this/now"},
	{"question":"今に","answers":["いまに"],"comment":"(adv) before long/even now"},
	{"question":"今にも","answers":["いまにも"],"comment":"(adv) at any time/soon"},
	{"question":"今回","answers":["こんかい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) now/this time/lately"},
	{"question":"今夜","answers":["こんや"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) this evening/tonight"},
	{"question":"今年","answers":["ことし"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) this year"},
	{"question":"今度","answers":["こんど"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) now/this time/next time/another time"},
	{"question":"今後","answers":["こんご"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) from now on/hereafter"},
	{"question":"今日","answers":["きょう","こんにち"],"comment":"(n-t) today/this day"},
	{"question":"今晩","answers":["こんばん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) tonight/this evening"},
	{"question":"今月","answers":["こんげつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) this month"},
	{"question":"今朝","answers":["けさ"],"comment":"(ik) (n-t) this morning"},
	{"question":"今週","answers":["こんしゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) this week"},
	{"question":"介入","answers":["かいにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) intervention"},
	{"question":"介抱","answers":["かいほう"],"comment":"(n,vs) nursing/looking after"},
	{"question":"介護","answers":["かいご"],"comment":"(n,vs) nursing"},
	{"question":"仏","answers":["ほとけ"],"comment":"(n) Buddha/merciful person/Buddhist image/the dead"},
	{"question":"仏像","answers":["ぶつぞう"],"comment":"(n) Buddhist image (statue)"},
	{"question":"仕える","answers":["つかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to serve/to work for"},
	{"question":"仕上","answers":["しあげ"],"comment":"(n) end/finishing touches/being finished"},
	{"question":"仕上がり","answers":["しあがり"],"comment":"(n) finish/end/completion"},
	{"question":"仕上がる","answers":["しあがる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be finished"},
	{"question":"仕上げる","answers":["しあげる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to finish up/to complete"},
	{"question":"仕事","answers":["しごと"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) work/occupation/employment"},
	{"question":"仕入れる","answers":["しいれる"],"comment":"(v1) to lay in stock/to replenish stock/to procure"},
	{"question":"仕切る","answers":["しきる"],"comment":"(v5r) to partition/to divide/to mark off/to settle accounts/to toe the mark"},
	{"question":"仕掛","answers":["しかけ"],"comment":"(n) device/trick/mechanism/gadget/(small) scale/half finished/commencement/set up/challenge"},
	{"question":"仕掛ける","answers":["しかける"],"comment":"(v1) to commence/to lay (mines)/to set (traps)/to wage (war)/to challenge"},
	{"question":"仕方","answers":["しかた"],"comment":"(n) way/method/means/resource/course"},
	{"question":"仕様","answers":["しよう"],"comment":"(n) way/method/resource/remedy/(technical) specification"},
	{"question":"仕立てる","answers":["したてる"],"comment":"(v1) to tailor/to make/to prepare/to train/to send (a messenger)"},
	{"question":"仕組","answers":["しくみ"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) structure/construction/arrangement/contrivance/(2) plan/plot/contrivance"},
	{"question":"他","answers":["た","ほか"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) other (esp. places and things)"},
	{"question":"他人","answers":["たにん"],"comment":"(n) another person/unrelated person/outsider/stranger"},
	{"question":"他動詞","answers":["たどうし"],"comment":"(n) transitive verb (direct obj)"},
	{"question":"他方","answers":["たほう"],"comment":"(adv,n) another side/different direction/(on) the other hand"},
	{"question":"付き合い","answers":["つきあい"],"comment":"(n) association/socializing/fellowship"},
	{"question":"付く","answers":["つく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) to adjoin/to be attached/to adhere/to be connected with/to be dyed/to be stained/to be scarred/to be recorded/to start (fires)/to follow/to become allied to/to accompany/to study with/to increase/to be added to"},
	{"question":"付ける","answers":["つける"],"comment":"(v1,vt) (1) to attach/to join/to add/to append/to affix/to stick/to glue/to fasten/to sew on/to apply (ointment)/(2) to furnish (a house with)/(3) to wear/to put on/(4) to keep a diary/to make an entry/(5) to appraise/to set (a price)/(6) to bring alongside/(7) to place (under guard or doctor)/(8) to follow/to shadow/(9) to load/to give (courage to)/(10) to keep (an eye on)/(11) to establish (relations or understanding)"},
	{"question":"付け加える","answers":["つけくわえる"],"comment":"(v1) to add one thing to another"},
	{"question":"付合う","answers":["つきあう"],"comment":"(v5u) to associate with/to keep company with/to get on with"},
	{"question":"付近","answers":["ふきん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) neighbourhood/vicinity/environs"},
	{"question":"付録","answers":["ふろく"],"comment":"(n) appendix/supplement"},
	{"question":"代える","answers":["かえる"],"comment":"(v1) to exchange/to interchange/to substitute/to replace"},
	{"question":"代る","answers":["かわる"],"comment":"(io) (v5r,vi) to take the place of/to relieve/to be substituted for/to be exchanged/to change places with/to take turns/to be replaced"},
	{"question":"代る代る","answers":["かわるがわる"],"comment":"(adv) alternately"},
	{"question":"代わり","answers":["かわり"],"comment":"(n) substitute/deputy/proxy/alternate/relief/compensation/second helping"},
	{"question":"代名詞","answers":["だいめいし"],"comment":"(n) pronoun"},
	{"question":"代弁","answers":["だいべん"],"comment":"(n,vs) pay by proxy/act for another/speak for another"},
	{"question":"代理","answers":["だいり"],"comment":"(n) representation/agency/proxy/deputy/agent/attorney/substitute/alternate/acting (principal, etc.)"},
	{"question":"代用","answers":["だいよう"],"comment":"(n) substitution"},
	{"question":"代表","answers":["だいひょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) representative/representation/delegation/type/example/model"},
	{"question":"代金","answers":["だいきん"],"comment":"(n) price/payment/cost/charge/the money/the bill"},
	{"question":"以上","answers":["いじょう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) more than/exceeding/greater than/this is all/over/above/and up/beyond/the above-mentioned/since/as long as/the end"},
	{"question":"以下","answers":["いか"],"comment":"(n) less than/up to/below/under/and downward/not exceeding/the following/the rest"},
	{"question":"以内","answers":["いない"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) within/inside of/less than"},
	{"question":"以前","answers":["いぜん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) ago/since/before/previous"},
	{"question":"以外","answers":["いがい"],"comment":"(n-adv) with the exception of/excepting"},
	{"question":"以後","answers":["いご"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) after this/from now on/hereafter/thereafter"},
	{"question":"以来","answers":["いらい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) since/henceforth"},
	{"question":"以降","answers":["いこう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) on and after/hereafter/thereafter"},
	{"question":"仮名","answers":["かな"],"comment":"(ok) (n) alias/pseudonym/pen name/nom de plume/(NB the karina reading is the origin of the word `kana')"},
	{"question":"仮名遣い","answers":["かなづかい"],"comment":"(n) kana orthography/syllabary spelling"},
	{"question":"仮定","answers":["かてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) assumption/supposition/hypothesis"},
	{"question":"仰ぐ","answers":["あおぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to look up (to)/to respect/to depend on/to ask for/to seek/to revere/to drink/to take"},
	{"question":"仲","answers":["なか"],"comment":"(n) relation/relationship"},
	{"question":"仲人","answers":["なこうど"],"comment":"(n) go-between/matchmaker"},
	{"question":"仲直り","answers":["なかなおり"],"comment":"(n,vs) reconciliation/make peace with"},
	{"question":"仲良し","answers":["なかよし"],"comment":"(n) intimate friend/bosom buddy/chum"},
	{"question":"仲間","answers":["なかま"],"comment":"(n) company/fellow/colleague/associate/comrade/mate/group/circle of friends/partner"},
	{"question":"件","answers":["けん"],"comment":"(n) matter/case/item"},
	{"question":"任す","answers":["まかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to entrust/to leave to a person"},
	{"question":"任せる","answers":["まかせる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to entrust to another/to leave to/(2) to do something at one's leisure"},
	{"question":"任務","answers":["にんむ"],"comment":"(n) duty/function/office/mission/task"},
	{"question":"任命","answers":["にんめい"],"comment":"(n) appointment/nomination/ordination/commission/designation"},
	{"question":"企業","answers":["きぎょう"],"comment":"(n) enterprise/undertaking"},
	{"question":"企画","answers":["きかく"],"comment":"(n,vs) planning/project"},
	{"question":"休み","answers":["やすみ"],"comment":"(n) (1) rest/recess/respite/(2) vacation/holiday/absence/suspension/(3) moulting"},
	{"question":"休む","answers":["やすむ"],"comment":"(v5m,vi) to rest/to have a break/to take a day off/to be finished/to be absent/to retire/to sleep"},
	{"question":"休める","answers":["やすめる"],"comment":"(v1) to rest/to suspend/to give relief"},
	{"question":"休学","answers":["きゅうがく"],"comment":"(n) temporary absence from school/suspension"},
	{"question":"休息","answers":["きゅうそく"],"comment":"(n) rest/relief/relaxation"},
	{"question":"休憩","answers":["きゅうけい"],"comment":"(n,vs) rest/break/recess/intermission"},
	{"question":"休戦","answers":["きゅうせん"],"comment":"(n) truce/armistice"},
	{"question":"休暇","answers":["きゅうか"],"comment":"(n) holiday/day off/furlough"},
	{"question":"休業","answers":["きゅうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) closed (e.g. store)/business suspended/shutdown/holiday"},
	{"question":"休講","answers":["きゅうこう"],"comment":"(n) lecture cancelled"},
	{"question":"休養","answers":["きゅうよう"],"comment":"(n) rest/break/recreation"},
	{"question":"会","answers":["かい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,vs) meeting/assembly/party/association/club"},
	{"question":"会う","answers":["あう"],"comment":"(v5u) to meet/to interview"},
	{"question":"会合","answers":["かいごう"],"comment":"(n) meeting/assembly"},
	{"question":"会員","answers":["かいいん"],"comment":"(n) member/the membership"},
	{"question":"会場","answers":["かいじょう"],"comment":"(n) assembly hall/meeting place/the grounds"},
	{"question":"会社","answers":["かいしゃ"],"comment":"(n) company/corporation"},
	{"question":"会見","answers":["かいけん"],"comment":"(n) interview/audience"},
	{"question":"会計","answers":["かいけい"],"comment":"(n) account/finance/accountant/treasurer/paymaster/reckoning/bill"},
	{"question":"会話","answers":["かいわ"],"comment":"(n) conversation"},
	{"question":"会談","answers":["かいだん"],"comment":"(n) conversation/conference/discussion/interview"},
	{"question":"会議","answers":["かいぎ"],"comment":"(n) meeting/conference/session/assembly/council/convention/congress"},
	{"question":"会館","answers":["かいかん"],"comment":"(n) meeting hall/assembly hall"},
	{"question":"伜","answers":["せがれ"],"comment":"(n) son/my son"},
	{"question":"伝える","answers":["つたえる"],"comment":"(v1) to convey/to report/to transmit/to communicate/to tell/to impart/to propagate/to teach/to bequeath"},
	{"question":"伝わる","answers":["つたわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be handed down/to be introduced/to be transmitted/to be circulated/to go along/to walk along"},
	{"question":"伝来","answers":["でんらい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) ancestral/hereditary/imported/transmitted/handed down"},
	{"question":"伝染","answers":["でんせん"],"comment":"(n) contagion"},
	{"question":"伝統","answers":["でんとう"],"comment":"(n) tradition/convention"},
	{"question":"伝言","answers":["でんごん"],"comment":"(n,vs) verbal message/rumor/word"},
	{"question":"伝記","answers":["でんき"],"comment":"(n) biography/life story"},
	{"question":"伝説","answers":["でんせつ"],"comment":"(n) tradition/legend/folklore"},
	{"question":"伝達","answers":["でんたつ"],"comment":"(n) transmission (e.g. news)/communication/delivery"},
	{"question":"伯母","answers":["おば"],"comment":"(n) (hum) aunt (older than one's parent)"},
	{"question":"伯母さん","answers":["おばさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) aunt"},
	{"question":"伯父","answers":["おじ"],"comment":"(n) (hum) uncle (older than one's parent)"},
	{"question":"伯父さん","answers":["おじさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) (uk) middle-aged gentleman/uncle"},
	{"question":"伴う","answers":["ともなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to accompany/to bring with/to be accompanied by/to be involved in"},
	{"question":"伸ばす","answers":["のばす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to lengthen/to stretch/to reach out/to postpone/to prolong/to extend/to grow (beard)"},
	{"question":"伸びる","answers":["のびる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to stretch/to extend/to make progress/to grow (beard, body height)/to grow stale (soba)/to lengthen/to spread/to be postponed/to be straightened/to be flattened/to be smoothed/to be exhausted"},
	{"question":"伺う","answers":["うかがう"],"comment":"(v5u,vi,vt) (hon) to visit/to ask/to inquire/to hear/to be told/to implore (a god for an oracle)"},
	{"question":"似る","answers":["にる"],"comment":"(v1) to resemble/to be similar"},
	{"question":"似合う","answers":["にあう"],"comment":"(v5u) to suit/to match/to become/to be like"},
	{"question":"似通う","answers":["にかよう"],"comment":"(v5u) to resemble closely"},
	{"question":"但し","answers":["ただし"],"comment":"(conj) but/however/provided that"},
	{"question":"位","answers":["くらい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n,suf,vs) grade/rank/court order/dignity/nobility/situation/throne/crown/occupying a position/about/almost/as/rather/at least/enough to"},
	{"question":"位置","answers":["いち"],"comment":"(n,vs) place/situation/position/location"},
	{"question":"低い","answers":["ひくい"],"comment":"(adj) short/low/humble/low (voice)"},
	{"question":"低下","answers":["ていか"],"comment":"(n,vs) fall/decline/lowering/deterioration"},
	{"question":"住","answers":["じゅう"],"comment":"(n) dwelling/living"},
	{"question":"住まい","answers":["すまい"],"comment":"(n) dwelling/house/residence/address"},
	{"question":"住む","answers":["すむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to abide/to reside/to live in/to inhabit/to dwell"},
	{"question":"住宅","answers":["じゅうたく"],"comment":"(n) resident/housing"},
	{"question":"住居","answers":["じゅうきょ"],"comment":"(n) dwelling/house/residence/address"},
	{"question":"住所","answers":["じゅうしょ"],"comment":"(n) address (e.g. of house)/residence/domicile"},
	{"question":"住民","answers":["じゅうみん"],"comment":"(n) citizens/inhabitants/residents/population"},
	{"question":"体","answers":["からだ"],"comment":"(n) appearance/air/condition/state/form"},
	{"question":"体付き","answers":["からだつき"],"comment":"(n) body build/figure"},
	{"question":"体制","answers":["たいせい"],"comment":"(n) order/system/structure/set-up/organization"},
	{"question":"体力","answers":["たいりょく"],"comment":"(n) physical strength"},
	{"question":"体操","answers":["たいそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) gymnastics/physical exercises/calisthenics"},
	{"question":"体格","answers":["たいかく"],"comment":"(n) physique/constitution"},
	{"question":"体温","answers":["たいおん"],"comment":"(n) temperature (body)"},
	{"question":"体積","answers":["たいせき"],"comment":"(n) capacity/volume"},
	{"question":"体系","answers":["たいけい"],"comment":"(n) system/organization"},
	{"question":"体育","answers":["たいいく"],"comment":"(n) physical education/gymnastics/athletics"},
	{"question":"体裁","answers":["ていさい"],"comment":"(n) decency/style/form/appearance/show/get-up/format"},
	{"question":"体重","answers":["たいじゅう"],"comment":"(n) one's body weight"},
	{"question":"体験","answers":["たいけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) personal experience"},
	{"question":"何","answers":["なに","なん"],"comment":"(int,n) what"},
	{"question":"何々","answers":["なになに"],"comment":"(int,n) such and such/What?/What is the matter?/What are the items?"},
	{"question":"何か","answers":["なにか"],"comment":"(exp) something"},
	{"question":"何だか","answers":["なんだか"],"comment":"(adv) a little/somewhat/somehow"},
	{"question":"何で","answers":["なんで"],"comment":"(adv) Why?/What for?"},
	{"question":"何でも","answers":["なんでも"],"comment":"(adv,exp) by all means/everything"},
	{"question":"何とか","answers":["なんとか"],"comment":"(adv,exp,n) somehow/anyhow/one way or another"},
	{"question":"何分","answers":["なにぶん"],"comment":"(n) what minute?/how many minutes?"},
	{"question":"何時か","answers":["いつか"],"comment":"(adv) (uk) sometime/someday/one day/some time or other/the other day/in due course/in time"},
	{"question":"何気ない","answers":["なにげない"],"comment":"(adj) casual/unconcerned"},
	{"question":"余り","answers":["あまり","あまり"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n,n-suf) (uk) not very (this form only used as adverb)/not much/remainder/rest/remnant/surplus/balance/excess/remains/scraps/residue/fullness/other/too much"},
	{"question":"余る","answers":["あまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to remain/to be left over/to be in excess/to be too many"},
	{"question":"余分","answers":["よぶん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) extra/excess/surplus"},
	{"question":"余地","answers":["よち"],"comment":"(n) place/room/margin/scope"},
	{"question":"余所","answers":["よそ"],"comment":"(n) another place/somewhere else/strange parts"},
	{"question":"余所見","answers":["よそみ"],"comment":"(n,vs) looking away/looking aside"},
	{"question":"余暇","answers":["よか"],"comment":"(n) leisure/leisure time/spare time"},
	{"question":"余程","answers":["よほど"],"comment":"(adv) very/greatly/much/to a large extent/quite"},
	{"question":"余興","answers":["よきょう"],"comment":"(n) side show/entertainment"},
	{"question":"余裕","answers":["よゆう"],"comment":"(n) surplus/composure/margin/room/time/allowance/scope/rope"},
	{"question":"余計","answers":["よけい"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) too much/unnecessary/abundance/surplus/excess/superfluity"},
	{"question":"作","answers":["さく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) a work/a harvest"},
	{"question":"作り","answers":["つくり"],"comment":"(n) make-up/sliced raw fish"},
	{"question":"作る","answers":["つくる"],"comment":"(v5r) to make/to create/to manufacture/to draw up/to write/to compose/to build/to coin/to cultivate/to organize/to establish/to make up (a face)/to trim (a tree)/to fabricate/to prepare (food)/to commit (sin)/to construct"},
	{"question":"作品","answers":["さくひん"],"comment":"(n) work/opus/performance/production"},
	{"question":"作家","answers":["さっか"],"comment":"(n) author/writer/novelist/artist"},
	{"question":"作成","answers":["さくせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) frame/draw up/make/producing/creating/preparing/writing"},
	{"question":"作戦","answers":["さくせん"],"comment":"(n) military or naval operations/tactics/strategy"},
	{"question":"作文","answers":["さくぶん"],"comment":"(n) composition/writing"},
	{"question":"作曲","answers":["さっきょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) composition/setting (of music)"},
	{"question":"作業","answers":["さぎょう"],"comment":"(n) work/operation/manufacturing/fatigue duty"},
	{"question":"作法","answers":["さほう"],"comment":"(n) manners/etiquette/propriety"},
	{"question":"作物","answers":["さくもつ"],"comment":"(n) produce (e.g. agricultural)/crops"},
	{"question":"作用","answers":["さよう"],"comment":"(n) action/operation/effect/function"},
	{"question":"作者","answers":["さくしゃ"],"comment":"(n) author/authoress"},
	{"question":"作製","answers":["さくせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) manufacture"},
	{"question":"使い道","answers":["つかいみち"],"comment":"(n) use"},
	{"question":"使う","answers":["つかう"],"comment":"(v5u) to use/to handle/to manipulate/to employ/to need/to want/to spend/to consume/to speak (English)/to practise (fencing)/to take (one's lunch)/to circulate (bad money)"},
	{"question":"使命","answers":["しめい"],"comment":"(n) mission/errand/message"},
	{"question":"使用","answers":["しよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) use/application/employment/utilization"},
	{"question":"使用人","answers":["しようにん"],"comment":"(n) employee/servant"},
	{"question":"例","answers":["れい"],"comment":"(n) instance/example/case/precedent/experience/custom/usage/parallel/illustration"},
	{"question":"例え","answers":["たとえ"],"comment":"(adv,n) example/even if/if/though/although"},
	{"question":"例えば","answers":["たとえば"],"comment":"(adv) for example/e.g."},
	{"question":"例える","answers":["たとえる"],"comment":"(v1) to compare/to liken/to speak figuratively/to illustrate/to use a simile"},
	{"question":"例外","answers":["れいがい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) exception"},
	{"question":"侍","answers":["さむらい"],"comment":"(n) Samurai/warrior"},
	{"question":"供","answers":["とも"],"comment":"(n,vs) accompanying/attendant/companion/retinue"},
	{"question":"供給","answers":["きょうきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) supply/provision"},
	{"question":"依存","answers":["いぞん"],"comment":"(n,vs) dependence/dependent/reliance"},
	{"question":"依然","answers":["いぜん"],"comment":"(adv,n) still/as yet"},
	{"question":"依頼","answers":["いらい"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) request/commission/dispatch/(2) dependence/trust"},
	{"question":"価値","answers":["かち"],"comment":"(n) value/worth/merit"},
	{"question":"価格","answers":["かかく"],"comment":"(n) price/value/cost"},
	{"question":"侮辱","answers":["ぶじょく"],"comment":"(n) insult/contempt/slight"},
	{"question":"侵す","answers":["おかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to invade/to raid/to trespass/to violate/to intrude on"},
	{"question":"侵入","answers":["しんにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) penetration/invasion/raid/aggression/trespass"},
	{"question":"侵略","answers":["しんりゃく"],"comment":"(n) aggression/invasion/raid"},
	{"question":"便","answers":["びん"],"comment":"way/means"},
	{"question":"便り","answers":["たより"],"comment":"(n) news/tidings/information/correspondence/letter"},
	{"question":"便利","answers":["べんり"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) convenient/handy/useful"},
	{"question":"便宜","answers":["べんぎ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) convenience/accommodation/advantage/expedience"},
	{"question":"便所","answers":["べんじょ"],"comment":"(n) toilet/lavatory/rest room/latrine/comfort station"},
	{"question":"便箋","answers":["びんせん"],"comment":"(n) writing paper/stationery"},
	{"question":"係","answers":["かかり"],"comment":"(n) official/duty/person in charge"},
	{"question":"係わる","answers":["かかわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to concern oneself in/to have to do with/to affect/to influence/to stick to (opinions)"},
	{"question":"促す","answers":["うながす"],"comment":"(v5s) to urge/to press/to suggest/to demand/to stimulate/to quicken/to incite/to invite (attention to)"},
	{"question":"促進","answers":["そくしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) promotion/acceleration/encouragement/facilitation/spurring on"},
	{"question":"俄","answers":["にわか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) sudden/abrupt/unexpected/improvised/offhand"},
	{"question":"保つ","answers":["たもつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to keep/to preserve/to hold/to retain/to maintain/to support/to sustain/to last/to endure/to keep well (food)/to wear well/to be durable"},
	{"question":"保健","answers":["ほけん"],"comment":"(n) health preservation/hygiene/sanitation"},
	{"question":"保存","answers":["ほぞん"],"comment":"(n,vs) preservation/conservation/storage/maintenance"},
	{"question":"保守","answers":["ほしゅ"],"comment":"(n) conservative/maintaining"},
	{"question":"保温","answers":["ほおん"],"comment":"(n) retaining warmth/keeping heat in/heat insulation"},
	{"question":"保管","answers":["ほかん"],"comment":"(n,vs) charge/custody/safekeeping/deposit/storage"},
	{"question":"保育","answers":["ほいく"],"comment":"(n,vs) nursing/nurturing/rearing/lactation/suckling"},
	{"question":"保証","answers":["ほしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) guarantee/security/assurance/pledge/warranty"},
	{"question":"保護","answers":["ほご"],"comment":"(n) care/protection/shelter/guardianship/favor/patronage"},
	{"question":"保険","answers":["ほけん"],"comment":"(n) insurance/guarantee"},
	{"question":"保障","answers":["ほしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) guarantee/security/assurance/pledge/warranty"},
	{"question":"保養","answers":["ほよう"],"comment":"(n) health preservation/recuperation/recreation"},
	{"question":"信じる","answers":["しんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to believe/to believe in/to place trust in/to confide in/to have faith in"},
	{"question":"信ずる","answers":["しんずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to believe/to believe in/to place trust in/to confide in/to have faith in"},
	{"question":"信仰","answers":["しんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) (religious) faith/belief/creed"},
	{"question":"信任","answers":["しんにん"],"comment":"(n,vs) trust/confidence/credence"},
	{"question":"信号","answers":["しんごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) traffic lights/signal/semaphore"},
	{"question":"信用","answers":["しんよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) confidence/dependence/credit/faith/reliance/belief/credence"},
	{"question":"信者","answers":["しんじゃ"],"comment":"(n) believer/adherent/devotee/Christian"},
	{"question":"信頼","answers":["しんらい"],"comment":"(n,vs) reliance/trust/confidence"},
	{"question":"修士","answers":["しゅうし"],"comment":"(n) Masters degree program"},
	{"question":"修学","answers":["しゅうがく"],"comment":"(n) learning"},
	{"question":"修正","answers":["しゅうせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) amendment/correction/revision/modification/alteration/retouching/update"},
	{"question":"修理","answers":["しゅうり"],"comment":"(n,vs) repairing/mending"},
	{"question":"修繕","answers":["しゅうぜん"],"comment":"(n,vs) repair/mending"},
	{"question":"修行","answers":["しゅぎょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) pursuit of knowledge/studying/learning/training/ascetic practice/discipline"},
	{"question":"修飾","answers":["しゅうしょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) ornamentation/embellishment/decoration/adornment/polish up (writing)/(2) modification (gram)"},
	{"question":"俳優","answers":["はいゆう"],"comment":"(n) actor/actress/player/performer"},
	{"question":"俳句","answers":["はいく"],"comment":"(n) haiku poetry (17-syllable poem usually in 3 lines of 5, 7 and 5 syllables)"},
	{"question":"俺","answers":["おれ"],"comment":"(n) I (ego) (boastful first-person pronoun)"},
	{"question":"倉庫","answers":["そうこ"],"comment":"(n) storehouse/warehouse/godown"},
	{"question":"個々","answers":["ここ"],"comment":"(n) individual/one by one"},
	{"question":"個人","answers":["こじん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) individual/private person/personal/private"},
	{"question":"個体","answers":["こたい"],"comment":"(n) an individual"},
	{"question":"個別","answers":["こべつ"],"comment":"(n) particular case"},
	{"question":"個性","answers":["こせい"],"comment":"(n) individuality/personality/idiosyncrasy"},
	{"question":"個所","answers":["かしょ"],"comment":"(n) passage/place/point/part"},
	{"question":"倍","answers":["ばい"],"comment":"(n,vi,vs,vt) twice/times/-fold/double/be doubled/increase"},
	{"question":"倍率","answers":["ばいりつ"],"comment":"(n) diameter/magnification"},
	{"question":"倒す","answers":["たおす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to throw down/to beat/to bring down/to blow down/to fell/to knock down/to trip up/to defeat/to ruin/to overthrow/to kill/to leave unpaid/to cheat"},
	{"question":"倒れる","answers":["たおれる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to collapse/to break down/to go bankrupt/to fall/to drop/to die/to succumb to/to fall senseless/to be ruined/to have a bad debt"},
	{"question":"倒産","answers":["とうさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (corporate) bankruptcy/insolvency"},
	{"question":"候補","answers":["こうほ"],"comment":"(n) candidacy"},
	{"question":"借り","answers":["かり"],"comment":"(n) borrowing/debt/loan"},
	{"question":"借りる","answers":["かりる"],"comment":"(v1) to borrow/to have a loan/to hire/to rent/to buy on credit"},
	{"question":"借金","answers":["しゃっきん"],"comment":"(n) debt/loan/liabilities"},
	{"question":"倣う","answers":["ならう"],"comment":"(ok) (v5u) (uk) to imitate/to follow/to emulate"},
	{"question":"値","answers":["あたい","ね"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) value/price/cost/worth/merit"},
	{"question":"値する","answers":["あたいする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to be worth/to deserve/to merit"},
	{"question":"値引き","answers":["ねびき"],"comment":"(n) price reduction/discount"},
	{"question":"値打ち","answers":["ねうち"],"comment":"(n) value/worth/price/dignity"},
	{"question":"値段","answers":["ねだん"],"comment":"(n) price/cost"},
	{"question":"倹約","answers":["けんやく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) thrift/economy/frugality"},
	{"question":"偉い","answers":["えらい"],"comment":"(adj) great/celebrated/eminent/terrible/awful/famous/remarkable/excellent"},
	{"question":"偉大","answers":["いだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) greatness"},
	{"question":"偏見","answers":["へんけん"],"comment":"(n) prejudice/narrow view"},
	{"question":"停止","answers":["ていし"],"comment":"(n,vs) suspension/interruption/stoppage/ban/standstill/deadlock/stalemate/abeyance"},
	{"question":"停滞","answers":["ていたい"],"comment":"(n) stagnation/tie-up/congestion/retention/accumulation/falling into arrears"},
	{"question":"停留所","answers":["ていりゅうじょ"],"comment":"(n) bus or tram stop"},
	{"question":"停車","answers":["ていしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) stopping (e.g. train)"},
	{"question":"停電","answers":["ていでん"],"comment":"(n,vs) failure of electricity"},
	{"question":"健やか","answers":["すこやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) vigorous/healthy/sound"},
	{"question":"健全","answers":["けんぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) health/soundness/wholesome"},
	{"question":"健在","answers":["けんざい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) in good health/well"},
	{"question":"健康","answers":["けんこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) health/sound/wholesome"},
	{"question":"側","answers":["そば"],"comment":"(n) side/edge/third person"},
	{"question":"側面","answers":["そくめん"],"comment":"(n) side/flank/sidelight/lateral"},
	{"question":"偶","answers":["たま"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) even number/couple/man and wife/friend/same kind/doll/occasional/rare"},
	{"question":"偶々","answers":["たまたま"],"comment":"(adv) casually/unexpectedly/accidentally/by chance"},
	{"question":"偶数","answers":["ぐうすう"],"comment":"(n) even number"},
	{"question":"偶然","answers":["ぐうぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n-adv,n) (by) chance/unexpectedly/suddenly/accident/fortuity"},
	{"question":"偽造","answers":["ぎぞう"],"comment":"(n) forgery/falsification/fabrication/counterfeiting"},
	{"question":"傍ら","answers":["かたわら"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) beside(s)/while/nearby"},
	{"question":"傑作","answers":["けっさく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) masterpiece/best work/boner/blunder"},
	{"question":"傘","answers":["かさ"],"comment":"(n) umbrella/parasol"},
	{"question":"備える","answers":["そなえる"],"comment":"(v1) to furnish/to provide for/to equip/to install/to have ready/to prepare for/to possess/to have/to be endowed with/to be armed with"},
	{"question":"備え付ける","answers":["そなえつける"],"comment":"(v1) to provide/to furnish/to equip/to install"},
	{"question":"備わる","answers":["そなわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be furnished with/to be endowed with/to possess/to be among/to be one of/to be possessed of"},
	{"question":"催し","answers":["もよおし"],"comment":"(n) event/festivities/function/social gathering/auspices/opening/holding (a meeting)"},
	{"question":"催す","answers":["もよおす"],"comment":"(v5s) to hold (a meeting)/to give (a dinner)/to feel/to show signs of/to develop symptoms of/to feel (sick)"},
	{"question":"催促","answers":["さいそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) request/demand/claim/urge (action)/press for"},
	{"question":"傷","answers":["きず"],"comment":"(n) wound/injury/hurt/cut/gash/bruise/scratch/scar/weak point"},
	{"question":"傷める","answers":["いためる"],"comment":"(v1) to damage/to impair/to spoil"},
	{"question":"傷付く","answers":["きずつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be hurt/to be wounded/to get injured"},
	{"question":"傷付ける","answers":["きずつける"],"comment":"(v1) to wound/to hurt someone's feelings"},
	{"question":"傾く","answers":["かたむく"],"comment":"(v5k) to incline toward/to slant/to lurch/to heel over/to be disposed to/to trend toward/to be prone to/to go down (sun)/to wane/to sink/to decline"},
	{"question":"傾ける","answers":["かたむける"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to incline/to list/to bend/to lean/to tip/to tilt/to slant/to concentrate on/to ruin (a country)/to squander/to empty"},
	{"question":"傾向","answers":["けいこう"],"comment":"(n) tendency/trend/inclination"},
	{"question":"傾斜","answers":["けいしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) inclination/slant/slope/bevel/list/dip"},
	{"question":"僅か","answers":["わずか"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) only/merely/a little/small quantity"},
	{"question":"働き","answers":["はたらき"],"comment":"(n) work/workings/activity/ability/talent/function/labor/action/operation/movement/motion/conjugation/inflection/achievement"},
	{"question":"働く","answers":["はたらく"],"comment":"(v5k) to work/to labor/to do/to act/to commit/to practise/to work on/to come into play/to be conjugated/to reduce the price"},
	{"question":"像","answers":["ぞう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) statue/image/figure/picture/portrait"},
	{"question":"僕","answers":["ぼく"],"comment":"(n) (male) I/manservant"},
	{"question":"僧","answers":["そう"],"comment":"(n) monk/priest"},
	{"question":"儀式","answers":["ぎしき"],"comment":"(n) ceremony/rite/ritual/service"},
	{"question":"億","answers":["おく"],"comment":"(num) 100,000,000/hundred million"},
	{"question":"優","answers":["ゆう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) actor/superiority/gentleness"},
	{"question":"優しい","answers":["やさしい"],"comment":"(adj) tender/kind/gentle/graceful/affectionate/amiable/suave"},
	{"question":"優れる","answers":["すぐれる"],"comment":"(v1) to surpass/to outstrip/to excel"},
	{"question":"優位","answers":["ゆうい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) predominance/ascendancy/superiority"},
	{"question":"優先","answers":["ゆうせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) preference/priority"},
	{"question":"優勝","answers":["ゆうしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) overall victory/championship"},
	{"question":"優勢","answers":["ゆうせい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) superiority/superior power/predominance/preponderance"},
	{"question":"優秀","answers":["ゆうしゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) superiority/excellence"},
	{"question":"優美","answers":["ゆうび"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) grace/refinement/elegance"},
	{"question":"優越","answers":["ゆうえつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) supremacy/predominance/being superior to"},
	{"question":"儲かる","answers":["もうかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be profitable/to yield a profit"},
	{"question":"儲ける","answers":["もうける"],"comment":"(v1) to get/to earn/to gain/to have (bear, beget) a child"},
	{"question":"元","answers":["もと"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,n-t) (1) origin/original/(2) former"},
	{"question":"元々","answers":["もともと"],"comment":"(adv,adj-no) originally/by nature/from the start"},
	{"question":"元年","answers":["がんねん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) first year (of a specific reign)"},
	{"question":"元日","answers":["がんじつ"],"comment":"(n) New Year's Day"},
	{"question":"元来","answers":["がんらい"],"comment":"(n-adv) originally/primarily/essentially/logically/naturally"},
	{"question":"元気","answers":["げんき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) health(y)/robust/vigor/energy/vitality/vim/stamina/spirit/courage/pep"},
	{"question":"元素","answers":["げんそ"],"comment":"(n) chemical element"},
	{"question":"元首","answers":["げんしゅ"],"comment":"(n) ruler/sovereign"},
	{"question":"兄","answers":["あに"],"comment":"(n) (hum) older brother"},
	{"question":"兄弟","answers":["きょうだい"],"comment":"(n) (hum) siblings"},
	{"question":"充実","answers":["じゅうじつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) fullness/completion/perfection/substantiality/enrichment"},
	{"question":"兆","answers":["きざし"],"comment":"(num) sign/omen/indication/portent/1,000,000,000,000/trillion (American)/billion (British)"},
	{"question":"先","answers":["さき","せん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) the future/priority/precedence/former/previous/old/late"},
	{"question":"先々月","answers":["せんせんげつ"],"comment":"(n-t) month before last"},
	{"question":"先ず","answers":["まず"],"comment":"(adv) first (of all)/to start with/about/almost/hardly (with neg. verb)/anyway/well/now"},
	{"question":"先だって","answers":["せんだって"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) recently/the other day"},
	{"question":"先代","answers":["せんだい"],"comment":"(n) family predecessor/previous age/previous generation"},
	{"question":"先天的","answers":["せんてんてき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) a priori/inborn/innate/inherent/congenital/hereditary"},
	{"question":"先日","answers":["せんじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) the other day/a few days ago"},
	{"question":"先月","answers":["せんげつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) last month"},
	{"question":"先生","answers":["せんせい"],"comment":"(n) teacher/master/doctor"},
	{"question":"先着","answers":["せんちゃく"],"comment":"(n) first arrival"},
	{"question":"先祖","answers":["せんぞ"],"comment":"(n) ancestor"},
	{"question":"先程","answers":["さきほど"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) some time ago"},
	{"question":"先端","answers":["せんたん"],"comment":"(n) pointed end/tip/fine point/spearhead/cusp/vanguard/advanced/leading edge"},
	{"question":"先行","answers":["せんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) preceding/going first"},
	{"question":"先輩","answers":["せんぱい"],"comment":"(n) senior (at work or school)/superior/elder/older graduate/progenitor/old-timer"},
	{"question":"先週","answers":["せんしゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) last week/the week before"},
	{"question":"先頭","answers":["せんとう"],"comment":"(n) head/lead/vanguard/first"},
	{"question":"光","answers":["ひかり"],"comment":"(n) light"},
	{"question":"光る","answers":["ひかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to shine/to glitter/to be bright"},
	{"question":"光景","answers":["こうけい"],"comment":"(n) scene/spectacle"},
	{"question":"光沢","answers":["こうたく"],"comment":"(n) brilliance/polish/lustre/glossy finish (of photographs)"},
	{"question":"光熱費","answers":["こうねつひ"],"comment":"(n) cost of fuel and light"},
	{"question":"光線","answers":["こうせん"],"comment":"(n) beam/light ray"},
	{"question":"克服","answers":["こくふく"],"comment":"(n) subjugation/conquest"},
	{"question":"免れる","answers":["まぬがれる"],"comment":"(v1) to escape from/to be rescued from/to avoid/to evade/to avert/to elude/to be exempted/to be relieved from pain/to get rid of"},
	{"question":"免税","answers":["めんぜい"],"comment":"(n,vs) tax exemption/duty exemption"},
	{"question":"免許","answers":["めんきょ"],"comment":"(n) license/permit/licence/certificate"},
	{"question":"免除","answers":["めんじょ"],"comment":"(n) exemption/exoneration/discharge"},
	{"question":"兎","answers":["うさぎ"],"comment":"(n) rabbit/hare/cony"},
	{"question":"児童","answers":["じどう"],"comment":"(n) children/juvenile"},
	{"question":"党","answers":["とう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) party (political)"},
	{"question":"入る","answers":["はいる"],"comment":"(v5r) to enter/to break into/to join/to enroll/to contain/to hold/to accommodate/to have (an income of)"},
	{"question":"入れる","answers":["いれる"],"comment":"(v1) to put in/to take in/to bring in/to let in/to admit/to introduce/to commit (to prison)/to usher in/to insert/to set (jewels)/to employ/to listen to/to tolerate/to comprehend/to include/to pay (interest)/to cast (votes)"},
	{"question":"入れ物","answers":["いれもの"],"comment":"(n) container/case/receptacle"},
	{"question":"入口","answers":["いりぐち"],"comment":"(n) entrance/gate/approach/mouth"},
	{"question":"入場","answers":["にゅうじょう"],"comment":"(n) entrance/admission/entering"},
	{"question":"入学","answers":["にゅうがく"],"comment":"(n) entry to school or university/matriculation"},
	{"question":"入手","answers":["にゅうしゅ"],"comment":"(n,vs) obtaining/coming to hand"},
	{"question":"入浴","answers":["にゅうよく"],"comment":"(n,vs) bathe/bathing"},
	{"question":"入社","answers":["にゅうしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) entry to a company"},
	{"question":"入賞","answers":["にゅうしょう"],"comment":"(n) winning a prize or place (in a contest)"},
	{"question":"入院","answers":["にゅういん"],"comment":"(n,vs) hospitalization"},
	{"question":"全","answers":["ぜん"],"comment":"(n,pref) all/whole/entire/complete/overall/pan"},
	{"question":"全く","answers":["まったく"],"comment":"(adv) really/truly/entirely/completely/wholly/perfectly/indeed"},
	{"question":"全て","answers":["すべて"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n) all/the whole/entirely/in general/wholly"},
	{"question":"全体","answers":["ぜんたい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) whole/entirety/whatever (is the matter)"},
	{"question":"全力","answers":["ぜんりょく"],"comment":"(n) all one's power/whole energy"},
	{"question":"全員","answers":["ぜんいん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) all members (unanimity)/all hands/the whole crew"},
	{"question":"全国","answers":["ぜんこく"],"comment":"(n) country-wide/nation-wide/whole country/national"},
	{"question":"全快","answers":["ぜんかい"],"comment":"(n) complete recovery of health"},
	{"question":"全滅","answers":["ぜんめつ"],"comment":"(n) annihilation"},
	{"question":"全然","answers":["ぜんぜん"],"comment":"(adv) (1) wholly/entirely/completely/(2) not at all (with neg. verb)"},
	{"question":"全盛","answers":["ぜんせい"],"comment":"(n) height of prosperity"},
	{"question":"全般","answers":["ぜんぱん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) (the) whole/universal/wholly/general"},
	{"question":"全身","answers":["ぜんしん"],"comment":"(n) the whole body/full-length (portrait)"},
	{"question":"全部","answers":["ぜんぶ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) all/entire/whole/altogether"},
	{"question":"全集","answers":["ぜんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) complete works"},
	{"question":"八","answers":["はち"],"comment":"(num) eight"},
	{"question":"八つ","answers":["やっつ"],"comment":"(num) eight"},
	{"question":"八日","answers":["ようか"],"comment":"(n) eight days/the eighth (day of the month)"},
	{"question":"八百屋","answers":["やおや"],"comment":"(n) greengrocer"},
	{"question":"公","answers":["おおやけ"],"comment":"(n,suf) prince/lord/duke/public/daimyo/companion/subordinate"},
	{"question":"公共","answers":["こうきょう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) public/community/public service/society/communal"},
	{"question":"公務","answers":["こうむ"],"comment":"(n) official business/public business"},
	{"question":"公務員","answers":["こうむいん"],"comment":"(n) government worker/public (civil) servant"},
	{"question":"公募","answers":["こうぼ"],"comment":"(n) public appeal/public contribution"},
	{"question":"公団","answers":["こうだん"],"comment":"(n) public corporation"},
	{"question":"公園","answers":["こうえん"],"comment":"(n) (public) park"},
	{"question":"公害","answers":["こうがい"],"comment":"(n) public nuisance/pollution"},
	{"question":"公平","answers":["こうへい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) fairness/impartial/justice"},
	{"question":"公式","answers":["こうしき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) formula/formality/official"},
	{"question":"公正","answers":["こうせい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) justice/fairness/impartiality"},
	{"question":"公演","answers":["こうえん"],"comment":"(n) public performance"},
	{"question":"公然","answers":["こうぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) open (e.g. secret)/public/official"},
	{"question":"公用","answers":["こうよう"],"comment":"(n) government business/public use/public expense"},
	{"question":"公立","answers":["こうりつ"],"comment":"(n) public (institution)"},
	{"question":"公衆","answers":["こうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) the public"},
	{"question":"公表","answers":["こうひょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) official announcement/proclamation"},
	{"question":"公認","answers":["こうにん"],"comment":"(n) official recognition/authorization/licence/accreditation"},
	{"question":"六","answers":["ろく"],"comment":"(num) six"},
	{"question":"六つ","answers":["むっつ"],"comment":"(num) six"},
	{"question":"六日","answers":["むいか"],"comment":"six days/sixth (day of month)"},
	{"question":"共に","answers":["ともに"],"comment":"(adv,vs) sharing with/participate in/both/alike/together/along with/with/including"},
	{"question":"共働き","answers":["ともばたらき"],"comment":"(n) dual income"},
	{"question":"共同","answers":["きょうどう"],"comment":"(n) cooperation/association/collaboration/joint"},
	{"question":"共和","answers":["きょうわ"],"comment":"(n) republicanism/cooperation"},
	{"question":"共存","answers":["きょうぞん"],"comment":"(n) coexistence"},
	{"question":"共学","answers":["きょうがく"],"comment":"(n) coeducation"},
	{"question":"共感","answers":["きょうかん"],"comment":"(n) sympathy/response"},
	{"question":"共稼ぎ","answers":["ともかせぎ"],"comment":"(n) working together/(husband and wife) earning a living together"},
	{"question":"共通","answers":["きょうつう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n,vs) commonness/community"},
	{"question":"共鳴","answers":["きょうめい"],"comment":"(n) resonance/sympathy"},
	{"question":"兵器","answers":["へいき"],"comment":"(n) arms/weapons/ordinance"},
	{"question":"兵士","answers":["へいし"],"comment":"(n) soldier"},
	{"question":"兵隊","answers":["へいたい"],"comment":"(n) soldier/sailor"},
	{"question":"具える","answers":["そなえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be furnished with"},
	{"question":"具わる","answers":["そなわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be furnished with/to be endowed with/to possess/to be among/to be one of/to be possessed of"},
	{"question":"具体","answers":["ぐたい"],"comment":"(n) concrete/tangible/material"},
	{"question":"具合","answers":["ぐあい"],"comment":"(n) condition/state/manner/health"},
	{"question":"典型","answers":["てんけい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) type/pattern/archetypal"},
	{"question":"兼ねる","answers":["かねる"],"comment":"(suf,v1) to hold (position)/to serve/to be unable/to be beyond one's ability/to combine with/to use with/cannot/to hesitate to/to be impatient"},
	{"question":"兼業","answers":["けんぎょう"],"comment":"(n) side line/second business"},
	{"question":"兼用","answers":["けんよう"],"comment":"(n) multi-use/combined use/combination/serving two purposes"},
	{"question":"内","answers":["うち"],"comment":"(n) inside"},
	{"question":"内乱","answers":["ないらん"],"comment":"(n) civil war/insurrection/rebellion/domestic conflict"},
	{"question":"内容","answers":["ないよう"],"comment":"(n) subject/contents/matter/substance/detail/import"},
	{"question":"内心","answers":["ないしん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) innermost thoughts/real intention/inmost heart/one's mind/in the heart"},
	{"question":"内科","answers":["ないか"],"comment":"(n) internist clinic/internal medicine"},
	{"question":"内緒","answers":["ないしょ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) secrecy/privacy/secret/internal evidence/one's circumstances"},
	{"question":"内線","answers":["ないせん"],"comment":"(n) phone extension/indoor wiring/inner line"},
	{"question":"内蔵","answers":["ないぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) involvement/internal (e.g. disk)"},
	{"question":"内訳","answers":["うちわけ"],"comment":"(n) the items/breakdown/classification"},
	{"question":"内部","answers":["ないぶ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) interior/inside/internal"},
	{"question":"内閣","answers":["ないかく"],"comment":"(n) cabinet/(government) ministry"},
	{"question":"内陸","answers":["ないりく"],"comment":"(n) inland"},
	{"question":"円","answers":["えん","まる"],"comment":"(n) circle/money"},
	{"question":"円い","answers":["まるい"],"comment":"(adj) round/circular/spherical"},
	{"question":"円周","answers":["えんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) circumference"},
	{"question":"円満","answers":["えんまん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) perfection/harmony/peace/smoothness/completeness/satisfaction/integrity"},
	{"question":"円滑","answers":["えんかつ"],"comment":"(ik) (adj-na,n) harmony/smoothness"},
	{"question":"再び","answers":["ふたたび"],"comment":"(adv) again/once more/a second time"},
	{"question":"再三","answers":["さいさん"],"comment":"(adv,n) again and again/repeatedly"},
	{"question":"再会","answers":["さいかい"],"comment":"(n) another meeting/meeting again/reunion"},
	{"question":"再建","answers":["さいけん"],"comment":"(n) (temple or shrine) rebuilding"},
	{"question":"再来年","answers":["さらいねん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) year after next"},
	{"question":"再来月","answers":["さらいげつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) month after next"},
	{"question":"再来週","answers":["さらいしゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) week after next"},
	{"question":"再現","answers":["さいげん"],"comment":"(n) reappearance/reproduction/return/revival"},
	{"question":"再生","answers":["さいせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) playback/regeneration/resuscitation/return to life/rebirth/reincarnation/narrow escape/reclamation/regrowth"},
	{"question":"再発","answers":["さいはつ"],"comment":"(n) return/relapse/reoccurrence"},
	{"question":"冒険","answers":["ぼうけん"],"comment":"(n) risk/venture/adventure"},
	{"question":"冒頭","answers":["ぼうとう"],"comment":"(adv,n) beginning/start/outset"},
	{"question":"冗談","answers":["じょうだん"],"comment":"(n) jest/joke"},
	{"question":"写し","answers":["うつし"],"comment":"(n) copy/duplicate/facsimile/transcript"},
	{"question":"写す","answers":["うつす"],"comment":"(v5s) to film/to transcribe/to duplicate/to reproduce/to trace/to describe/to picture/to photograph/to imitate"},
	{"question":"写る","answers":["うつる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be photographed/to be projected"},
	{"question":"写生","answers":["しゃせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) sketching/drawing from nature/portrayal/description"},
	{"question":"写真","answers":["しゃしん"],"comment":"(n) photograph"},
	{"question":"冠","answers":["かんむり"],"comment":"(n,vs) crown/diadem/first/best/peerless/cap/naming/designating/initiating on coming of age/top character radical"},
	{"question":"冬","answers":["ふゆ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) winter"},
	{"question":"冬眠","answers":["とうみん"],"comment":"(n,vs) hibernation/winter sleep"},
	{"question":"冴える","answers":["さえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be clear/to be serene/to be cold/to be skillful"},
	{"question":"冷える","answers":["ひえる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to grow cold/to get chilly/to cool down"},
	{"question":"冷たい","answers":["つめたい"],"comment":"(adj) cold (to the touch)/chilly/icy/freezing/coldhearted"},
	{"question":"冷ます","answers":["さます"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to cool/to dampen/to let cool/to throw a damper on/to spoil"},
	{"question":"冷める","answers":["さめる"],"comment":"(v1) to become cool/to wear off/to abate/to subside/to dampen/to cool down (interest)/to come down (fever)"},
	{"question":"冷やかす","answers":["ひやかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to banter/to make fun of/to jeer at/to cool/to refrigerate"},
	{"question":"冷やす","answers":["ひやす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to cool/to refrigerate"},
	{"question":"冷凍","answers":["れいとう"],"comment":"(n) freezing/cold storage/refrigeration"},
	{"question":"冷房","answers":["れいぼう"],"comment":"(n) cooling/air-conditioning"},
	{"question":"冷淡","answers":["れいたん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) coolness/indifference"},
	{"question":"冷蔵","answers":["れいぞう"],"comment":"(n) cold storage/refrigeration"},
	{"question":"冷蔵庫","answers":["れいぞうこ"],"comment":"(n) refrigerator"},
	{"question":"冷酷","answers":["れいこく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cruelty/coldheartedness/relentless/ruthless"},
	{"question":"冷静","answers":["れいせい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) calm/composure/coolness/serenity"},
	{"question":"凌ぐ","answers":["しのぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to outdo/to surpass/to endure/to keep out (rain)/to stave off/to tide over/to pull through/to defy/to slight/to excel/to eclipse"},
	{"question":"凍える","answers":["こごえる"],"comment":"(v1) to freeze/to be chilled/to be frozen"},
	{"question":"凍る","answers":["こおる"],"comment":"(v5r) to freeze/to be frozen over/to congeal"},
	{"question":"凝らす","answers":["こらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to concentrate/to devote/to apply/to strain/to rack"},
	{"question":"凝る","answers":["こる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stiffen/to harden"},
	{"question":"几帳面","answers":["きちょうめん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) methodical/punctual/steady"},
	{"question":"処分","answers":["しょぶん"],"comment":"(n,vs) disposal/dealing/punishment"},
	{"question":"処理","answers":["しょり"],"comment":"(n,vs) processing/dealing with/treatment/disposition/disposal"},
	{"question":"処置","answers":["しょち"],"comment":"(n,vs) treatment"},
	{"question":"処罰","answers":["しょばつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) punishment"},
	{"question":"凶作","answers":["きょうさく"],"comment":"(n) bad harvest/poor crop"},
	{"question":"凸凹","answers":["でこぼこ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unevenness/roughness/ruggedness"},
	{"question":"凹む","answers":["へこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be dented/to be indented/to yield to/to give/to sink/to collapse/to cave in/to be snubbed"},
	{"question":"出かける","answers":["でかける"],"comment":"(v1) to depart/to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing)/to set out/to start/to be going out"},
	{"question":"出くわす","answers":["でくわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to happen to meet/to come across"},
	{"question":"出す","answers":["だす"],"comment":"(v5s) to put out/to send"},
	{"question":"出る","answers":["でる"],"comment":"(v1) to appear/to come forth/to leave"},
	{"question":"出世","answers":["しゅっせ"],"comment":"(n) promotion/successful career/eminence"},
	{"question":"出会い","answers":["であい"],"comment":"(n) meeting/rendezvous/encounter"},
	{"question":"出会う","answers":["であう"],"comment":"(v5u) to meet by chance/to come across/to happen to encounter/to hold a rendezvous/to have a date"},
	{"question":"出入り","answers":["でいり"],"comment":"(n) in and out/coming and going/free association/income and expenditure/debits and credit"},
	{"question":"出入口","answers":["でいりぐち"],"comment":"(n) exit and entrance"},
	{"question":"出動","answers":["しゅつどう"],"comment":"(n) sailing/marching/going out"},
	{"question":"出勤","answers":["しゅっきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) going to work/at work"},
	{"question":"出口","answers":["でぐち"],"comment":"(n) exit/gateway/way out/outlet/leak/vent"},
	{"question":"出合い","answers":["であい"],"comment":"(n) an encounter"},
	{"question":"出合う","answers":["であう"],"comment":"(v5u) to meet by chance/to come across/to happen to encounter/to hold a rendezvous/to have a date"},
	{"question":"出品","answers":["しゅっぴん"],"comment":"(n) exhibit/display"},
	{"question":"出場","answers":["しゅつじょう"],"comment":"(n) one's turn/place of projection/production center"},
	{"question":"出席","answers":["しゅっせき"],"comment":"(n,vs) attendance/presence"},
	{"question":"出張","answers":["しゅっちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) official tour/business trip"},
	{"question":"出掛ける","answers":["でかける"],"comment":"(v1) to depart/to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing)/to set out/to start/to be going out"},
	{"question":"出来るだけ","answers":["できるだけ"],"comment":"if at all possible"},
	{"question":"出来上がり","answers":["できあがり"],"comment":"(n) be finished/ready/made for/cut out"},
	{"question":"出来上がる","answers":["できあがる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to be finished/to be ready/by definition/(2) to be very drunk"},
	{"question":"出来事","answers":["できごと"],"comment":"(n) incident/affair/happening/event"},
	{"question":"出演","answers":["しゅつえん"],"comment":"(n) performance/stage appearance"},
	{"question":"出版","answers":["しゅっぱん"],"comment":"(n,vs) publication"},
	{"question":"出現","answers":["しゅつげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) appearance/arrival/make one's appearance"},
	{"question":"出生","answers":["しゅっしょう","しゅっせい"],"comment":"(n) birth"},
	{"question":"出産","answers":["しゅっさん"],"comment":"(n) (child)birth/delivery/production (of goods)"},
	{"question":"出発","answers":["しゅっぱつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) departure"},
	{"question":"出直し","answers":["でなおし"],"comment":"(n) adjustment/touch up"},
	{"question":"出社","answers":["しゅっしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) arrival (in a country, at work, etc.)"},
	{"question":"出血","answers":["しゅっけつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) bleeding/haemorrhage"},
	{"question":"出費","answers":["しゅっぴ"],"comment":"(n) expenses/disbursements"},
	{"question":"出身","answers":["しゅっしん"],"comment":"(n) graduate from/come from"},
	{"question":"出迎え","answers":["でむかえ"],"comment":"(n) meeting/reception"},
	{"question":"出迎える","answers":["でむかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to meet/to greet"},
	{"question":"出題","answers":["しゅつだい"],"comment":"(n) proposing a question"},
	{"question":"刀","answers":["かたな"],"comment":"(n) sword/saber/knife/engraving tool"},
	{"question":"刃","answers":["は"],"comment":"(n) blade/sword"},
	{"question":"分","answers":["ぶ","ぶん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,pref) dividing/part/segment/share/ration/rate/degree/one's lot/one's status/relation/duty/kind/lot/branch/detached"},
	{"question":"分かれる","answers":["わかれる"],"comment":"(v1) to branch off/to diverge from/to fork/to split/to dispense/to scatter/to divide into"},
	{"question":"分ける","answers":["わける"],"comment":"(v1) to divide/to separate"},
	{"question":"分る","answers":["わかる"],"comment":"(io) (v5r) to be understood"},
	{"question":"分子","answers":["ぶんし"],"comment":"(n) numerator/molecule"},
	{"question":"分布","answers":["ぶんぷ"],"comment":"(n) distribution"},
	{"question":"分担","answers":["ぶんたん"],"comment":"(n,vs) apportionment/sharing"},
	{"question":"分散","answers":["ぶんさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) dispersion/decentralization/variance (statistics)"},
	{"question":"分数","answers":["ぶんすう"],"comment":"(n) fraction (in math)"},
	{"question":"分析","answers":["ぶんせき"],"comment":"(n,vs) analysis"},
	{"question":"分業","answers":["ぶんぎょう"],"comment":"(n) division of labor/specialization/assembly-line production"},
	{"question":"分母","answers":["ぶんぼ"],"comment":"(n) denominator"},
	{"question":"分裂","answers":["ぶんれつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) split/division/break up"},
	{"question":"分解","answers":["ぶんかい"],"comment":"(n) analysis/disassembly"},
	{"question":"分配","answers":["ぶんぱい"],"comment":"(n) division/sharing"},
	{"question":"分野","answers":["ぶんや"],"comment":"(n) field/sphere/realm/division/branch"},
	{"question":"分量","answers":["ぶんりょう"],"comment":"(n) amount/quantity"},
	{"question":"分離","answers":["ぶんり"],"comment":"(n) separation/detachment/segregation/isolation"},
	{"question":"分類","answers":["ぶんるい"],"comment":"(n,vs) classification"},
	{"question":"切ない","answers":["せつない"],"comment":"(adj) painful/trying/oppressive/suffocating"},
	{"question":"切り","answers":["きり"],"comment":"(n,suf) limits/end/bounds/period/place to leave off/closing sentence/all there is/only/since"},
	{"question":"切る","answers":["きる"],"comment":"(suf,v5r) to cut/to chop/to hash/to carve/to saw/to clip/to shear/to slice/to strip/to fell/to cut down/to punch/to sever (connections)/to pause/to break off/to disconnect/to turn off/to hang up/to cross (a street)/to discount/to sell below cost/to shake (water) off/to finish/to be through/to complete"},
	{"question":"切れ","answers":["きれ"],"comment":"(n) cloth/piece/cut/chop/strip/slice/scrap/counter for such"},
	{"question":"切れる","answers":["きれる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to cut well/to be sharp/(2) to break (off)/to snap/to wear out/(3) to be injured/(4) to burst/to collapse/(5) to be disconnected/to be out of/to expire/to sever (connections) with/(6) to be shrewd/to have a sharp mind"},
	{"question":"切れ目","answers":["きれめ"],"comment":"(n) break/pause/gap/end/rift/interruption/cut/section/notch/incision/end (of a task)"},
	{"question":"切実","answers":["せつじつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) compelling/serious/severe/acute/earnest/pressing/urgent"},
	{"question":"切手","answers":["きって"],"comment":"man of ability"},
	{"question":"切替","answers":["きりかえ"],"comment":"(n) exchange/conversion/replacement/switching (to)/switchover"},
	{"question":"切符","answers":["きっぷ"],"comment":"(n) ticket"},
	{"question":"切開","answers":["せっかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) clearing (land)/opening up/cutting through"},
	{"question":"刈る","answers":["かる"],"comment":"(v5r) to cut (hair)/to mow (grass)/to harvest/to clip/to shear/to reap/to trim/to prune"},
	{"question":"刊行","answers":["かんこう"],"comment":"(n) publication/issue"},
	{"question":"刑","answers":["けい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,vs) penalty/sentence/punishment"},
	{"question":"刑事","answers":["けいじ"],"comment":"(n) criminal case/(police) detective"},
	{"question":"刑罰","answers":["けいばつ"],"comment":"(n) judgement/penalty/punishment"},
	{"question":"列","answers":["れつ"],"comment":"(n) queue/line/row"},
	{"question":"列島","answers":["れっとう"],"comment":"(n) chain of islands"},
	{"question":"列車","answers":["れっしゃ"],"comment":"(n) train (ordinary)"},
	{"question":"初めて","answers":["はじめて"],"comment":"(adv,n) for the first time"},
	{"question":"初めに","answers":["はじめに"],"comment":"(expr) to begin with/first of all"},
	{"question":"初旬","answers":["しょじゅん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) first 10 days of the month"},
	{"question":"初歩","answers":["しょほ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) elements/rudiments/ABC's of.."},
	{"question":"初版","answers":["しょはん"],"comment":"(n) first edition"},
	{"question":"初級","answers":["しょきゅう"],"comment":"(n) elementary level"},
	{"question":"初耳","answers":["はつみみ"],"comment":"(n) something heard for the first time"},
	{"question":"判","answers":["はん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) size (of paper or books)"},
	{"question":"判事","answers":["はんじ"],"comment":"(n) judge/judiciary"},
	{"question":"判子","answers":["はんこ"],"comment":"(n) seal (used for signature)"},
	{"question":"判定","answers":["はんてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) judgement/decision/award/verdict"},
	{"question":"判断","answers":["はんだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) judgement/decision/adjudication/conclusion/decipherment/divination"},
	{"question":"判決","answers":["はんけつ"],"comment":"(n) judicial decision/judgement/sentence/decree"},
	{"question":"別","answers":["べつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,n-suf) distinction/difference/different/another/particular/separate/extra/exception"},
	{"question":"別々","answers":["べつべつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) separately/individually"},
	{"question":"別に","answers":["べつに"],"comment":"(adv) (not) particularly/nothing"},
	{"question":"別れ","answers":["わかれ"],"comment":"(n) parting/separation/farewell/(lateral) branch/fork/offshoot/division/section"},
	{"question":"別れる","answers":["わかれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be divided/to part from/to separate/to bid farewell"},
	{"question":"別荘","answers":["べっそう"],"comment":"(n) holiday house/villa"},
	{"question":"利口","answers":["りこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) clever/shrewd/bright/sharp/wise/intelligent"},
	{"question":"利子","answers":["りし"],"comment":"(n) interest (bank)"},
	{"question":"利害","answers":["りがい"],"comment":"(n) advantages and disadvantages/interest"},
	{"question":"利息","answers":["りそく"],"comment":"(n) interest (bank)"},
	{"question":"利潤","answers":["りじゅん"],"comment":"(n) profit/returns"},
	{"question":"利点","answers":["りてん"],"comment":"(n) advantage/point in favor"},
	{"question":"利用","answers":["りよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) use/utilization/application"},
	{"question":"利益","answers":["りえき"],"comment":"(n) profits/gains/(political, economic) interest"},
	{"question":"到底","answers":["とうてい"],"comment":"(adv) (cannot) possibly"},
	{"question":"到着","answers":["とうちゃく"],"comment":"(n,vs) arrival"},
	{"question":"到達","answers":["とうたつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) reaching/attaining/arrival"},
	{"question":"制する","answers":["せいする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to control/to command/to get the better of"},
	{"question":"制作","answers":["せいさく"],"comment":"(n,vs) work (film, book)"},
	{"question":"制定","answers":["せいてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) enactment/establishment/creation"},
	{"question":"制度","answers":["せいど"],"comment":"(n) system/institution/organization"},
	{"question":"制服","answers":["せいふく"],"comment":"(n) uniform"},
	{"question":"制約","answers":["せいやく"],"comment":"(n,vs) limitation/restriction/condition/constraints"},
	{"question":"制裁","answers":["せいさい"],"comment":"(n) restraint/sanctions/punishment"},
	{"question":"制限","answers":["せいげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) restriction/restraint/limitation"},
	{"question":"刷る","answers":["する"],"comment":"(v5r) to print"},
	{"question":"券","answers":["けん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) ticket/coupon/bond/certificate"},
	{"question":"刺さる","answers":["ささる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stick/to be stuck"},
	{"question":"刺す","answers":["さす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pierce/to stab/to prick/to thrust/to bite/to sting/to pin down/to stitch/to put (a runner) out/to pole (a boat)/to catch (with a line)/to stick"},
	{"question":"刺激","answers":["しげき"],"comment":"(n,vs) stimulus/impetus/incentive/excitement/irritation/encouragement/motivation"},
	{"question":"刺繍","answers":["ししゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) embroidery"},
	{"question":"刺身","answers":["さしみ"],"comment":"(n) sliced raw fish"},
	{"question":"刻む","answers":["きざむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to mince/to carve/to engrave/to cut fine/to chop up/to hash/to chisel/to notch"},
	{"question":"剃る","answers":["そる"],"comment":"(v5r) to shave"},
	{"question":"剃刀","answers":["かみそり"],"comment":"(n) razor"},
	{"question":"削る","answers":["けずる"],"comment":"(v5r) to cut down little by little/to take a percentage"},
	{"question":"削減","answers":["さくげん"],"comment":"(n) cut/reduction/curtailment"},
	{"question":"削除","answers":["さくじょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) elimination/cancellation/deletion/erasure"},
	{"question":"前","answers":["まえ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t,suf) (1) before/in front/fore part/ago/previously/(2) head (of a line)/(3) in the presence of/lady (so-and-so)/(4) (five minutes) to/(5) helping/portion"},
	{"question":"前もって","answers":["まえもって"],"comment":"(adv) in advance/beforehand/previously"},
	{"question":"前例","answers":["ぜんれい"],"comment":"(n) precedent"},
	{"question":"前売","answers":["まえうり"],"comment":"(n) advance sale/booking"},
	{"question":"前後","answers":["ぜんご"],"comment":"(n-adv,suf) around/throughout/front and back/before and behind/before and after/about that (time)/longitudinal/context/nearly/approximately"},
	{"question":"前提","answers":["ぜんてい"],"comment":"(n) preamble/premise/reason/prerequisite"},
	{"question":"前置き","answers":["まえおき"],"comment":"(n) preface/introduction"},
	{"question":"前者","answers":["ぜんしゃ"],"comment":"(n) the former"},
	{"question":"前途","answers":["ぜんと"],"comment":"(n) future prospects/outlook/the journey ahead"},
	{"question":"前進","answers":["ぜんしん"],"comment":"(n) advance/drive/progress"},
	{"question":"剥く","answers":["むく"],"comment":"(v5k) to peel/to skin/to pare/to hull"},
	{"question":"剥ぐ","answers":["はぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to tear off/to peel off/to rip off/to strip off/to skin/to flay/to disrobe/to deprive of"},
	{"question":"剥げる","answers":["はげる"],"comment":"(v1) to come off/to be worn off/to fade/to discolor"},
	{"question":"剥す","answers":["はがす"],"comment":"(io) (v5s) to tear off/to peel off/to rip off/to strip off/to skin/to flay/to disrobe/to deprive of/to detach/to disconnect"},
	{"question":"副詞","answers":["ふくし"],"comment":"(n) adverb"},
	{"question":"割る","answers":["わる"],"comment":"(v5r) to divide/to cut/to break/to halve/to separate/to split/to rip/to crack/to smash/to dilute"},
	{"question":"割れる","answers":["われる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to break/to split/to cleave/to fissure/to be smashed/to crack/to be torn"},
	{"question":"割合","answers":["わりあい"],"comment":"(adv,n) (1) rate/ratio/percentage/proportion/(2) comparatively/(3) contrary to expectations"},
	{"question":"割引","answers":["わりびき"],"comment":"(n,suf) discount/reduction/rebate/tenths discounted"},
	{"question":"割当","answers":["わりあて"],"comment":"(n) allotment/assignment/allocation/quota/rationing"},
	{"question":"割算","answers":["わりざん"],"comment":"(n) division (math)"},
	{"question":"割込む","answers":["わりこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to cut in/to thrust oneself into/to wedge oneself in/to muscle in on/to interrupt/to disturb"},
	{"question":"創作","answers":["そうさく"],"comment":"(n) production/literary creation/work"},
	{"question":"創刊","answers":["そうかん"],"comment":"(n,vs) launching (e.g. newspaper)/first issue"},
	{"question":"創立","answers":["そうりつ"],"comment":"(n) establishment/founding/organization"},
	{"question":"創造","answers":["そうぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) creation"},
	{"question":"劇","answers":["げき"],"comment":"(n) drama/play"},
	{"question":"劇団","answers":["げきだん"],"comment":"(n) troupe/theatrical company"},
	{"question":"劇場","answers":["げきじょう"],"comment":"(n) theatre/playhouse"},
	{"question":"力","answers":["ちから"],"comment":"(n-suf) strength/power"},
	{"question":"力強い","answers":["ちからづよい"],"comment":"(adj) reassuring/emboldened"},
	{"question":"功績","answers":["こうせき"],"comment":"(n) achievements/merit/meritorious service/meritorious deed"},
	{"question":"加える","answers":["くわえる"],"comment":"(v1) to append/to sum up/to add (up)/to include/to increase/to inflict"},
	{"question":"加わる","answers":["くわわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to join in/to accede to/to increase/to gain in (influence)"},
	{"question":"加入","answers":["かにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) becoming a member/joining/entry/admission/subscription/affiliation/adherence/signing"},
	{"question":"加味","answers":["かみ"],"comment":"(n) seasoning/flavoring"},
	{"question":"加工","answers":["かこう"],"comment":"(n) manufacturing/processing/treatment"},
	{"question":"加減","answers":["かげん"],"comment":"(n) addition and subtraction/allowance for/degree/extent/measure/condition/seasoning/flavor/moderation/adjustment/influence (of the weather)/state of health/chance"},
	{"question":"加熱","answers":["かねつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) heating"},
	{"question":"加速","answers":["かそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) acceleration"},
	{"question":"加速度","answers":["かそくど"],"comment":"(n) acceleration"},
	{"question":"劣る","answers":["おとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to fall behind/to be inferior to"},
	{"question":"助かる","answers":["たすかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be saved/to be rescued/to survive/to be helpful"},
	{"question":"助け","answers":["たすけ"],"comment":"(n) assistance"},
	{"question":"助ける","answers":["たすける"],"comment":"(v1) to help/to save/to rescue/to give relief to/to spare (life)/to reinforce/to promote/to abet"},
	{"question":"助動詞","answers":["じょどうし"],"comment":"(n) auxiliary verb"},
	{"question":"助手","answers":["じょしゅ"],"comment":"(n) helper/helpmeet/assistant/tutor"},
	{"question":"助教授","answers":["じょきょうじゅ"],"comment":"(n) assistant professor"},
	{"question":"助言","answers":["じょげん"],"comment":"(n) advice/suggestion"},
	{"question":"助詞","answers":["じょし"],"comment":"(n) (gram) particle/postposition"},
	{"question":"努めて","answers":["つとめて"],"comment":"(adv,exp) make an effort!/work hard!"},
	{"question":"努める","answers":["つとめる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to serve/to fill a post/to serve under/to work (for)/(2) to exert oneself/to endeavor/to be diligent/(3) to play (the part of)"},
	{"question":"努力","answers":["どりょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) great effort/exertion/endeavour/effort"},
	{"question":"励ます","answers":["はげます"],"comment":"(v5s) to encourage/to cheer/to raise (the voice)"},
	{"question":"励む","answers":["はげむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be zealous/to brace oneself/to endeavour/to strive/to make an effort"},
	{"question":"労働","answers":["ろうどう"],"comment":"(n) manual labor/toil/work"},
	{"question":"労力","answers":["ろうりょく"],"comment":"(n) labour/effort/toil/trouble"},
	{"question":"効き目","answers":["ききめ"],"comment":"(n) effect/virtue/efficacy/impression"},
	{"question":"効く","answers":["きく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be effective"},
	{"question":"効力","answers":["こうりょく"],"comment":"(n) effect/efficacy/validity/potency"},
	{"question":"効果","answers":["こうか"],"comment":"(n,adj-no) effect/effectiveness/efficacy/result"},
	{"question":"効率","answers":["こうりつ"],"comment":"(n) efficiency"},
	{"question":"勇ましい","answers":["いさましい"],"comment":"(adj) brave/valiant/gallant/courageous"},
	{"question":"勇敢","answers":["ゆうかん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) bravery/heroism/gallantry"},
	{"question":"勇気","answers":["ゆうき"],"comment":"(n) courage/bravery/valour/nerve/boldness"},
	{"question":"勉強","answers":["べんきょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) study/diligence/discount/reduction"},
	{"question":"動かす","answers":["うごかす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to move/to shift/to set in motion/to operate/to inspire/to rouse/to influence/to mobilize/to deny/to change"},
	{"question":"動き","answers":["うごき"],"comment":"(n) movement/activity/trend/development/change"},
	{"question":"動く","answers":["うごく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) to move/to stir/to shift/to shake/to swing/to operate/to run/to go/to work/to be touched/to be influenced/to waver/to fluctuate/to vary/to change/to be transferred"},
	{"question":"動作","answers":["どうさ"],"comment":"(n) action/movements/motions/bearing/behaviour/manners"},
	{"question":"動力","answers":["どうりょく"],"comment":"(n) power/motive power/dynamic force"},
	{"question":"動向","answers":["どうこう"],"comment":"(n) trend/tendency/movement/attitude"},
	{"question":"動員","answers":["どういん"],"comment":"(n,vs) mobilization"},
	{"question":"動揺","answers":["どうよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) disturbance/unrest/shaking/trembling/pitching/rolling/oscillation/agitation/excitement/commotion"},
	{"question":"動機","answers":["どうき"],"comment":"(n) motive/incentive"},
	{"question":"動物","answers":["どうぶつ"],"comment":"(n) animal"},
	{"question":"動物園","answers":["どうぶつえん"],"comment":"(n) zoo/zoological gardens"},
	{"question":"動的","answers":["どうてき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dynamic/kinetic"},
	{"question":"動詞","answers":["どうし"],"comment":"(n) verb"},
	{"question":"勘","answers":["かん"],"comment":"(n) perception/intuition/the sixth sense"},
	{"question":"勘定","answers":["かんじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) calculation/counting/consideration/reckoning/settlement of an account/allowance"},
	{"question":"勘弁","answers":["かんべん"],"comment":"(n,vs) pardon/forgiveness/forbearance"},
	{"question":"勘違い","answers":["かんちがい"],"comment":"(n,vs) misunderstanding/wrong guess"},
	{"question":"務め","answers":["つとめ"],"comment":"(n) (1) service/duty/business/responsibility/task/(2) Buddhist religious services"},
	{"question":"務める","answers":["つとめる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to serve/to fill a post/to serve under/to work (for)/(2) to exert oneself/to endeavor/to be diligent/(3) to play (the part of)"},
	{"question":"勝ち","answers":["かち"],"comment":"(n) win/victory"},
	{"question":"勝つ","answers":["かつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to win/to gain victory"},
	{"question":"勝る","answers":["まさる"],"comment":"(v5r) to excel/to surpass/to outrival"},
	{"question":"勝利","answers":["しょうり"],"comment":"(n) victory/triumph/conquest/success/win"},
	{"question":"勝手","answers":["かって"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) kitchen/one's own convenience/one's way/selfishness"},
	{"question":"勝手に","answers":["かってに"],"comment":"arbitrarily/of it's own accord/involuntarily/wilfully/as one pleases"},
	{"question":"勝敗","answers":["しょうはい"],"comment":"(n) victory or defeat/issue (of battle)"},
	{"question":"勝負","answers":["しょうぶ"],"comment":"(n,vs) victory or defeat/match/contest/game/bout"},
	{"question":"募る","answers":["つのる"],"comment":"(v5r) to invite/to solicit help, participation, etc"},
	{"question":"募金","answers":["ぼきん"],"comment":"(n) fund-raising/collection of funds"},
	{"question":"募集","answers":["ぼしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) recruiting/taking applications"},
	{"question":"勢い","answers":["いきおい"],"comment":"(adv,n) force/vigor/energy/spirit/life/authority/influence/power/might/impetus/course (of events)/tendency/necessarily"},
	{"question":"勢力","answers":["せいりょく"],"comment":"(n) influence/power/might/strength/potency/force/energy"},
	{"question":"勤め","answers":["つとめ"],"comment":"(n) (1) service/duty/business/responsibility/task/(2) Buddhist religious services"},
	{"question":"勤める","answers":["つとめる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to serve/to fill a post/to serve under/to work (for)/(2) to exert oneself/to endeavor/to be diligent/(3) to play (the part of)"},
	{"question":"勤め先","answers":["つとめさき"],"comment":"(n) place of work"},
	{"question":"勤労","answers":["きんろう"],"comment":"(n) labor/exertion/diligent service"},
	{"question":"勤勉","answers":["きんべん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) industry/diligence"},
	{"question":"勤務","answers":["きんむ"],"comment":"(n,vs) service/duty/work"},
	{"question":"勧める","answers":["すすめる"],"comment":"(v1) to recommend/to advise/to encourage/to offer (wine)"},
	{"question":"勧告","answers":["かんこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) advice/counsel/remonstrance/recommendation"},
	{"question":"勧誘","answers":["かんゆう"],"comment":"(n,vs) invitation/solicitation/canvassing/inducement/persuasion/encouragement"},
	{"question":"勿論","answers":["もちろん"],"comment":"(adv) (uk) of course/certainly/naturally"},
	{"question":"匂い","answers":["におい"],"comment":"(n) odour/scent/smell/stench/fragrance/aroma/perfume"},
	{"question":"匂う","answers":["におう"],"comment":"(v5u,vi) to be fragrant/to smell/to stink/to glow/to be bright"},
	{"question":"包み","answers":["つつみ"],"comment":"(n) bundle/package/parcel/bale"},
	{"question":"包む","answers":["つつむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be engulfed in/to be enveloped by/to wrap up/to tuck in/to pack/to do up/to cover with/to dress in/to conceal"},
	{"question":"包帯","answers":["ほうたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) bandage/dressing"},
	{"question":"包装","answers":["ほうそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) packing/wrapping"},
	{"question":"化ける","answers":["ばける"],"comment":"(v1) to change with age/to spoil from weathering"},
	{"question":"化合","answers":["かごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) chemical combination"},
	{"question":"化学","answers":["かがく"],"comment":"(n) chemistry"},
	{"question":"化石","answers":["かせき"],"comment":"(n) fossil/petrifaction/fossilization"},
	{"question":"化粧","answers":["けしょう"],"comment":"(n) make-up (cosmetic)"},
	{"question":"化繊","answers":["かせん"],"comment":"(n) synthetic fibres"},
	{"question":"北","answers":["きた"],"comment":"north"},
	{"question":"北極","answers":["ほっきょく"],"comment":"(n) North Pole"},
	{"question":"匙","answers":["さじ"],"comment":"(n) spoon"},
	{"question":"匹敵","answers":["ひってき"],"comment":"(n,vs) comparing with/match/rival/equal"},
	{"question":"区分","answers":["くぶん"],"comment":"(n) division/section/demarcation/(traffic) lane/compartment/classification/sorting"},
	{"question":"区切り","answers":["くぎり"],"comment":"(n) an end/a stop/punctuation"},
	{"question":"区切る","answers":["くぎる"],"comment":"(v5r,vt) to punctuate/to cut off/to mark off/to stop/to put an end to"},
	{"question":"区別","answers":["くべつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) distinction/differentiation/classification"},
	{"question":"区域","answers":["くいき"],"comment":"(n) limits/boundary/domain/zone/sphere/territory"},
	{"question":"区画","answers":["くかく"],"comment":"(n) division/section/compartment/boundary/area/block"},
	{"question":"区間","answers":["くかん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) section (of track, etc)"},
	{"question":"医学","answers":["いがく"],"comment":"(n) medical science/medicine"},
	{"question":"医師","answers":["いし"],"comment":"(n) doctor/physician"},
	{"question":"医療","answers":["いりょう"],"comment":"(n) medical care/medical treatment"},
	{"question":"医者","answers":["いしゃ"],"comment":"(n) doctor (medical)"},
	{"question":"医院","answers":["いいん"],"comment":"(n) doctor's office (surgery)/clinic/dispensary"},
	{"question":"十","answers":["じゅう","とお"],"comment":"(num) 10/ten"},
	{"question":"十分","answers":["じゅうぶん"],"comment":"10 minutes"},
	{"question":"十字路","answers":["じゅうじろ"],"comment":"(n) crossroads"},
	{"question":"十日","answers":["とおか"],"comment":"ten days/the tenth (day of the month)"},
	{"question":"千","answers":["せん"],"comment":"thousand/many"},
	{"question":"午前","answers":["ごぜん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) morning/A.M./am"},
	{"question":"午後","answers":["ごご"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) afternoon/p.m./pm"},
	{"question":"半","answers":["はん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n,n-suf) half"},
	{"question":"半ば","answers":["なかば"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) middle/half/semi/halfway/partly"},
	{"question":"半分","answers":["はんぶん"],"comment":"half minute"},
	{"question":"半島","answers":["はんとう"],"comment":"(n) peninsula"},
	{"question":"半径","answers":["はんけい"],"comment":"(n) radius"},
	{"question":"半端","answers":["はんぱ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) remnant/fragment/incomplete set/fraction/odd sum/incompleteness"},
	{"question":"卑しい","answers":["いやしい"],"comment":"(adj) greedy/vulgar/shabby/humble/base/mean/vile"},
	{"question":"卑怯","answers":["ひきょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cowardice/meanness/unfairness"},
	{"question":"卒業","answers":["そつぎょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) graduation"},
	{"question":"卒直","answers":["そっちょく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) frankness/candour/openheartedness"},
	{"question":"協会","answers":["きょうかい"],"comment":"(n) association/society/organization"},
	{"question":"協力","answers":["きょうりょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) cooperation/collaboration"},
	{"question":"協定","answers":["きょうてい"],"comment":"(n) arrangement/pact/agreement"},
	{"question":"協調","answers":["きょうちょう"],"comment":"(n) co-operation/conciliation/harmony/firm (market) tone"},
	{"question":"協議","answers":["きょうぎ"],"comment":"(n,vs) conference/consultation/discussion/negotiation"},
	{"question":"南","answers":["みなみ"],"comment":"(n,vs) South/proceeding south"},
	{"question":"南北","answers":["なんぼく"],"comment":"(n) south and north"},
	{"question":"南極","answers":["なんきょく"],"comment":"(n) south pole/Antarctic"},
	{"question":"南米","answers":["なんべい"],"comment":"(n) South America"},
	{"question":"単なる","answers":["たんなる"],"comment":"(adj-pn) mere/simple/sheer"},
	{"question":"単に","answers":["たんに"],"comment":"(adv,n) simply/merely/only/solely"},
	{"question":"単一","answers":["たんいつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) single/simple/sole/individual/unitory"},
	{"question":"単位","answers":["たんい"],"comment":"(n) unit/denomination/credit (in school)"},
	{"question":"単数","answers":["たんすう"],"comment":"(n) singular (number)"},
	{"question":"単独","answers":["たんどく"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) sole/independence/single/solo (flight)"},
	{"question":"単純","answers":["たんじゅん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) simplicity"},
	{"question":"単語","answers":["たんご"],"comment":"(n) word/vocabulary/(usually) single-character word"},
	{"question":"単調","answers":["たんちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) monotony/monotone/dullness"},
	{"question":"博士","answers":["はかせ"],"comment":"(n) doctorate/PhD"},
	{"question":"博物館","answers":["はくぶつかん"],"comment":"(n) museum"},
	{"question":"占う","answers":["うらなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to forecast/to predict"},
	{"question":"占める","answers":["しめる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to comprise/to account for/to make up (of)/(2) to hold/to occupy"},
	{"question":"占領","answers":["せんりょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) occupation/capture/possession/have a room to oneself"},
	{"question":"印","answers":["しるし"],"comment":"(n) (1) mark/(2) symbol/(3) evidence"},
	{"question":"印刷","answers":["いんさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) printing"},
	{"question":"印象","answers":["いんしょう"],"comment":"(n) impression"},
	{"question":"印鑑","answers":["いんかん"],"comment":"(n) stamp/seal"},
	{"question":"危うい","answers":["あやうい"],"comment":"(adj) dangerous/critical/grave/uncertain/unreliable/limping/narrow/close/watch out!"},
	{"question":"危ない","answers":["あぶない"],"comment":"(adj) dangerous/critical/grave/uncertain/unreliable/limping/narrow/close/watch out!"},
	{"question":"危ぶむ","answers":["あやぶむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to fear/to have misgivings/to be doubtful/to mistrust"},
	{"question":"危害","answers":["きがい"],"comment":"(n) injury/harm/danger"},
	{"question":"危機","answers":["きき"],"comment":"(n) crisis"},
	{"question":"危険","answers":["きけん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) danger/peril/hazard"},
	{"question":"即する","answers":["そくする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to conform to/to agree with/to be adapted to/to be based on"},
	{"question":"即座に","answers":["そくざに"],"comment":"immediately/right away"},
	{"question":"却って","answers":["かえって"],"comment":"(adv) on the contrary/rather/all the more/instead"},
	{"question":"卵","answers":["たまご"],"comment":"(n) (1) egg(s)/spawn/roe/(2) (an expert) in the making"},
	{"question":"卸す","answers":["おろす"],"comment":"(v5s) to sell wholesale/grated (vegetables)"},
	{"question":"厄介","answers":["やっかい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) trouble/burden/care/bother/worry/dependence/support/kindness/obligation"},
	{"question":"厚い","answers":["あつい"],"comment":"(adj) cordial/kind/warm(hearted)/thick/deep"},
	{"question":"厚かましい","answers":["あつかましい"],"comment":"(adj) impudent/shameless/brazen"},
	{"question":"原","answers":["はら"],"comment":"(n) field/plain/prairie/tundra/moor/wilderness"},
	{"question":"原っぱ","answers":["はらっぱ"],"comment":"(n) open field/empty lot/plain"},
	{"question":"原作","answers":["げんさく"],"comment":"(n) original work"},
	{"question":"原典","answers":["げんてん"],"comment":"(n) original (text)"},
	{"question":"原則","answers":["げんそく"],"comment":"(n) principle/general rule"},
	{"question":"原因","answers":["げんいん"],"comment":"(n) cause/origin/source"},
	{"question":"原型","answers":["げんけい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) prototype/model/pattern/archetypal"},
	{"question":"原始","answers":["げんし"],"comment":"(n) origin/primeval"},
	{"question":"原子","answers":["げんし"],"comment":"(n) atom"},
	{"question":"原形","answers":["げんけい"],"comment":"(n) original form/base form"},
	{"question":"原文","answers":["げんぶん"],"comment":"(n) the text/original"},
	{"question":"原料","answers":["げんりょう"],"comment":"(n) raw materials"},
	{"question":"原書","answers":["げんしょ"],"comment":"(n) original document"},
	{"question":"原油","answers":["げんゆ"],"comment":"(n) crude oil"},
	{"question":"原点","answers":["げんてん"],"comment":"(n) origin (coordinates)/starting point"},
	{"question":"原爆","answers":["げんばく"],"comment":"(n) atomic bomb"},
	{"question":"原理","answers":["げんり"],"comment":"(n) principle/theory/fundamental truth"},
	{"question":"原産","answers":["げんさん"],"comment":"(n) place of origin/habitat"},
	{"question":"原稿","answers":["げんこう"],"comment":"(n) manuscript/copy"},
	{"question":"厳か","answers":["おごそか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) austere/majestic/dignified/stately/awful/impressive"},
	{"question":"厳しい","answers":["きびしい"],"comment":"(adj) severe/strict/stern/austere/grave/solemn/majestic/intense (cold)"},
	{"question":"厳密","answers":["げんみつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) strict/close"},
	{"question":"厳重","answers":["げんじゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) strict/rigour/severe/firm/strong/secure"},
	{"question":"去る","answers":["さる"],"comment":"(v5r) to leave/to go away"},
	{"question":"去年","answers":["きょねん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) last year"},
	{"question":"参る","answers":["まいる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) (hum) to go/to come/to call/(2) to be defeated/to collapse/to die/(3) to be annoyed/to be nonplussed/(4) to be madly in love/(5) to visit (shrine, grave)"},
	{"question":"参上","answers":["さんじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) calling on/visiting"},
	{"question":"参加","answers":["さんか"],"comment":"(n,vs) participation"},
	{"question":"参照","answers":["さんしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) reference/consultation/consultation"},
	{"question":"参考","answers":["さんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) reference/consultation"},
	{"question":"参議院","answers":["さんぎいん"],"comment":"(n) House of Councillors"},
	{"question":"又","answers":["また"],"comment":"(adv,conj,n) again/and"},
	{"question":"又は","answers":["または"],"comment":"(conj,exp) or/otherwise"},
	{"question":"及び","answers":["および"],"comment":"(conj) and/as well as"},
	{"question":"及ぶ","answers":["およぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to reach/to come up to/to amount to/to befall/to happen to/to extend/to match/to equal"},
	{"question":"及ぼす","answers":["およぼす"],"comment":"(v5s) to exert/to cause/to exercise"},
	{"question":"友","answers":["とも"],"comment":"(n) friend/companion/pal"},
	{"question":"友人","answers":["ゆうじん"],"comment":"(n) friend"},
	{"question":"友好","answers":["ゆうこう"],"comment":"(n) friendship"},
	{"question":"友情","answers":["ゆうじょう"],"comment":"(n) friendship/fellowship"},
	{"question":"友達","answers":["ともだち"],"comment":"(n) friend"},
	{"question":"双子","answers":["ふたご"],"comment":"(n) twins/a twin"},
	{"question":"反する","answers":["はんする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to be inconsistent with/to oppose/to contradict/to transgress/to rebel"},
	{"question":"反る","answers":["かえる","そる"],"comment":"(v5r) to warp/to be warped/to curve/to be curved/to be arched/to bend (backward)"},
	{"question":"反乱","answers":["はんらん"],"comment":"(n) insurrection/mutiny/rebellion/revolt/uprising"},
	{"question":"反対","answers":["はんたい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) opposition/resistance/antagonism/hostility/contrast/objection/dissension/reverse/opposite/vice versa"},
	{"question":"反射","answers":["はんしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) reflection/reverberation"},
	{"question":"反応","answers":["はんのう"],"comment":"(n) reaction/response"},
	{"question":"反感","answers":["はんかん"],"comment":"(n) antipathy/revolt/animosity"},
	{"question":"反抗","answers":["はんこう"],"comment":"(n) opposition/resistance/insubordination/defiance/hostility/rebellion"},
	{"question":"反撃","answers":["はんげき"],"comment":"(n,vs) counterattack/counteroffensive/counterblow"},
	{"question":"反映","answers":["はんえい"],"comment":"(n,vs) reflection/influence"},
	{"question":"反発","answers":["はんぱつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) repelling/rebound/recover/oppose"},
	{"question":"反省","answers":["はんせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) reflection/reconsideration/introspection/meditation/contemplation"},
	{"question":"反響","answers":["はんきょう"],"comment":"(n) echo/reverberation/repercussion/reaction/influence"},
	{"question":"収まる","answers":["おさまる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to be in one's place/to be installed/to settle into/(2) to be obtained/to be settled/to be paid/to be delivered"},
	{"question":"収める","answers":["おさめる"],"comment":"(v1) to obtain/to reap/to pay/to supply/to accept"},
	{"question":"収入","answers":["しゅうにゅう"],"comment":"(n) income/receipts/revenue"},
	{"question":"収容","answers":["しゅうよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) accommodation/reception/housing/(2) seating/(3) custody/(4) admission/(5) entering (in a dictionary)"},
	{"question":"収支","answers":["しゅうし"],"comment":"(n) income and expenditure"},
	{"question":"収益","answers":["しゅうえき"],"comment":"(n) earnings/proceeds/returns"},
	{"question":"収穫","answers":["しゅうかく"],"comment":"(n,vs) harvest/crop/ingathering"},
	{"question":"収集","answers":["しゅうしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) gathering up/collection/accumulation"},
	{"question":"叔母","answers":["おば"],"comment":"(n) aunt (younger than one's parent)"},
	{"question":"叔母さん","answers":["おばさん"],"comment":"(n) (1) aunt/(2) middle-aged lady"},
	{"question":"叔父","answers":["おじ"],"comment":"(n) uncle (younger than one's parent)"},
	{"question":"叔父さん","answers":["おじさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) (uk) middle-aged gentleman/uncle"},
	{"question":"取り上げる","answers":["とりあげる"],"comment":"(v1) to take up/to pick up/to disqualify/to confiscate/to deprive"},
	{"question":"取り付ける","answers":["とりつける"],"comment":"(v1) to furnish/to install/to get someone's agreement"},
	{"question":"取り入れる","answers":["とりいれる"],"comment":"(v1) to harvest/to take in/to adopt"},
	{"question":"取り出す","answers":["とりだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to take out/to produce/to pick out"},
	{"question":"取り寄せる","answers":["とりよせる"],"comment":"(v1) to order/to send away for"},
	{"question":"取り巻く","answers":["とりまく"],"comment":"(v5k) to surround/to circle/to enclose"},
	{"question":"取り戻す","answers":["とりもどす"],"comment":"(v5s) to take back/to regain"},
	{"question":"取り扱う","answers":["とりあつかう"],"comment":"(v5u) to treat/to handle/to deal in"},
	{"question":"取り替え","answers":["とりかえ"],"comment":"(n) swap/exchange"},
	{"question":"取り替える","answers":["とりかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to exchange/to replace"},
	{"question":"取り次ぐ","answers":["とりつぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to act as an agent for/to announce (someone)/to convey (a message)"},
	{"question":"取り消す","answers":["とりけす"],"comment":"(v5s) to cancel"},
	{"question":"取り混ぜる","answers":["とりまぜる"],"comment":"(v1) to mix/to put together"},
	{"question":"取り立てる","answers":["とりたてる"],"comment":"(v1) to collect/to extort/to appoint/to promote"},
	{"question":"取り組む","answers":["とりくむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to tackle/to wrestle with/to engage in a bout/to come to grips with"},
	{"question":"取り締まる","answers":["とりしまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to manage/to control/to supervise"},
	{"question":"取り調べる","answers":["とりしらべる"],"comment":"(v1) to investigate/to examine"},
	{"question":"取り除く","answers":["とりのぞく"],"comment":"(v5k) to remove/to take away/to set apart"},
	{"question":"取る","answers":["とる"],"comment":"(v5r) to take/to pick up/to harvest/to earn/to choose"},
	{"question":"取れる","answers":["とれる"],"comment":"(v1) to come off/to be taken off/to be removed/to be obtained/to leave/to come out (e.g. photo)/to be interpreted"},
	{"question":"取引","answers":["とりひき"],"comment":"(n) transactions/dealings/business"},
	{"question":"取扱","answers":["とりあつかい"],"comment":"(n) treatment/service/handling/management"},
	{"question":"取材","answers":["しゅざい"],"comment":"(n) choice of subject/collecting data"},
	{"question":"取締り","answers":["とりしまり"],"comment":"(n) control/management/supervision"},
	{"question":"受かる","answers":["うかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to pass (examination)"},
	{"question":"受ける","answers":["うける"],"comment":"(v1) to undertake/to accept/to take (lesson, test, damage)/to undergo/to experience/to catch (e.g. a ball)/to become popular"},
	{"question":"受け付ける","answers":["うけつける"],"comment":"(v1) to be accepted/to receive (an application)"},
	{"question":"受け入れ","answers":["うけいれ"],"comment":"(n) receiving/acceptance"},
	{"question":"受け入れる","answers":["うけいれる"],"comment":"(v1) to accept/to receive"},
	{"question":"受け取る","answers":["うけとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to receive/to get/to accept/to take/to interpret/to understand"},
	{"question":"受け持つ","answers":["うけもつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to take (be in) charge of"},
	{"question":"受け止める","answers":["うけとめる"],"comment":"(v1) to catch/to stop the blow/to react to/to take"},
	{"question":"受け継ぐ","answers":["うけつぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to inherit/to succeed/to take over"},
	{"question":"受付","answers":["うけつけ"],"comment":"(n) receipt/acceptance/reception (desk)/information desk"},
	{"question":"受取","answers":["うけとり"],"comment":"(n) receipt"},
	{"question":"受持ち","answers":["うけもち"],"comment":"(n) charge (of something)/matter in one's charge"},
	{"question":"受話器","answers":["じゅわき"],"comment":"(n) (telephone) receiver"},
	{"question":"受身","answers":["うけみ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) passive/passive voice"},
	{"question":"受験","answers":["じゅけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) taking an examination"},
	{"question":"口","answers":["くち"],"comment":"(n) mouth/orifice/opening"},
	{"question":"口吟む","answers":["くちずさむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to hum"},
	{"question":"口実","answers":["こうじつ"],"comment":"(n) excuse"},
	{"question":"口紅","answers":["くちべに"],"comment":"(n) lipstick"},
	{"question":"口述","answers":["こうじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) verbal statement"},
	{"question":"口頭","answers":["こうとう"],"comment":"(n) oral"},
	{"question":"古い","answers":["ふるい"],"comment":"(adj) old (not person)/aged/ancient/antiquated/stale/threadbare/outmoded/obsolete article"},
	{"question":"古代","answers":["こだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n-t) ancient times"},
	{"question":"古典","answers":["こてん"],"comment":"(n) old book/classics/classic"},
	{"question":"古里","answers":["ふるさと"],"comment":"(n) home town/birthplace/old village/historic village/native place/one's old home"},
	{"question":"句","answers":["く"],"comment":"sentence"},
	{"question":"句読点","answers":["くとうてん"],"comment":"(n) punctuation marks"},
	{"question":"叩く","answers":["たたく","はたく"],"comment":"(v5k) to strike/to clap/to dust/to beat"},
	{"question":"只","answers":["ただ"],"comment":"(adj-pn,adv,conj) free of charge/mere/sole/only/usual/common"},
	{"question":"叫び","answers":["さけび"],"comment":"(n) shout/scream/outcry"},
	{"question":"叫ぶ","answers":["さけぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to shout/to cry"},
	{"question":"召し上がる","answers":["めしあがる"],"comment":"(v5r) (pol) to eat"},
	{"question":"召す","answers":["めす"],"comment":"(v5s) to call/to send for/to put on/to wear/to take (a bath)/to ride in/to buy/to eat/to drink/to catch (a cold)"},
	{"question":"可","answers":["か"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) passable"},
	{"question":"可決","answers":["かけつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) approval/adoption (e.g. motion, bill)/passage"},
	{"question":"可能","answers":["かのう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) possible/practicable/feasible"},
	{"question":"台","answers":["だい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) stand/rack/table/support"},
	{"question":"台所","answers":["だいどころ"],"comment":"(n) kitchen"},
	{"question":"台本","answers":["だいほん"],"comment":"(n) libretto/scenario"},
	{"question":"台無し","answers":["だいなし"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) mess/spoiled/(come to) nothing"},
	{"question":"台詞","answers":["せりふ"],"comment":"(n) speech/words/one's lines/remarks"},
	{"question":"台風","answers":["たいふう"],"comment":"(n) typhoon"},
	{"question":"叱る","answers":["しかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to scold"},
	{"question":"右","answers":["みぎ"],"comment":"(n) right hand side"},
	{"question":"叶う","answers":["かなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to come true (wish)"},
	{"question":"叶える","answers":["かなえる"],"comment":"(v1) to grant (request, wish)"},
	{"question":"司る","answers":["つかさどる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rule/to govern/to administer"},
	{"question":"司会","answers":["しかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) chairmanship"},
	{"question":"司法","answers":["しほう"],"comment":"(n) administration of justice"},
	{"question":"各々","answers":["おのおの"],"comment":"each/every/either/respectively/severally"},
	{"question":"各地","answers":["かくち"],"comment":"(n) every place/various places"},
	{"question":"各種","answers":["かくしゅ"],"comment":"(n) every kind/all sorts"},
	{"question":"各自","answers":["かくじ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) individual/each"},
	{"question":"合う","answers":["あう"],"comment":"(v5u) to fit/to suit/to agree with/to match/to be correct/to be profitable"},
	{"question":"合わす","answers":["あわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to join together/to face/to unite/to be opposite/to combine/to connect/to add up/to mix/to match/to overlap/to compare/to check with"},
	{"question":"合わせる","answers":["あわせる"],"comment":"(v1) to join together/to be opposite/to face/to unite/to combine/to connect/to add up/to mix/to match/to overlap/to compare/to check with"},
	{"question":"合併","answers":["がっぺい"],"comment":"(ok) (n) combination/union/amalgamation/consolidation/merger/coalition/fusion/annexation/affiliation/incorporation"},
	{"question":"合同","answers":["ごうどう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) combination/incorporation/union/amalgamation/fusion/congruence"},
	{"question":"合唱","answers":["がっしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) chorus/singing in a chorus"},
	{"question":"合図","answers":["あいず"],"comment":"(n,vs) sign/signal"},
	{"question":"合意","answers":["ごうい"],"comment":"(n) agreement/consent/mutual understanding"},
	{"question":"合成","answers":["ごうせい"],"comment":"(n) synthesis/composition/synthetic/composite/mixed/combined/compound"},
	{"question":"合格","answers":["ごうかく"],"comment":"(n,vs) success/passing (e.g. exam)/eligibility"},
	{"question":"合流","answers":["ごうりゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) confluence/union/linking up/merge"},
	{"question":"合理","answers":["ごうり"],"comment":"(n) rational"},
	{"question":"合致","answers":["がっち"],"comment":"(n) agreement/concurrence/conforming to"},
	{"question":"合計","answers":["ごうけい"],"comment":"(n,vs) sum total/total amount"},
	{"question":"合議","answers":["ごうぎ"],"comment":"(n) consultation/conference"},
	{"question":"合間","answers":["あいま"],"comment":"(n) interval"},
	{"question":"吊す","answers":["つるす"],"comment":"(v5s) to hang"},
	{"question":"吊り革","answers":["つりかわ"],"comment":"(n) strap"},
	{"question":"吊る","answers":["つる"],"comment":"(v5r) to hang"},
	{"question":"同い年","answers":["おないどし"],"comment":"(n) of the same age"},
	{"question":"同じ","answers":["おなじ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) same/identical/equal/uniform/equivalent/similar/common (origin)/changeless"},
	{"question":"同一","answers":["どういつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) identity/sameness/similarity/equality/fairness"},
	{"question":"同僚","answers":["どうりょう"],"comment":"(n) coworker/colleague/associate"},
	{"question":"同士","answers":["どうし"],"comment":"(n) fellow/companion/comrade"},
	{"question":"同封","answers":["どうふう"],"comment":"(n,vs) enclosure (e.g. in a letter)"},
	{"question":"同居","answers":["どうきょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) living together"},
	{"question":"同志","answers":["どうし"],"comment":"(n) same mind/comrade/kindred soul"},
	{"question":"同情","answers":["どうじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) sympathy/compassion/sympathize/pity/feel for"},
	{"question":"同意","answers":["どうい"],"comment":"(n) agreement/consent/same meaning/same opinion/approval"},
	{"question":"同感","answers":["どうかん"],"comment":"(n) agreement/same opinion/same feeling/sympathy/concurrence"},
	{"question":"同時","answers":["どうじ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) simultaneous(ly)/concurrent/same time/synchronous"},
	{"question":"同格","answers":["どうかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) the same rank/equality/apposition"},
	{"question":"同様","answers":["どうよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) identical/equal to/same (kind)/like"},
	{"question":"同盟","answers":["どうめい"],"comment":"(n,vs) alliance/union/league"},
	{"question":"同等","answers":["どうとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) equality/equal/same rights/same rank"},
	{"question":"同級","answers":["どうきゅう"],"comment":"(n) the same grade/same class"},
	{"question":"同調","answers":["どうちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) sympathy/agree with/alignment/tuning"},
	{"question":"名","answers":["な"],"comment":"(n) name/reputation"},
	{"question":"名人","answers":["めいじん"],"comment":"(n) master/expert"},
	{"question":"名付ける","answers":["なづける"],"comment":"(v1) to name (someone)"},
	{"question":"名作","answers":["めいさく"],"comment":"(n) masterpiece"},
	{"question":"名刺","answers":["めいし"],"comment":"(n) business card"},
	{"question":"名前","answers":["なまえ"],"comment":"(n) name"},
	{"question":"名字","answers":["みょうじ"],"comment":"(n) surname/family name"},
	{"question":"名所","answers":["めいしょ"],"comment":"(n) famous place"},
	{"question":"名札","answers":["なふだ"],"comment":"(n) name plate/name tag"},
	{"question":"名残","answers":["なごり"],"comment":"(n) remains/traces/memory"},
	{"question":"名物","answers":["めいぶつ"],"comment":"(n) famous product/special product/speciality"},
	{"question":"名産","answers":["めいさん"],"comment":"(n) noted product"},
	{"question":"名称","answers":["めいしょう"],"comment":"(n) name"},
	{"question":"名簿","answers":["めいぼ"],"comment":"(n) register of names"},
	{"question":"名詞","answers":["めいし"],"comment":"(n) noun"},
	{"question":"名誉","answers":["めいよ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) honor/credit/prestige"},
	{"question":"名高い","answers":["なだかい"],"comment":"(adj) famous/celebrated/well-known"},
	{"question":"吐き気","answers":["はきけ"],"comment":"(n) nausea/sickness in the stomach"},
	{"question":"吐く","answers":["はく"],"comment":"(v5k) (1) to breathe/(2) to tell (lies)/(3) to vomit/to disgorge"},
	{"question":"向う","answers":["むかう"],"comment":"(io) (v5u) to face/to go towards"},
	{"question":"向かい","answers":["むかい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) facing/opposite/across the street/other side"},
	{"question":"向く","answers":["むく"],"comment":"(v5k) to face"},
	{"question":"向ける","answers":["むける"],"comment":"(v1) to turn towards/to point"},
	{"question":"向こう","answers":["むこう"],"comment":"(n) beyond/over there/opposite direction/the other party"},
	{"question":"向上","answers":["こうじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) elevation/rise/improvement/advancement/progress"},
	{"question":"君","answers":["きみ"],"comment":"(n,suf) Mr (junior)/master/boy"},
	{"question":"君主","answers":["くんしゅ"],"comment":"(n) ruler/monarch"},
	{"question":"吟味","answers":["ぎんみ"],"comment":"(n) testing/scrutiny/careful investigation"},
	{"question":"吠える","answers":["ほえる"],"comment":"(v1) to bark/to bay/to howl/to bellow/to roar/to cry"},
	{"question":"否","answers":["いや"],"comment":"(n) no/the noes"},
	{"question":"否定","answers":["ひてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) negation/denial/repudiation"},
	{"question":"否決","answers":["ひけつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) rejection/negation/voting down"},
	{"question":"含む","answers":["ふくむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to hold in the mouth/to bear in mind/to understand/to cherish/to harbor/to contain/to comprise/to have/to hold/to include/to embrace/to be charged or loaded with/to be dripping with/to be full of/to be suffused with"},
	{"question":"含める","answers":["ふくめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to include/to instruct/to make one understand/to put in one's mouth"},
	{"question":"吸う","answers":["すう"],"comment":"(v5u) to smoke/to breathe in/to suck"},
	{"question":"吸収","answers":["きゅうしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) absorption/suction/attraction"},
	{"question":"吹く","answers":["ふく"],"comment":"(v5k) (1) to blow (wind, etc)/(2) to emit/to spout"},
	{"question":"吹奏","answers":["すいそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) playing wind instruments"},
	{"question":"吹雪","answers":["ふぶき"],"comment":"(n) snow storm"},
	{"question":"呆然","answers":["ぼうぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dumbfounded/overcome with surprise/in blank amazement"},
	{"question":"告げる","answers":["つげる"],"comment":"(v1) to inform"},
	{"question":"告白","answers":["こくはく"],"comment":"(n,vs) confession/acknowledgement"},
	{"question":"呑気","answers":["のんき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) carefree/optimistic/careless/reckless/heedless"},
	{"question":"呟く","answers":["つぶやく"],"comment":"(v5k) to mutter/to murmur"},
	{"question":"周り","answers":["まわり"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) circumference/surroundings/circulation"},
	{"question":"周囲","answers":["しゅうい"],"comment":"(n) surroundings/circumference/environs"},
	{"question":"周期","answers":["しゅうき"],"comment":"(n) cycle/period"},
	{"question":"周辺","answers":["しゅうへん"],"comment":"(n) circumference/outskirts/environs/(computer) peripheral"},
	{"question":"味","answers":["あじ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) flavor/taste"},
	{"question":"味わい","answers":["あじわい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) flavour/meaning/significance"},
	{"question":"味わう","answers":["あじわう"],"comment":"(v5u) to taste/to savor/to relish"},
	{"question":"味噌","answers":["みそ"],"comment":"(n) (1) miso/bean paste/(2) key (main) point"},
	{"question":"味方","answers":["みかた"],"comment":"(n) friend/ally/supporter"},
	{"question":"味覚","answers":["みかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) taste/palate/sense of taste"},
	{"question":"呼び出す","answers":["よびだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to summon/to call (e.g. phone)"},
	{"question":"呼び掛ける","answers":["よびかける"],"comment":"(v1) to call out to/to accost/to address (crowd)/to appeal"},
	{"question":"呼び止める","answers":["よびとめる"],"comment":"(v1) to challenge/to call somebody to halt"},
	{"question":"呼ぶ","answers":["よぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to call out/to invite"},
	{"question":"呼吸","answers":["こきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) breath/respiration"},
	{"question":"命","answers":["いのち"],"comment":"(n) command/decree/life/destiny"},
	{"question":"命じる","answers":["めいじる"],"comment":"(v1) to order/to command/to appoint"},
	{"question":"命ずる","answers":["めいずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to command/to appoint"},
	{"question":"命中","answers":["めいちゅう"],"comment":"(n) a hit"},
	{"question":"命令","answers":["めいれい"],"comment":"(n,vs) order/command/decree/directive/(software) instruction"},
	{"question":"和やか","answers":["なごやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) mild/calm/gentle/quiet/harmonious"},
	{"question":"和らげる","answers":["やわらげる"],"comment":"(v1) to soften/to moderate/to relieve"},
	{"question":"和文","answers":["わぶん"],"comment":"(n) Japanese text/sentence in Japanese"},
	{"question":"和服","answers":["わふく"],"comment":"(n) Japanese clothes"},
	{"question":"和英","answers":["わえい"],"comment":"(n) Japanese-English"},
	{"question":"咲く","answers":["さく"],"comment":"(v5k) to bloom"},
	{"question":"咳","answers":["せき"],"comment":"(n) cough"},
	{"question":"哀れ","answers":["あわれ"],"comment":"(adj-na,int,n) helpless/pathos/pity/sorrow/grief/misery/compassion"},
	{"question":"品","answers":["しな","ひん"],"comment":"(n) thing/article/goods/dignity/article (goods)/counter for meal courses"},
	{"question":"品物","answers":["しなもの"],"comment":"(n) goods/article/thing"},
	{"question":"品種","answers":["ひんしゅ"],"comment":"(n) brand/kind/description"},
	{"question":"品質","answers":["ひんしつ"],"comment":"(n) quality"},
	{"question":"哲学","answers":["てつがく"],"comment":"(n) philosophy"},
	{"question":"唇","answers":["くちびる"],"comment":"(n) lips"},
	{"question":"唯","answers":["ただ","たった"],"comment":"(adj-pn,adv,conj) free of charge/mere/sole/only/usual/common"},
	{"question":"唯一","answers":["ゆいいつ"],"comment":"(adv,n) only/sole/unique"},
	{"question":"唱える","answers":["となえる"],"comment":"(v1) to recite/to chant/to call upon"},
	{"question":"唾","answers":["つば"],"comment":"(n) saliva/spit/sputum"},
	{"question":"商人","answers":["しょうにん"],"comment":"(n) trader/shopkeeper/merchant"},
	{"question":"商品","answers":["しょうひん"],"comment":"(n) commodity/article of commerce/goods/stock/merchandise"},
	{"question":"商売","answers":["しょうばい"],"comment":"(n,vs) trade/business/commerce/transaction/occupation"},
	{"question":"商店","answers":["しょうてん"],"comment":"(n) shop/business firm"},
	{"question":"商業","answers":["しょうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) commerce/trade/business"},
	{"question":"商社","answers":["しょうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) trading company/firm"},
	{"question":"問い","answers":["とい"],"comment":"(n) question/query"},
	{"question":"問い合わせ","answers":["といあわせ"],"comment":"(n) enquiry/ENQ"},
	{"question":"問い合わせる","answers":["といあわせる"],"comment":"(v1) to enquire/to seek information"},
	{"question":"問う","answers":["とう"],"comment":"(v5u-s) to ask/to question/to charge (i.e. with a crime)/to accuse/without regard to (neg)"},
	{"question":"問屋","answers":["とんや"],"comment":"(n) wholesale store"},
	{"question":"問答","answers":["もんどう"],"comment":"(n) questions and answers/dialogue"},
	{"question":"問題","answers":["もんだい"],"comment":"(n) problem/question"},
	{"question":"善","answers":["ぜん"],"comment":"(n) good/goodness/right/virtue"},
	{"question":"善し悪し","answers":["よしあし"],"comment":"(n) good or bad/merits or demerits/quality/suitability"},
	{"question":"善良","answers":["ぜんりょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) goodness/excellence/virtue"},
	{"question":"喉","answers":["のど"],"comment":"(n) (uk) throat"},
	{"question":"喜び","answers":["よろこび"],"comment":"(n) (a) joy/(a) delight/rapture/pleasure/gratification/rejoicing/congratulations/felicitations"},
	{"question":"喜ぶ","answers":["よろこぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to be delighted/to be glad"},
	{"question":"喜劇","answers":["きげき"],"comment":"(n) comedy/funny show"},
	{"question":"喧嘩","answers":["けんか"],"comment":"(n) quarrel/(drunken) brawl/failure"},
	{"question":"喫茶店","answers":["きっさてん"],"comment":"(n) coffee lounge"},
	{"question":"営む","answers":["いとなむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to carry on (e.g. in ceremony)/to run a business"},
	{"question":"営業","answers":["えいぎょう"],"comment":"(n) business/trade/management"},
	{"question":"嗅ぐ","answers":["かぐ"],"comment":"(v5g,vt) to sniff/to smell"},
	{"question":"嗜好","answers":["しこう"],"comment":"(n) taste/liking/preference"},
	{"question":"嘆く","answers":["なげく"],"comment":"(v5k) to sigh/to lament/to grieve"},
	{"question":"嘗める","answers":["なめる"],"comment":"(v1) to lick/to taste/to experience/to make fun of/to make light of/to put down/to treat with contempt"},
	{"question":"嘘","answers":["うそ"],"comment":"(n) lie/falsehood/incorrect fact/inappropriate"},
	{"question":"嘘つき","answers":["うそつき"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) (uk) liar (sometimes said with not much seriousness)/fibber"},
	{"question":"嘴","answers":["くちばし"],"comment":"(n) (uk) beak/bill"},
	{"question":"噂","answers":["うわさ"],"comment":"(n) rumour/report/gossip/common talk"},
	{"question":"噛み切る","answers":["かみきる"],"comment":"(v5r) to bite off/to gnaw through"},
	{"question":"噛む","answers":["かむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to bite/to chew/to gnaw"},
	{"question":"器","answers":["うつわ"],"comment":"(n) bowl/vessel/container"},
	{"question":"器具","answers":["きぐ"],"comment":"(n) utensil"},
	{"question":"器官","answers":["きかん"],"comment":"(n) organ (of body)/instrument"},
	{"question":"器械","answers":["きかい"],"comment":"(n) instrument"},
	{"question":"器用","answers":["きよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) skillful/handy"},
	{"question":"噴出","answers":["ふんしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) spewing/gushing/spouting/eruption/effusion"},
	{"question":"噴水","answers":["ふんすい"],"comment":"(n) water fountain"},
	{"question":"噴火","answers":["ふんか"],"comment":"(n,vs) eruption"},
	{"question":"囁く","answers":["ささやく"],"comment":"(v5k) to whisper/to murmur"},
	{"question":"四","answers":["し","よん"],"comment":"(num) four"},
	{"question":"四つ","answers":["よっつ"],"comment":"(n) four"},
	{"question":"四つ角","answers":["よつかど"],"comment":"(n) four corners/crossroads"},
	{"question":"四季","answers":["しき"],"comment":"(n) four seasons"},
	{"question":"四捨五入","answers":["ししゃごにゅう"],"comment":"(n) rounding up (fractions)"},
	{"question":"四日","answers":["よっか"],"comment":"(n) (1) 4th day of month/(2) four days"},
	{"question":"四角","answers":["しかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) square"},
	{"question":"四角い","answers":["しかくい"],"comment":"(adj) square"},
	{"question":"回","answers":["かい"],"comment":"(n) counter for occurrences"},
	{"question":"回す","answers":["まわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to turn/to revolve"},
	{"question":"回り","answers":["まわり"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) circumference/surroundings/circulation"},
	{"question":"回り道","answers":["まわりみち"],"comment":"(n) detour"},
	{"question":"回る","answers":["まわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to wander around"},
	{"question":"回収","answers":["かいしゅう"],"comment":"(n) collection/recovery"},
	{"question":"回復","answers":["かいふく"],"comment":"(n,vs) recovery (from illness)/improvement/rehabilitation/restoration"},
	{"question":"回数","answers":["かいすう"],"comment":"(n) number of times/frequency"},
	{"question":"回数券","answers":["かいすうけん"],"comment":"(n) book of tickets"},
	{"question":"回答","answers":["かいとう"],"comment":"(n) reply/answer"},
	{"question":"回覧","answers":["かいらん"],"comment":"(n) circulation"},
	{"question":"回路","answers":["かいろ"],"comment":"(n) circuit (electric)"},
	{"question":"回転","answers":["かいてん"],"comment":"(n,vs) rotation/revolution/turning"},
	{"question":"回送","answers":["かいそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) forwarding"},
	{"question":"因る","answers":["よる"],"comment":"(v5r) to come from"},
	{"question":"団体","answers":["だんたい"],"comment":"(n) organization/association"},
	{"question":"団地","answers":["だんち"],"comment":"(n) multi-unit apartments"},
	{"question":"団扇","answers":["うちわ"],"comment":"(n) fan"},
	{"question":"団結","answers":["だんけつ"],"comment":"(n) unity/union/combination"},
	{"question":"困る","answers":["こまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be worried/to be bothered"},
	{"question":"困難","answers":["こんなん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) difficulty/distress"},
	{"question":"囲む","answers":["かこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to surround/to encircle"},
	{"question":"図","answers":["ず"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) figure (e.g. Fig 1)/drawing/picture/illustration"},
	{"question":"図る","answers":["はかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to plot/to attempt/to plan/to take in/to deceive/to devise/to design/to refer A to B"},
	{"question":"図形","answers":["ずけい"],"comment":"(n) figure"},
	{"question":"図書","answers":["としょ"],"comment":"(n) books"},
	{"question":"図書館","answers":["としょかん"],"comment":"(n) library"},
	{"question":"図表","answers":["ずひょう"],"comment":"(n) chart/diagram/graph"},
	{"question":"図鑑","answers":["ずかん"],"comment":"(n) picture book"},
	{"question":"固い","answers":["かたい"],"comment":"(adj) stubborn/firm (not viscous or easily moved)/certain/solemn"},
	{"question":"固まる","answers":["かたまる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to harden/to solidify/to become firm/to become certain"},
	{"question":"固める","answers":["かためる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to harden/to freeze/to fortify"},
	{"question":"固定","answers":["こてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) fixation/fixing (e.g. salary, capital)"},
	{"question":"固有","answers":["こゆう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,pref) characteristic/tradition/peculiar/inherent/eigen-"},
	{"question":"国","answers":["くに"],"comment":"(n) country"},
	{"question":"国交","answers":["こっこう"],"comment":"(n) diplomatic relations"},
	{"question":"国会","answers":["こっかい"],"comment":"(n) National Diet/parliament/congress"},
	{"question":"国境","answers":["こっきょう"],"comment":"(n) national or state border"},
	{"question":"国定","answers":["こくてい"],"comment":"(n) state-sponsored/national"},
	{"question":"国家","answers":["こっか"],"comment":"(n) state/country/nation"},
	{"question":"国有","answers":["こくゆう"],"comment":"(n) national ownership"},
	{"question":"国民","answers":["こくみん"],"comment":"(n) national/people/citizen"},
	{"question":"国王","answers":["こくおう"],"comment":"(n) king"},
	{"question":"国産","answers":["こくさん"],"comment":"(n) domestic products"},
	{"question":"国立","answers":["こくりつ"],"comment":"(n) national"},
	{"question":"国籍","answers":["こくせき"],"comment":"(n) nationality"},
	{"question":"国語","answers":["こくご"],"comment":"(n) national language"},
	{"question":"国連","answers":["こくれん"],"comment":"(n) U.N./United Nations"},
	{"question":"国防","answers":["こくぼう"],"comment":"(n) national defence"},
	{"question":"国際","answers":["こくさい"],"comment":"(n) international"},
	{"question":"園芸","answers":["えんげい"],"comment":"(n) horticulture/gardening"},
	{"question":"土","answers":["つち"],"comment":"(n) earth/soil"},
	{"question":"土俵","answers":["どひょう"],"comment":"(n) arena"},
	{"question":"土台","answers":["どだい"],"comment":"(adv,n) foundation/base/basis"},
	{"question":"土地","answers":["とち"],"comment":"(n) plot of land/lot/soil"},
	{"question":"土手","answers":["どて"],"comment":"(n) embankment/bank"},
	{"question":"土曜","answers":["どよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Saturday"},
	{"question":"土曜日","answers":["どようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Saturday"},
	{"question":"土木","answers":["どぼく"],"comment":"(n) public works"},
	{"question":"土産","answers":["みやげ"],"comment":"(n) present/souvenir"},
	{"question":"圧倒","answers":["あっとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) overwhelm/overpower/overwhelming"},
	{"question":"圧力","answers":["あつりょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) stress/pressure"},
	{"question":"圧縮","answers":["あっしゅく"],"comment":"(n,vs) compression/condensation/pressure"},
	{"question":"圧迫","answers":["あっぱく"],"comment":"(n,vs) pressure/coercion/oppression"},
	{"question":"在る","answers":["ある"],"comment":"(v5r-i) to live/to be"},
	{"question":"在学","answers":["ざいがく"],"comment":"(n) (enrolled) in school"},
	{"question":"在庫","answers":["ざいこ"],"comment":"(n) stockpile/stock"},
	{"question":"地","answers":["ち"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) earth"},
	{"question":"地下","answers":["ちか"],"comment":"(n) basement/underground"},
	{"question":"地下水","answers":["ちかすい"],"comment":"(n) underground water"},
	{"question":"地下鉄","answers":["ちかてつ"],"comment":"(n) underground train/subway"},
	{"question":"地主","answers":["じぬし"],"comment":"(n) landlord"},
	{"question":"地位","answers":["ちい"],"comment":"(n) (social) position/status"},
	{"question":"地元","answers":["じもと"],"comment":"(n) local"},
	{"question":"地区","answers":["ちく"],"comment":"(n) district/section/sector"},
	{"question":"地名","answers":["ちめい"],"comment":"(n) place name"},
	{"question":"地味","answers":["じみ"],"comment":"(n) soil fertility/product of the soil"},
	{"question":"地図","answers":["ちず"],"comment":"(n) map"},
	{"question":"地域","answers":["ちいき"],"comment":"(n) area/region"},
	{"question":"地帯","answers":["ちたい"],"comment":"(n) area/zone"},
	{"question":"地平線","answers":["ちへいせん"],"comment":"(n) horizon"},
	{"question":"地形","answers":["ちけい"],"comment":"(n) terrain/geographical features/topography"},
	{"question":"地方","answers":["ちほう"],"comment":"(n) area/locality/district/region/the coast"},
	{"question":"地点","answers":["ちてん"],"comment":"(n) site/point on a map"},
	{"question":"地獄","answers":["じごく"],"comment":"(n) hell"},
	{"question":"地球","answers":["ちきゅう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) the earth"},
	{"question":"地理","answers":["ちり"],"comment":"(n) geography"},
	{"question":"地盤","answers":["じばん"],"comment":"(n) (the) ground"},
	{"question":"地質","answers":["ちしつ"],"comment":"(n) geological features"},
	{"question":"地震","answers":["じしん"],"comment":"(n) earthquake"},
	{"question":"地面","answers":["じめん"],"comment":"(n) ground/earth's surface"},
	{"question":"坂","answers":["さか"],"comment":"(n) slope/hill"},
	{"question":"均衡","answers":["きんこう"],"comment":"(n) equilibrium/balance"},
	{"question":"坊さん","answers":["ぼうさん"],"comment":"(n) Buddhist priest/monk"},
	{"question":"坊っちゃん","answers":["ぼっちゃん"],"comment":"(n) son (of others)"},
	{"question":"坊や","answers":["ぼうや"],"comment":"(n) boy"},
	{"question":"垂れる","answers":["たれる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) (1) to hang/to droop/to dangle/to sag/to lower/to pull down/(2) to leave behind (at death)/to give/to confer/(3) to drip/to ooze/to trickle/to drop"},
	{"question":"垂直","answers":["すいちょく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) vertical/perpendicular"},
	{"question":"型","answers":["かた"],"comment":"(n) mold/model/style/shape/data-type"},
	{"question":"垢","answers":["あか"],"comment":"(n) dirt/filth"},
	{"question":"垣根","answers":["かきね"],"comment":"(n) hedge"},
	{"question":"埃","answers":["ほこり"],"comment":"(n) dust"},
	{"question":"埋まる","answers":["うまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be buried/to be surrounded/to overflow/to be filled"},
	{"question":"埋める","answers":["うずめる","うめる"],"comment":"(v1) to bury/to fill up/to fill (a seat, a vacant position)"},
	{"question":"埋め込む","answers":["うめこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to bury"},
	{"question":"埋蔵","answers":["まいぞう"],"comment":"(n) buried property/treasure trove"},
	{"question":"城","answers":["しろ"],"comment":"(n) castle"},
	{"question":"城下","answers":["じょうか"],"comment":"(n) land near the castle"},
	{"question":"執着","answers":["しゅうじゃく","しゅうちゃく"],"comment":"(n) attachment/adhesion/tenacity"},
	{"question":"執筆","answers":["しっぴつ"],"comment":"(n) writing"},
	{"question":"基","answers":["もと"],"comment":"(n) basis"},
	{"question":"基づく","answers":["もとづく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be grounded on/to be based on/to be due to/to originate from"},
	{"question":"基地","answers":["きち"],"comment":"(n) base"},
	{"question":"基本","answers":["きほん"],"comment":"(n) foundation/basis/standard"},
	{"question":"基準","answers":["きじゅん"],"comment":"(n) standard/basis/criteria/norm"},
	{"question":"基盤","answers":["きばん"],"comment":"(n) foundation/basis"},
	{"question":"基礎","answers":["きそ"],"comment":"(n) foundation/basis"},
	{"question":"基金","answers":["ききん"],"comment":"(n) fund/foundation"},
	{"question":"堀","answers":["ほり"],"comment":"(n) moat/canal"},
	{"question":"堂々","answers":["どうどう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) magnificent/grand/impressive"},
	{"question":"堅い","answers":["かたい"],"comment":"(adj) hard (esp. wood)/steadfast/honorable/stuffy writing"},
	{"question":"堤防","answers":["ていぼう"],"comment":"(n) bank/weir"},
	{"question":"堪える","answers":["たえる"],"comment":"(v1) to bear/to stand/to endure/to put up with/to support/to withstand/to resist/to brave/to be fit for/to be equal to"},
	{"question":"報じる","answers":["ほうじる"],"comment":"(v1) to inform/to report"},
	{"question":"報ずる","answers":["ほうずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to inform/to report"},
	{"question":"報告","answers":["ほうこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) report/information"},
	{"question":"報道","answers":["ほうどう"],"comment":"(n) information/report"},
	{"question":"報酬","answers":["ほうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) remuneration/recompense/reward/toll"},
	{"question":"場","answers":["ば"],"comment":"(n) place/field (physics)"},
	{"question":"場合","answers":["ばあい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) case/situation"},
	{"question":"場所","answers":["ばしょ"],"comment":"(n) place/location"},
	{"question":"場面","answers":["ばめん"],"comment":"(n) scene/setting (e.g. of novel)"},
	{"question":"塀","answers":["へい"],"comment":"(n) wall/fence"},
	{"question":"塊","answers":["かたまり"],"comment":"(n) lump/mass/clod/cluster"},
	{"question":"塔","answers":["とう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) tower/pagoda"},
	{"question":"塗る","answers":["ぬる"],"comment":"(v5r) to paint/to plaster/to lacquer/to varnish"},
	{"question":"塞がる","answers":["ふさがる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be plugged up/to be shut up"},
	{"question":"塞ぐ","answers":["ふさぐ"],"comment":"(v5g,vt) to stop up/to close up/to block (up)/to occupy/to fill up/to take up/to stand in another's way/to plug up/to shut up"},
	{"question":"塩","answers":["しお"],"comment":"(n) salt"},
	{"question":"塩辛い","answers":["しおからい"],"comment":"(adj) salty (taste)"},
	{"question":"塵","answers":["ごみ","ちり"],"comment":"(n) dust/dirt"},
	{"question":"塵取り","answers":["ちりとり"],"comment":"(n) dustpan"},
	{"question":"塵紙","answers":["ちりがみ"],"comment":"(n) tissue paper/toilet paper"},
	{"question":"塵芥","answers":["ごみ"],"comment":"(n) trash/rubbish"},
	{"question":"塾","answers":["じゅく"],"comment":"(n) coaching school/lessons"},
	{"question":"境","answers":["さかい"],"comment":"(n) border/boundary/mental state"},
	{"question":"境界","answers":["きょうかい"],"comment":"(n) boundary"},
	{"question":"境遇","answers":["きょうぐう"],"comment":"(n) environment/circumstances"},
	{"question":"墓","answers":["はか"],"comment":"(n) grave/tomb"},
	{"question":"墓地","answers":["ぼち"],"comment":"(n) cemetery/graveyard"},
	{"question":"増える","answers":["ふえる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to increase/to multiply"},
	{"question":"増す","answers":["ます"],"comment":"(v5s,vi) to increase/to grow"},
	{"question":"増やす","answers":["ふやす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to increase/to add to/to augment"},
	{"question":"増加","answers":["ぞうか"],"comment":"(n,vs) increase/addition"},
	{"question":"増大","answers":["ぞうだい"],"comment":"(n,vs) enlargement"},
	{"question":"増強","answers":["ぞうきょう"],"comment":"(n) augment/reinforce/increase"},
	{"question":"増減","answers":["ぞうげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) increase and decrease/fluctuation"},
	{"question":"増進","answers":["ぞうしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) promoting/increase/advance"},
	{"question":"墜落","answers":["ついらく"],"comment":"(n,vs) falling/crashing"},
	{"question":"墨","answers":["すみ"],"comment":"(n) ink"},
	{"question":"壁","answers":["かべ"],"comment":"(n) wall"},
	{"question":"壊す","answers":["こわす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to break/to break down"},
	{"question":"壊れる","answers":["こわれる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to be broken/to break"},
	{"question":"壮大","answers":["そうだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) magnificent/grand/majestic/splendid"},
	{"question":"声","answers":["こえ"],"comment":"(n) voice"},
	{"question":"声明","answers":["せいめい"],"comment":"(n) declaration/statement/proclamation"},
	{"question":"売り出し","answers":["うりだし"],"comment":"(n) (bargain) sale"},
	{"question":"売り出す","answers":["うりだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to put on sale/to market/to become popular"},
	{"question":"売り切れ","answers":["うりきれ"],"comment":"(n) sold-out"},
	{"question":"売り切れる","answers":["うりきれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be sold out"},
	{"question":"売り場","answers":["うりば"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) place where things are sold/salesfloor/counter (in shop)"},
	{"question":"売る","answers":["うる"],"comment":"(v5r) to sell"},
	{"question":"売れる","answers":["うれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be sold"},
	{"question":"売上","answers":["うりあげ"],"comment":"(n) amount sold/proceeds"},
	{"question":"売店","answers":["ばいてん"],"comment":"(n) shop/stand"},
	{"question":"売行き","answers":["うれゆき"],"comment":"(n) sales"},
	{"question":"売買","answers":["ばいばい"],"comment":"(n) trade/buying and selling"},
	{"question":"壷","answers":["つぼ"],"comment":"(n) tsubo jar/pot/vase"},
	{"question":"変","answers":["へん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) change/incident/disturbance/strange/flat (music)/odd/peculiar/suspicious-looking/queer/eccentric/funny"},
	{"question":"変える","answers":["かえる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to change/to alter/to vary/to convert/to revise/to amend"},
	{"question":"変わる","answers":["かわる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to change/to be transformed/to vary/to be revised/to be different/to move location"},
	{"question":"変動","answers":["へんどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) change/fluctuation"},
	{"question":"変化","answers":["へんか"],"comment":"(n) goblin/ghost/apparition/bugbear"},
	{"question":"変更","answers":["へんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) change/modification/alteration"},
	{"question":"変遷","answers":["へんせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) change/transition/vicissitudes"},
	{"question":"変革","answers":["へんかく"],"comment":"(n) change/reform/revolution/upheaval/(the) Reformation"},
	{"question":"夏","answers":["なつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) summer"},
	{"question":"夏休み","answers":["なつやすみ"],"comment":"(n) summer vacation/summer holiday"},
	{"question":"夕べ","answers":["ゆうべ"],"comment":"(n) evening"},
	{"question":"夕刊","answers":["ゆうかん"],"comment":"(n) evening paper"},
	{"question":"夕方","answers":["ゆうがた"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) evening"},
	{"question":"夕日","answers":["ゆうひ"],"comment":"(n) (in) the evening sun/setting sun"},
	{"question":"夕暮れ","answers":["ゆうぐれ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) evening/(evening) twilight"},
	{"question":"夕焼け","answers":["ゆうやけ"],"comment":"(n) sunset"},
	{"question":"夕立","answers":["ゆうだち"],"comment":"(n) (sudden) evening shower (rain)"},
	{"question":"夕飯","answers":["ゆうはん"],"comment":"(n) evening meal"},
	{"question":"外","answers":["そと","ほか"],"comment":"(n) other place/the rest"},
	{"question":"外す","answers":["はずす"],"comment":"(v5s) to unfasten/to remove"},
	{"question":"外れる","answers":["はずれる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to be disconnected/to get out of place/to be off/to be out (e.g. of gear)"},
	{"question":"外交","answers":["がいこう"],"comment":"(n) diplomacy"},
	{"question":"外出","answers":["がいしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) outing/going out"},
	{"question":"外国","answers":["がいこく"],"comment":"(n) foreign country"},
	{"question":"外国人","answers":["がいこくじん"],"comment":"(n) foreigner"},
	{"question":"外方","answers":["そっぽ"],"comment":"(n) look (or turn) the other way"},
	{"question":"外来","answers":["がいらい"],"comment":"(n) (abbr) imported/outpatient clinic"},
	{"question":"外相","answers":["がいしょう"],"comment":"(n) Foreign Minister"},
	{"question":"外科","answers":["げか"],"comment":"(n) surgical department"},
	{"question":"外観","answers":["がいかん"],"comment":"(n) appearance/exterior/facade"},
	{"question":"外貨","answers":["がいか"],"comment":"(n) imported goods/foreign money"},
	{"question":"外部","answers":["がいぶ"],"comment":"(n) the outside/external"},
	{"question":"多い","answers":["おおい"],"comment":"(adj) many/numerous"},
	{"question":"多分","answers":["たぶん"],"comment":"(adv,n) perhaps/probably"},
	{"question":"多少","answers":["たしょう"],"comment":"(adj-no,adv,n) more or less/somewhat/a little/some"},
	{"question":"多忙","answers":["たぼう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) busy/pressure of work"},
	{"question":"多数決","answers":["たすうけつ"],"comment":"(n) majority rule"},
	{"question":"多様","answers":["たよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) diversity/variety"},
	{"question":"夜","answers":["よ","よる"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) evening/night"},
	{"question":"夜中","answers":["よなか"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) midnight/dead of night"},
	{"question":"夜具","answers":["やぐ"],"comment":"(n) bedding"},
	{"question":"夜明け","answers":["よあけ"],"comment":"(n) dawn/daybreak"},
	{"question":"夜更け","answers":["よふけ"],"comment":"(n) late at night"},
	{"question":"夜更し","answers":["よふかし"],"comment":"(n) staying up late/keeping late hours/sitting up late at night/nighthawk"},
	{"question":"夜行","answers":["やこう"],"comment":"(n) walking around at night/night train/night travel"},
	{"question":"夜間","answers":["やかん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) at night/nighttime"},
	{"question":"夢","answers":["ゆめ"],"comment":"(n) dream"},
	{"question":"夢中","answers":["むちゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) daze/(in a) trance/ecstasy/delirium/engrossment"},
	{"question":"大いに","answers":["おおいに"],"comment":"(adv) very/much/greatly"},
	{"question":"大きい","answers":["おおきい"],"comment":"(adj) big/large/great"},
	{"question":"大した","answers":["たいした"],"comment":"(adj-pn) considerable/great/important/significant/a big deal"},
	{"question":"大して","answers":["たいして"],"comment":"(adv) (not so) much/(not) very"},
	{"question":"大丈夫","answers":["だいじょうぶ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) safe/all right/O.K."},
	{"question":"大事","answers":["だいじ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) important/valuable/serious matter"},
	{"question":"大人","answers":["おとな"],"comment":"(n) adult"},
	{"question":"大会","answers":["たいかい"],"comment":"(n) convention/tournament/mass meeting/rally"},
	{"question":"大体","answers":["だいたい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) general/substantially/outline/main point"},
	{"question":"大使","answers":["たいし"],"comment":"(n) ambassador"},
	{"question":"大使館","answers":["たいしかん"],"comment":"(n) embassy"},
	{"question":"大便","answers":["だいべん"],"comment":"(n) feces/excrement/shit"},
	{"question":"大凡","answers":["おおよそ"],"comment":"(adv,n) (uk) about/roughly/as a rule/approximately"},
	{"question":"大分","answers":["だいぶ","だいぶん"],"comment":"(adv) considerably/greatly/a lot"},
	{"question":"大切","answers":["たいせつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) important"},
	{"question":"大勢","answers":["おおぜい"],"comment":"(n) great number of people"},
	{"question":"大半","answers":["たいはん"],"comment":"(n) majority/mostly/generally"},
	{"question":"大好き","answers":["だいすき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) very likeable/like very much"},
	{"question":"大学","answers":["だいがく"],"comment":"(n) university"},
	{"question":"大学生","answers":["だいがくせい"],"comment":"(n) college student"},
	{"question":"大学院","answers":["だいがくいん"],"comment":"(n) graduate school"},
	{"question":"大家","answers":["おおや","たいか"],"comment":"(n) rich family/distinguished family"},
	{"question":"大小","answers":["だいしょう"],"comment":"(n) size"},
	{"question":"大層","answers":["たいそう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) very much/exaggerated/very fine"},
	{"question":"大工","answers":["だいく"],"comment":"(n) carpenter"},
	{"question":"大幅","answers":["おおはば"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) full width/large scale/drastic"},
	{"question":"大戦","answers":["たいせん"],"comment":"(n) great war/great battle"},
	{"question":"大抵","answers":["たいてい"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) usually/generally"},
	{"question":"大方","answers":["おおかた"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) perhaps/almost all/majority"},
	{"question":"大木","answers":["たいぼく"],"comment":"(n) large tree"},
	{"question":"大柄","answers":["おおがら"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) large build/large pattern"},
	{"question":"大概","answers":["たいがい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) in general/mainly"},
	{"question":"大気","answers":["たいき"],"comment":"(n) atmosphere"},
	{"question":"大水","answers":["おおみず"],"comment":"(n) flood"},
	{"question":"大空","answers":["おおぞら"],"comment":"(n) heaven/firmament/the sky"},
	{"question":"大筋","answers":["おおすじ"],"comment":"(n) outline/summary"},
	{"question":"大統領","answers":["だいとうりょう"],"comment":"(n) president/chief executive"},
	{"question":"大胆","answers":["だいたん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) bold/daring/audacious"},
	{"question":"大臣","answers":["だいじん"],"comment":"(n) cabinet minister"},
	{"question":"大衆","answers":["たいしゅう"],"comment":"(n) general public"},
	{"question":"大通り","answers":["おおどおり"],"comment":"(n) main street"},
	{"question":"大部","answers":["たいぶ"],"comment":"(adv,n) most (e.g. most part)/greater/fairly/a good deal/much"},
	{"question":"大部分","answers":["だいぶぶん"],"comment":"(n-t) most part/greater part/majority"},
	{"question":"大金","answers":["たいきん"],"comment":"(n) great cost"},
	{"question":"大陸","answers":["たいりく"],"comment":"(n) continent"},
	{"question":"天","answers":["てん"],"comment":"(n) heaven/sky"},
	{"question":"天下","answers":["てんか"],"comment":"(n) the world/whole country/descent from heaven/having one's own way/the public/the ruling power"},
	{"question":"天体","answers":["てんたい"],"comment":"(n) heavenly body"},
	{"question":"天候","answers":["てんこう"],"comment":"(n) weather"},
	{"question":"天国","answers":["てんごく"],"comment":"(n) paradise/heaven/Kingdom of Heaven"},
	{"question":"天地","answers":["てんち"],"comment":"(n) heaven and earth/the universe/nature/top and bottom/realm/sphere/world"},
	{"question":"天才","answers":["てんさい"],"comment":"(n) genius/prodigy/natural gift"},
	{"question":"天気","answers":["てんき"],"comment":"(n) weather/the elements/fine weather"},
	{"question":"天気予報","answers":["てんきよほう"],"comment":"weather forecast/weather report"},
	{"question":"天災","answers":["てんさい"],"comment":"(n) natural calamity/disaster"},
	{"question":"天然","answers":["てんねん"],"comment":"(n) nature/spontaneity"},
	{"question":"天皇","answers":["てんのう"],"comment":"(n) Emperor of Japan"},
	{"question":"太い","answers":["ふとい"],"comment":"(adj) fat/thick"},
	{"question":"太る","answers":["ふとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to grow fat (stout, plump)/to become fat"},
	{"question":"太陽","answers":["たいよう"],"comment":"(n) sun/solar"},
	{"question":"太鼓","answers":["たいこ"],"comment":"(n) drum/tambourine"},
	{"question":"夫","answers":["おっと"],"comment":"(n) (hum) (my) husband"},
	{"question":"夫人","answers":["ふじん"],"comment":"(n) wife/Mrs/madam"},
	{"question":"夫妻","answers":["ふさい"],"comment":"(n) man and wife/married couple"},
	{"question":"夫婦","answers":["ふうふ"],"comment":"(n) married couple/spouses/husband and wife/couple/pair"},
	{"question":"失う","answers":["うしなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to lose/to part with"},
	{"question":"失恋","answers":["しつれん"],"comment":"(n,vs) disappointed love/broken heart/unrequited love/be lovelorn"},
	{"question":"失敗","answers":["しっぱい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) failure/mistake/blunder"},
	{"question":"失望","answers":["しつぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) disappointment/despair"},
	{"question":"失格","answers":["しっかく"],"comment":"(n) disqualification/elimination/incapacity (legal)"},
	{"question":"失業","answers":["しつぎょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) unemployment"},
	{"question":"失礼","answers":["しつれい"],"comment":"(adj-na,int,n,vs,exp) (1) discourtesy/impoliteness/(2) Excuse me/Goodbye"},
	{"question":"失脚","answers":["しっきゃく"],"comment":"(n,vs) losing one's standing/being overthrown/falling"},
	{"question":"失調","answers":["しっちょう"],"comment":"(n) lack of harmony"},
	{"question":"奇妙","answers":["きみょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) strange/queer/curious"},
	{"question":"奉る","answers":["たてまつる"],"comment":"(v5r) to offer/to present/to revere/to do respectfully"},
	{"question":"奉仕","answers":["ほうし"],"comment":"(n) attendance/service"},
	{"question":"契機","answers":["けいき"],"comment":"(n) opportunity/chance"},
	{"question":"契約","answers":["けいやく"],"comment":"(n) contract/compact/agreement"},
	{"question":"奥","answers":["おく"],"comment":"(n) interior/inner part"},
	{"question":"奥さん","answers":["おくさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) wife/your wife/his wife/married lady/madam"},
	{"question":"奨励","answers":["しょうれい"],"comment":"(n) encouragement/promotion/message/address"},
	{"question":"奨学金","answers":["しょうがくきん"],"comment":"(n) scholarship"},
	{"question":"奪う","answers":["うばう"],"comment":"(v5u) to snatch away"},
	{"question":"奮闘","answers":["ふんとう"],"comment":"(n) hard struggle/strenuous effort"},
	{"question":"女","answers":["おんな"],"comment":"(n) woman/girl/daughter"},
	{"question":"女の人","answers":["おんなのひと"],"comment":"woman"},
	{"question":"女の子","answers":["おんなのこ"],"comment":"(n) girl"},
	{"question":"女優","answers":["じょゆう"],"comment":"(n) actress"},
	{"question":"女史","answers":["じょし"],"comment":"(n) Ms."},
	{"question":"女子","answers":["じょし"],"comment":"(n) woman/girl"},
	{"question":"女性","answers":["じょせい"],"comment":"(n) woman"},
	{"question":"女房","answers":["にょうぼう"],"comment":"(n) wife"},
	{"question":"女王","answers":["じょおう"],"comment":"(n) queen"},
	{"question":"奴","answers":["やつ"],"comment":"(n) (vulg) fellow/guy/chap"},
	{"question":"好き","answers":["すき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) liking/fondness/love"},
	{"question":"好き好き","answers":["すきずき"],"comment":"(n) matter of taste"},
	{"question":"好き嫌い","answers":["すききらい"],"comment":"(n) likes and dislikes/taste"},
	{"question":"好ましい","answers":["このましい"],"comment":"(adj) nice/likeable/desirable"},
	{"question":"好み","answers":["このみ"],"comment":"(n) liking/taste/choice"},
	{"question":"好む","answers":["このむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to like/to prefer"},
	{"question":"好意","answers":["こうい"],"comment":"(n) good will/favor/courtesy"},
	{"question":"好況","answers":["こうきょう"],"comment":"(n) prosperous conditions/healthy economy"},
	{"question":"好評","answers":["こうひょう"],"comment":"(n) popularity/favorable reputation"},
	{"question":"好調","answers":["こうちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) favourable/promising/satisfactory/in good shape"},
	{"question":"妊娠","answers":["にんしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) conception/pregnancy"},
	{"question":"妙","answers":["みょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) strange/unusual"},
	{"question":"妥協","answers":["だきょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) compromise/giving in"},
	{"question":"妥当","answers":["だとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) valid/proper/right/appropriate"},
	{"question":"妥結","answers":["だけつ"],"comment":"(n) agreement"},
	{"question":"妨げる","answers":["さまたげる"],"comment":"(v1) to disturb/to prevent"},
	{"question":"妨害","answers":["ぼうがい"],"comment":"(n,vs) disturbance/obstruction/hindrance/jamming/interference"},
	{"question":"妬む","answers":["ねたむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be jealous/to be envious"},
	{"question":"妹","answers":["いもうと"],"comment":"(n) (hum) younger sister"},
	{"question":"妻","answers":["つま"],"comment":"(n) (hum) wife"},
	{"question":"姉","answers":["あね"],"comment":"(n) (hum) older sister"},
	{"question":"姉妹","answers":["しまい"],"comment":"(n) sisters"},
	{"question":"始まり","answers":["はじまり"],"comment":"(n) origin/beginning"},
	{"question":"始まる","answers":["はじまる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to begin"},
	{"question":"始めに","answers":["はじめに"],"comment":"to begin with/first of all"},
	{"question":"始める","answers":["はじめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to start/to begin"},
	{"question":"始末","answers":["しまつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) management/(2) dealing/settlement/(3) cleaning up afterwards"},
	{"question":"始発","answers":["しはつ"],"comment":"(n) first train"},
	{"question":"始終","answers":["しじゅう"],"comment":"(adv,n) continuously/from beginning to end"},
	{"question":"姓","answers":["せい"],"comment":"(n) surname/family name"},
	{"question":"姓名","answers":["せいめい"],"comment":"(n) full name"},
	{"question":"委員","answers":["いいん"],"comment":"(n) committee member"},
	{"question":"委託","answers":["いたく"],"comment":"(n,vs) consign (goods (for sale) to a firm)/entrust (person with something)/commit"},
	{"question":"姪","answers":["めい"],"comment":"(n) niece"},
	{"question":"姿","answers":["すがた"],"comment":"(n) figure/shape/appearance"},
	{"question":"姿勢","answers":["しせい"],"comment":"(n) attitude/posture"},
	{"question":"威力","answers":["いりょく"],"comment":"(n) power/might/authority/influence"},
	{"question":"威張る","answers":["いばる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be proud/to swagger"},
	{"question":"娘","answers":["むすめ"],"comment":"(n) (hum) daughter"},
	{"question":"娯楽","answers":["ごらく"],"comment":"(n) pleasure/amusement"},
	{"question":"婉曲","answers":["えんきょく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) euphemistic/circumlocution/roundabout/indirect/insinuating"},
	{"question":"婚約","answers":["こんやく"],"comment":"(n,vs) engagement/betrothal"},
	{"question":"婦人","answers":["ふじん"],"comment":"(n) woman/female"},
	{"question":"婿","answers":["むこ"],"comment":"(n) son-in-law"},
	{"question":"嫁","answers":["よめ"],"comment":"(n) bride/daughter-in-law"},
	{"question":"嫉妬","answers":["しっと"],"comment":"(n,vs) jealousy"},
	{"question":"嫌","answers":["いや"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant/reluctant"},
	{"question":"嫌い","answers":["きらい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dislike/hate"},
	{"question":"嫌う","answers":["きらう"],"comment":"(v5u) to hate/to dislike/to loathe"},
	{"question":"嫌がる","answers":["いやがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to hate/to dislike"},
	{"question":"嬉しい","answers":["うれしい"],"comment":"(adj) happy/glad/pleasant"},
	{"question":"子","answers":["こ"],"comment":"(n) first sign of Chinese zodiac (The Rat, 11pm-1am, north, November)"},
	{"question":"子供","answers":["こども"],"comment":"(n) child/children"},
	{"question":"子孫","answers":["しそん"],"comment":"(n) descendants/posterity/offspring"},
	{"question":"子息","answers":["しそく"],"comment":"(n) (hon) son"},
	{"question":"字","answers":["じ"],"comment":"(n) character/hand-writing"},
	{"question":"字体","answers":["じたい"],"comment":"(n) type/font/lettering"},
	{"question":"字引","answers":["じびき"],"comment":"(n) dictionary"},
	{"question":"存じる","answers":["ぞんじる"],"comment":"(v1) (hum) to know"},
	{"question":"存在","answers":["そんざい"],"comment":"(n,vs) existence/being"},
	{"question":"存続","answers":["そんぞく"],"comment":"(n,vs) duration/continuance"},
	{"question":"孝行","answers":["こうこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) filial piety"},
	{"question":"季刊","answers":["きかん"],"comment":"(n) quarterly (e.g. magazine)"},
	{"question":"季節","answers":["きせつ"],"comment":"(n) season"},
	{"question":"孤児","answers":["こじ"],"comment":"(n) orphan"},
	{"question":"孤独","answers":["こどく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) isolation/loneliness/solitude"},
	{"question":"孤立","answers":["こりつ"],"comment":"(n) isolation/helplessness"},
	{"question":"学","answers":["がく"],"comment":"(n) learning/scholarship/erudition/knowledge"},
	{"question":"学ぶ","answers":["まなぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to study (in depth)/to learn/to take lessons in"},
	{"question":"学会","answers":["がっかい"],"comment":"(n) scientific society/academic meeting"},
	{"question":"学力","answers":["がくりょく"],"comment":"(n) scholarship/knowledge/literary ability"},
	{"question":"学問","answers":["がくもん"],"comment":"(n) scholarship/study/learning"},
	{"question":"学士","answers":["がくし"],"comment":"(n) university graduate"},
	{"question":"学年","answers":["がくねん"],"comment":"(n) year in school/grade in school"},
	{"question":"学期","answers":["がっき"],"comment":"(n) term (school)"},
	{"question":"学校","answers":["がっこう"],"comment":"(n) school"},
	{"question":"学歴","answers":["がくれき"],"comment":"(n) academic background"},
	{"question":"学生","answers":["がくせい"],"comment":"(n) student"},
	{"question":"学科","answers":["がっか"],"comment":"(n) study subject/course of study"},
	{"question":"学級","answers":["がっきゅう"],"comment":"(n) grade in school"},
	{"question":"学習","answers":["がくしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) study/learning"},
	{"question":"学者","answers":["がくしゃ"],"comment":"(n) scholar"},
	{"question":"学芸","answers":["がくげい"],"comment":"(n) arts and sciences/liberal arts"},
	{"question":"学術","answers":["がくじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) science/learning/scholarship"},
	{"question":"学説","answers":["がくせつ"],"comment":"(n) theory"},
	{"question":"学部","answers":["がくぶ"],"comment":"(n) department of a university/undergraduate"},
	{"question":"孫","answers":["まご"],"comment":"(n) grandchild"},
	{"question":"宅","answers":["たく"],"comment":"(n) house/home/husband"},
	{"question":"宇宙","answers":["うちゅう"],"comment":"(n) universe/cosmos/space"},
	{"question":"守る","answers":["まもる"],"comment":"(v5r) to protect/to obey/to guard/to abide (by the rules)"},
	{"question":"守備","answers":["しゅび"],"comment":"(n) defense"},
	{"question":"守衛","answers":["しゅえい"],"comment":"(n) security guard/doorkeeper"},
	{"question":"安い","answers":["やすい"],"comment":"(adj) cheap/inexpensive/peaceful/quiet/gossipy/thoughtless"},
	{"question":"安っぽい","answers":["やすっぽい"],"comment":"(adj) cheap-looking/tawdry/insignificant"},
	{"question":"安全","answers":["あんぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) safety/security"},
	{"question":"安定","answers":["あんてい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) stability/equilibrium"},
	{"question":"安心","answers":["あんしん"],"comment":"(n) (Buddhism) obtaining peace of mind through faith or ascetic practice"},
	{"question":"安易","answers":["あんい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) easy-going"},
	{"question":"安静","answers":["あんせい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) rest"},
	{"question":"完ぺき","answers":["かんぺき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) perfection/completeness/flawless"},
	{"question":"完了","answers":["かんりょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) completion/conclusion"},
	{"question":"完全","answers":["かんぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) perfection/completeness"},
	{"question":"完成","answers":["かんせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) complete/completion/(2) perfection/accomplishment"},
	{"question":"宗教","answers":["しゅうきょう"],"comment":"(n) religion"},
	{"question":"官僚","answers":["かんりょう"],"comment":"(n) bureaucrat/bureaucracy"},
	{"question":"官庁","answers":["かんちょう"],"comment":"(n) government office/authorities"},
	{"question":"宙返り","answers":["ちゅうがえり"],"comment":"(n) somersault/looping-the-loop"},
	{"question":"定まる","answers":["さだまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to become settled/to be fixed"},
	{"question":"定める","answers":["さだめる"],"comment":"(v1) to decide/to establish/to determine"},
	{"question":"定休日","answers":["ていきゅうび"],"comment":"(n) regular holiday"},
	{"question":"定価","answers":["ていか"],"comment":"(n) established price"},
	{"question":"定員","answers":["ていいん"],"comment":"(n) fixed number of regular personnel/capacity (of boat, hall, aeroplane, etc.)"},
	{"question":"定年","answers":["ていねん"],"comment":"(n) retirement age"},
	{"question":"定期","answers":["ていき"],"comment":"(n) fixed term"},
	{"question":"定期券","answers":["ていきけん"],"comment":"(n) commuter pass/season ticket"},
	{"question":"定義","answers":["ていぎ"],"comment":"(n,vs) definition"},
	{"question":"定規","answers":["じょうぎ"],"comment":"(n) (measuring) ruler"},
	{"question":"定食","answers":["ていしょく"],"comment":"(n) set meal/special (of the day)"},
	{"question":"宛てる","answers":["あてる"],"comment":"(v1) to address"},
	{"question":"宛名","answers":["あてな"],"comment":"(n) address/direction"},
	{"question":"宜しい","answers":["よろしい"],"comment":"(adj) (hon) good/OK/all right/fine/very well/will do/may/can"},
	{"question":"宝","answers":["たから"],"comment":"(n) treasure"},
	{"question":"宝石","answers":["ほうせき"],"comment":"(n) gem/jewel"},
	{"question":"実","answers":["じつ","み"],"comment":"(n) fruit/nut/seed/content/good result"},
	{"question":"実に","answers":["じつに"],"comment":"(adv) indeed/truly/surely"},
	{"question":"実は","answers":["じつは"],"comment":"(adv,exp) as a matter of fact/by the way"},
	{"question":"実る","answers":["みのる"],"comment":"(v5r) to bear fruit/to ripen"},
	{"question":"実例","answers":["じつれい"],"comment":"(n) example/illustration"},
	{"question":"実力","answers":["じつりょく"],"comment":"(n) merit/efficiency/arms/force"},
	{"question":"実家","answers":["じっか"],"comment":"(n) (one's parents') home"},
	{"question":"実感","answers":["じっかん"],"comment":"(n) feelings (actual, true)"},
	{"question":"実態","answers":["じったい"],"comment":"(n) truth/fact"},
	{"question":"実施","answers":["じっし"],"comment":"(n,vs) enforcement/enact/put into practice/carry out/operation"},
	{"question":"実業家","answers":["じつぎょうか"],"comment":"(n) industrialist/businessman"},
	{"question":"実物","answers":["じつぶつ"],"comment":"(n) real thing/original"},
	{"question":"実現","answers":["じつげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) implementation/materialization/realization"},
	{"question":"実用","answers":["じつよう"],"comment":"(n) practical use/utility"},
	{"question":"実績","answers":["じっせき"],"comment":"(n) achievements/actual results"},
	{"question":"実習","answers":["じっしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) practice/training"},
	{"question":"実行","answers":["じっこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) practice/performance/execution (e.g. program)/realization"},
	{"question":"実費","answers":["じっぴ"],"comment":"(n) actual expense/cost price"},
	{"question":"実践","answers":["じっせん"],"comment":"(n) practice/put into practice"},
	{"question":"実際","answers":["じっさい"],"comment":"(adj-no,adv,n) practical/actual condition/status quo"},
	{"question":"実験","answers":["じっけん"],"comment":"(n) experiment"},
	{"question":"客","answers":["きゃく"],"comment":"(n) guest/customer"},
	{"question":"客席","answers":["きゃくせき"],"comment":"(n) guest seating"},
	{"question":"客観","answers":["きゃっかん"],"comment":"(n) objective"},
	{"question":"客間","answers":["きゃくま"],"comment":"(n) parlor/guest room"},
	{"question":"宣伝","answers":["せんでん"],"comment":"(n,vs) propaganda/publicity"},
	{"question":"宣教","answers":["せんきょう"],"comment":"(n) religious mission"},
	{"question":"宣言","answers":["せんげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) declaration/proclamation/announcement"},
	{"question":"宮殿","answers":["きゅうでん"],"comment":"(n) palace"},
	{"question":"害","answers":["がい"],"comment":"(n,vs) injury/harm/evil influence/damage"},
	{"question":"害する","answers":["がいする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to injure/to damage/to harm/to kill/to hinder"},
	{"question":"宴会","answers":["えんかい"],"comment":"(n) party/banquet"},
	{"question":"家","answers":["いえ","うち"],"comment":"(suf) house/family"},
	{"question":"家主","answers":["やぬし"],"comment":"(n) landlord"},
	{"question":"家事","answers":["かじ"],"comment":"(n) housework/domestic chores"},
	{"question":"家具","answers":["かぐ"],"comment":"(n) furniture"},
	{"question":"家内","answers":["かない"],"comment":"(n) (hum) wife"},
	{"question":"家出","answers":["いえで"],"comment":"(n,vs) running away from home/leaving home"},
	{"question":"家屋","answers":["かおく"],"comment":"(n) house/building"},
	{"question":"家庭","answers":["かてい"],"comment":"(n) home/family/household"},
	{"question":"家族","answers":["かぞく"],"comment":"(n) family/members of a family"},
	{"question":"家来","answers":["けらい"],"comment":"(n) retainer/retinue/servant"},
	{"question":"家畜","answers":["かちく"],"comment":"(n) domestic animals/livestock/cattle"},
	{"question":"家計","answers":["かけい"],"comment":"(n) household economy/family finances"},
	{"question":"家賃","answers":["やちん"],"comment":"(n) rent"},
	{"question":"容器","answers":["ようき"],"comment":"(n) container/vessel"},
	{"question":"容易","answers":["ようい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) easy/simple/plain"},
	{"question":"容積","answers":["ようせき"],"comment":"(n) capacity/volume"},
	{"question":"宿","answers":["やど"],"comment":"(n) inn/lodging"},
	{"question":"宿命","answers":["しゅくめい"],"comment":"(n) fate/destiny/predestination"},
	{"question":"宿泊","answers":["しゅくはく"],"comment":"(n) lodging"},
	{"question":"宿題","answers":["しゅくだい"],"comment":"(n) homework"},
	{"question":"寂しい","answers":["さびしい"],"comment":"(adj) lonely/lonesome/solitary/desolate"},
	{"question":"寄せる","answers":["よせる"],"comment":"(v1) to collect/to gather/to add/to put aside"},
	{"question":"寄り掛かる","answers":["よりかかる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to lean against/to recline on/to lean on/to rely on"},
	{"question":"寄る","answers":["よる"],"comment":"(v5r) to visit/to drop in/to approach"},
	{"question":"寄与","answers":["きよ"],"comment":"(n,vs) contribution/service"},
	{"question":"寄付","answers":["きふ"],"comment":"(n,vs) contribution/donation"},
	{"question":"寄贈","answers":["きぞう"],"comment":"(n) donation/presentation"},
	{"question":"密か","answers":["ひそか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) secret/private/surreptitious"},
	{"question":"密度","answers":["みつど"],"comment":"(n) density"},
	{"question":"密接","answers":["みっせつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) related/connected/close/intimate"},
	{"question":"密集","answers":["みっしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) crowd/close formation/dense"},
	{"question":"富","answers":["とみ"],"comment":"(n) wealth/fortune"},
	{"question":"富む","answers":["とむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be rich/to become rich"},
	{"question":"富豪","answers":["ふごう"],"comment":"(n) wealthy person/millionaire"},
	{"question":"寒い","answers":["さむい"],"comment":"(adj) cold (e.g. weather)"},
	{"question":"寒帯","answers":["かんたい"],"comment":"(n) frigid zone"},
	{"question":"寒気","answers":["さむけ"],"comment":"(n) (1) cold/frost/(2) a cold/a chill/shivering fit"},
	{"question":"寛容","answers":["かんよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) forbearance/tolerance/generosity"},
	{"question":"寝かせる","answers":["ねかせる"],"comment":"(v1) to put to bed/to lay down/to ferment"},
	{"question":"寝る","answers":["ねる"],"comment":"(v1) to go to bed/to lie down/to sleep"},
	{"question":"寝台","answers":["しんだい"],"comment":"(n) bed/couch"},
	{"question":"寝坊","answers":["ねぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) sleeping in late"},
	{"question":"寝巻","answers":["ねまき"],"comment":"(n) sleep-wear/nightclothes/pyjamas/nightgown/nightdress"},
	{"question":"寝間着","answers":["ねまき"],"comment":"(n) sleep-wear/nightclothes/pyjamas/nightgown/nightdress"},
	{"question":"察する","answers":["さっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to guess/to sense/to presume/to judge/to sympathize with"},
	{"question":"寧ろ","answers":["むしろ"],"comment":"(adv) rather/better/instead"},
	{"question":"審判","answers":["しんぱん"],"comment":"(n,vs) refereeing/trial/judgement/umpire/referee"},
	{"question":"審査","answers":["しんさ"],"comment":"(n) judging/inspection/examination/investigation"},
	{"question":"審議","answers":["しんぎ"],"comment":"(n) deliberation"},
	{"question":"寮","answers":["りょう"],"comment":"(n) hostel/dormitory"},
	{"question":"寸法","answers":["すんぽう"],"comment":"(n) measurement/size/dimension"},
	{"question":"寺","answers":["てら"],"comment":"(n) temple"},
	{"question":"寺院","answers":["じいん"],"comment":"(n) temple"},
	{"question":"対","answers":["たい","つい"],"comment":"(n) pair/couple/set"},
	{"question":"対する","answers":["たいする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to face/to confront/to oppose"},
	{"question":"対処","answers":["たいしょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) deal with/cope"},
	{"question":"対応","answers":["たいおう"],"comment":"(n,vs) interaction/correspondence/coping with/dealing with"},
	{"question":"対抗","answers":["たいこう"],"comment":"(n) opposition/antagonism"},
	{"question":"対比","answers":["たいひ"],"comment":"(n,vs) contrast/comparison"},
	{"question":"対決","answers":["たいけつ"],"comment":"(n) confrontation/showdown"},
	{"question":"対照","answers":["たいしょう"],"comment":"(n) contrast/antithesis/comparison"},
	{"question":"対立","answers":["たいりつ"],"comment":"(n) confrontation/opposition/antagonism"},
	{"question":"対等","answers":["たいとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) equivalent"},
	{"question":"対策","answers":["たいさく"],"comment":"(n) counter-plan/counter-measure"},
	{"question":"対話","answers":["たいわ"],"comment":"(n,vs) interactive/interaction/conversation/dialogue"},
	{"question":"対談","answers":["たいだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) talk/dialogue/conversation"},
	{"question":"対象","answers":["たいしょう"],"comment":"(n) target/object (of worship, study, etc)/subject (of taxation, etc)"},
	{"question":"対面","answers":["たいめん"],"comment":"(n) interview/meeting"},
	{"question":"寿命","answers":["じゅみょう"],"comment":"(n) life span"},
	{"question":"封","answers":["ふう"],"comment":"(n) seal"},
	{"question":"封建","answers":["ほうけん"],"comment":"(n) feudalistic"},
	{"question":"封筒","answers":["ふうとう"],"comment":"(n) envelope"},
	{"question":"封鎖","answers":["ふうさ"],"comment":"(n) blockade/freezing (funds)"},
	{"question":"専ら","answers":["もっぱら"],"comment":"(adv) wholly/solely/entirely"},
	{"question":"専修","answers":["せんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) specialization"},
	{"question":"専制","answers":["せんせい"],"comment":"(n) despotism/autocracy"},
	{"question":"専攻","answers":["せんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) major subject/special study"},
	{"question":"専用","answers":["せんよう"],"comment":"(n,pref,suf) exclusive use/personal use"},
	{"question":"専門","answers":["せんもん"],"comment":"(n) speciality/subject of study/expert"},
	{"question":"射す","answers":["さす"],"comment":"(v5s) to shine/to strike"},
	{"question":"将来","answers":["しょうらい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) future/prospects"},
	{"question":"将棋","answers":["しょうぎ"],"comment":"(n) Japanese chess"},
	{"question":"尊い","answers":["とうとい"],"comment":"(adj) precious/valuable/priceless/noble/exalted/sacred"},
	{"question":"尊ぶ","answers":["とうとぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to value/to prize/to esteem"},
	{"question":"尊敬","answers":["そんけい"],"comment":"(n,vs) respect/esteem/reverence/honour"},
	{"question":"尊重","answers":["そんちょう"],"comment":"(n) respect/esteem/regard"},
	{"question":"尋ねる","answers":["たずねる"],"comment":"(v1) to ask/to enquire"},
	{"question":"導く","answers":["みちびく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be guided/to be shown"},
	{"question":"導入","answers":["どうにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) introduction/bringing in/leading in"},
	{"question":"小さい","answers":["ちいさい"],"comment":"(adj) small/little/tiny"},
	{"question":"小便","answers":["しょうべん"],"comment":"(n) (col) urine/piss"},
	{"question":"小児科","answers":["しょうにか"],"comment":"(n) pediatrics"},
	{"question":"小切手","answers":["こぎって"],"comment":"(n) cheque/check"},
	{"question":"小包","answers":["こづつみ"],"comment":"(n) parcel/package"},
	{"question":"小売","answers":["こうり"],"comment":"(n,vs) retail"},
	{"question":"小学校","answers":["しょうがっこう"],"comment":"(n) primary school/elementary school"},
	{"question":"小学生","answers":["しょうがくせい"],"comment":"(n) grade school student"},
	{"question":"小屋","answers":["こや"],"comment":"(n) hut/cabin/shed/(animal) pen"},
	{"question":"小指","answers":["こゆび"],"comment":"(n) little finger"},
	{"question":"小数","answers":["しょうすう"],"comment":"(n) fraction (part of)/decimal"},
	{"question":"小柄","answers":["こがら"],"comment":"(n) knife attached to the sheath of a sword"},
	{"question":"小母さん","answers":["おばさん"],"comment":"(n) (uk) lady/woman/ma'am"},
	{"question":"小父さん","answers":["おじさん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) (uk) middle-aged gentleman/uncle"},
	{"question":"小説","answers":["しょうせつ"],"comment":"(n) novel/story"},
	{"question":"小遣い","answers":["こづかい"],"comment":"(n) personal expenses/pocket money/spending money/incidental expenses/allowance"},
	{"question":"小銭","answers":["こぜに"],"comment":"(n) coins/small change"},
	{"question":"小鳥","answers":["ことり"],"comment":"(n) small bird"},
	{"question":"小麦","answers":["こむぎ"],"comment":"(n) wheat"},
	{"question":"少々","answers":["しょうしょう"],"comment":"(adv,exp,n-adv,n) just a minute/small quantity"},
	{"question":"少し","answers":["すこし"],"comment":"(adv,n) (1) small quantity/little/few/something/(2) little while/(3) short distance"},
	{"question":"少しも","answers":["すこしも"],"comment":"(adv,exp) anything of/not one bit"},
	{"question":"少ない","answers":["すくない"],"comment":"(adj) few/a little/scarce/insufficient/seldom"},
	{"question":"少女","answers":["しょうじょ"],"comment":"(n) daughter/young lady/virgin/maiden/little girl"},
	{"question":"少年","answers":["しょうねん"],"comment":"(n) boys/juveniles"},
	{"question":"尖る","answers":["とがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to taper to a point/to become sharp/to be sour/to look displeased"},
	{"question":"尤も","answers":["もっとも"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,conj,n) quite right/plausible/natural/but then/although"},
	{"question":"就く","answers":["つく"],"comment":"(v5k) to settle in (place)/to take (seat, position)/to study (under teacher)"},
	{"question":"就任","answers":["しゅうにん"],"comment":"(n,vs) inauguration/assumption of office"},
	{"question":"就業","answers":["しゅうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) employment/starting work"},
	{"question":"就職","answers":["しゅうしょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) finding employment/inauguration"},
	{"question":"尻","answers":["しり"],"comment":"(n) buttocks/bottom"},
	{"question":"尽きる","answers":["つきる"],"comment":"(v1) to be used up/to be run out/to be exhausted/to be consumed/to come to an end"},
	{"question":"尽くす","answers":["つくす"],"comment":"(v5s) (1) to exhaust/to run out/(2) to devote/to serve (a person)/to befriend"},
	{"question":"尾","answers":["お"],"comment":"(n) tail/ridge"},
	{"question":"尿","answers":["にょう"],"comment":"(n) urine"},
	{"question":"局","answers":["きょく"],"comment":"(n) court lady/lady in waiting"},
	{"question":"局限","answers":["きょくげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) limit/localize"},
	{"question":"居る","answers":["いる","おる"],"comment":"(v5r) (uk) (hum) to be (animate)/to be/to exist"},
	{"question":"居住","answers":["きょじゅう"],"comment":"(n) residence"},
	{"question":"居眠り","answers":["いねむり"],"comment":"(n,vs) dozing/nodding off"},
	{"question":"居間","answers":["いま"],"comment":"(n) living room (western style)"},
	{"question":"屈折","answers":["くっせつ"],"comment":"(n) bending/indentation/refraction"},
	{"question":"届","answers":["とどけ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) report/notification/registration"},
	{"question":"届く","answers":["とどく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) to reach"},
	{"question":"届ける","answers":["とどける"],"comment":"(v1) to deliver/to forward/to send/to report/to file notice (to the authorities)"},
	{"question":"屋上","answers":["おくじょう"],"comment":"(n) rooftop"},
	{"question":"屋外","answers":["おくがい"],"comment":"(n) outdoors"},
	{"question":"屋敷","answers":["やしき"],"comment":"(n) mansion"},
	{"question":"屋根","answers":["やね"],"comment":"(n) roof"},
	{"question":"屎尿","answers":["しにょう"],"comment":"(n) excreta/raw sewage/human waste/night soil"},
	{"question":"屑","answers":["くず"],"comment":"(n) waste/scrap"},
	{"question":"展望","answers":["てんぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) view/outlook/prospect"},
	{"question":"展示","answers":["てんじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) exhibition/display"},
	{"question":"展覧会","answers":["てんらんかい"],"comment":"(n) exhibition"},
	{"question":"展開","answers":["てんかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) develop/expansion (opposite of compression)"},
	{"question":"属する","answers":["ぞくする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to belong to/to come under/to be affiliated with/to be subject to"},
	{"question":"履く","answers":["はく"],"comment":"(v5k) to wear/to put on (lower body)"},
	{"question":"履歴","answers":["りれき"],"comment":"(n) personal history/background/career/log"},
	{"question":"山","answers":["やま"],"comment":"(n) (1) mountain/(2) pile/heap/(3) climax/critical point"},
	{"question":"山岳","answers":["さんがく"],"comment":"(n) mountains"},
	{"question":"山林","answers":["さんりん"],"comment":"(n) mountain forest/mountains and forest"},
	{"question":"山脈","answers":["さんみゃく"],"comment":"(n) mountain range"},
	{"question":"山腹","answers":["さんぷく"],"comment":"(n) hillside/mountainside"},
	{"question":"岩","answers":["いわ"],"comment":"(n) rock/crag"},
	{"question":"岩石","answers":["がんせき"],"comment":"(n) rock"},
	{"question":"岬","answers":["みさき"],"comment":"(n) cape (on coast)"},
	{"question":"岸","answers":["きし"],"comment":"(n) bank/coast/shore"},
	{"question":"峠","answers":["とうげ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) ridge/(mountain) pass/difficult part"},
	{"question":"峰","answers":["みね"],"comment":"(n) peak/ridge"},
	{"question":"島","answers":["しま"],"comment":"(n) island"},
	{"question":"崇拝","answers":["すうはい"],"comment":"(n,vs) worship/adoration/admiration/cult"},
	{"question":"崖","answers":["がけ"],"comment":"(n) cliff"},
	{"question":"崩す","answers":["くずす"],"comment":"(v5s) to destroy/to pull down/to make change (money)"},
	{"question":"崩れる","answers":["くずれる"],"comment":"(v1) to collapse/to crumble"},
	{"question":"崩壊","answers":["ほうかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) collapse/decay (physics)/crumbling/breaking down/caving in"},
	{"question":"嵐","answers":["あらし"],"comment":"(n) storm/tempest"},
	{"question":"川","answers":["かわ"],"comment":"(n) river"},
	{"question":"州","answers":["しゅう"],"comment":"(n) sandbank"},
	{"question":"巡る","answers":["めぐる"],"comment":"(v5r) to go around"},
	{"question":"巡査","answers":["じゅんさ"],"comment":"(n) police/policeman"},
	{"question":"巣","answers":["す"],"comment":"(n) nest/rookery/breeding place/beehive/cobweb/den/haunt"},
	{"question":"工事","answers":["こうじ"],"comment":"(n) construction work"},
	{"question":"工作","answers":["こうさく"],"comment":"(n) work/construction/handicraft/maneuvering"},
	{"question":"工員","answers":["こういん"],"comment":"(n) factory worker"},
	{"question":"工場","answers":["こうじょう","こうば"],"comment":"(n) factory/plant/mill/workshop"},
	{"question":"工夫","answers":["くふう"],"comment":"(n) labourer/worker"},
	{"question":"工学","answers":["こうがく"],"comment":"(n) engineering"},
	{"question":"工業","answers":["こうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) (manufacturing) industry"},
	{"question":"工芸","answers":["こうげい"],"comment":"(n) industrial arts"},
	{"question":"左","answers":["ひだり"],"comment":"(n) left hand side"},
	{"question":"左利き","answers":["ひだりきき"],"comment":"(n) left-handedness/sake drinker/left-hander"},
	{"question":"左右","answers":["さゆう"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) left and right/(2) influence/control/domination"},
	{"question":"巧み","answers":["たくみ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) skill/cleverness"},
	{"question":"巧妙","answers":["こうみょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) ingenious/skillful/clever/deft"},
	{"question":"巨大","answers":["きょだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) huge/gigantic/enormous"},
	{"question":"差","answers":["さ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) difference/variation"},
	{"question":"差し上げる","answers":["さしあげる"],"comment":"(v1) (pol) to give/to hold up/to lift up/to offer"},
	{"question":"差し出す","answers":["さしだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to present/to submit/to tender/to hold out"},
	{"question":"差し引き","answers":["さしひき"],"comment":"(n) deduction/subtraction/balance/ebb and flow/rise and fall"},
	{"question":"差し支え","answers":["さしつかえ"],"comment":"(n) hindrance/impediment"},
	{"question":"差し支える","answers":["さしつかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to interfere/to hinder/to become impeded"},
	{"question":"差す","answers":["さす"],"comment":"(v5s) to raise (stretch out) hands/to raise umbrella"},
	{"question":"差別","answers":["さべつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) discrimination/distinction/differentiation"},
	{"question":"差額","answers":["さがく"],"comment":"(n) balance/difference/margin"},
	{"question":"巻く","answers":["まく"],"comment":"(v5k) to wind/to coil/to roll"},
	{"question":"市","answers":["いち","し"],"comment":"(n-suf) city"},
	{"question":"市場","answers":["いちば","しじょう"],"comment":"(n) (the) market (as a concept)"},
	{"question":"市民","answers":["しみん"],"comment":"(n) citizen/townspeople"},
	{"question":"布","answers":["ぬの"],"comment":"(n) cloth"},
	{"question":"布告","answers":["ふこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) edict/ordinance/proclamation"},
	{"question":"布団","answers":["ふとん"],"comment":"(n) bedding (Japanese style)/futon"},
	{"question":"布巾","answers":["ふきん"],"comment":"(n) tea-towel/dish cloth"},
	{"question":"希望","answers":["きぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) hope/wish/aspiration"},
	{"question":"席","answers":["せき"],"comment":"(n) seat"},
	{"question":"帯","answers":["おび"],"comment":"(n-suf) band (e.g. conduction, valence)"},
	{"question":"帯びる","answers":["おびる"],"comment":"(v1) to wear/to carry/to be entrusted/to have/to take on/to have a trace of/to be tinged with"},
	{"question":"帰す","answers":["かえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to send back"},
	{"question":"帰り","answers":["かえり"],"comment":"(n) return/coming back"},
	{"question":"帰る","answers":["かえる"],"comment":"(v5r) to go back/to go home/to come home/to return"},
	{"question":"帰京","answers":["ききょう"],"comment":"(n) returning to Tokyo"},
	{"question":"帰宅","answers":["きたく"],"comment":"(n,vs) returning home"},
	{"question":"常に","answers":["つねに"],"comment":"(adv) always/constantly"},
	{"question":"常識","answers":["じょうしき"],"comment":"(n) common sense"},
	{"question":"帽子","answers":["ぼうし"],"comment":"(n) hat"},
	{"question":"幅","answers":["はば"],"comment":"(n) width/breadth"},
	{"question":"幕","answers":["まく"],"comment":"curtain/bunting/act (in play)"},
	{"question":"干し物","answers":["ほしもの"],"comment":"(n) dried washing (clothes)"},
	{"question":"干す","answers":["ほす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to air/to dry/to desiccate/to drain (off)/to drink up"},
	{"question":"干渉","answers":["かんしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) interference/intervention"},
	{"question":"平たい","answers":["ひらたい"],"comment":"(adj) flat/even/level/simple/plain"},
	{"question":"平ら","answers":["たいら"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) flatness/level/smooth/calm/plain/sitting tailor fashion"},
	{"question":"平仮名","answers":["ひらがな"],"comment":"(n) hiragana/47 syllables/the cursive syllabary"},
	{"question":"平凡","answers":["へいぼん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) common/commonplace/ordinary/mediocre"},
	{"question":"平和","answers":["へいわ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) peace/harmony"},
	{"question":"平均","answers":["へいきん"],"comment":"(n) equilibrium/balance/average/mean"},
	{"question":"平常","answers":["へいじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n-t) normal/usual"},
	{"question":"平方","answers":["へいほう"],"comment":"(n) square (e.g. metre)/square"},
	{"question":"平日","answers":["へいじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) weekday/ordinary days"},
	{"question":"平気","answers":["へいき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) coolness/calmness/composure/unconcern"},
	{"question":"平等","answers":["びょうどう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) equality (a)/impartiality/evenness"},
	{"question":"平野","answers":["へいや"],"comment":"(n) plain/open field"},
	{"question":"年","answers":["とし"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) year/age"},
	{"question":"年中","answers":["ねんじゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) whole year/always/everyday"},
	{"question":"年代","answers":["ねんだい"],"comment":"(n) age/era/period/date"},
	{"question":"年号","answers":["ねんごう"],"comment":"(n) name of an era/year number"},
	{"question":"年寄","answers":["としより"],"comment":"(n) old people/the aged"},
	{"question":"年度","answers":["ねんど"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) year/fiscal year/school year/term"},
	{"question":"年月","answers":["としつき","ねんげつ"],"comment":"(n) months and years"},
	{"question":"年賀","answers":["ねんが"],"comment":"(n) New Year's greetings/New Year's card"},
	{"question":"年輪","answers":["ねんりん"],"comment":"(n) annual tree ring"},
	{"question":"年鑑","answers":["ねんかん"],"comment":"(n) yearbook"},
	{"question":"年長","answers":["ねんちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) seniority"},
	{"question":"年間","answers":["ねんかん"],"comment":"(n-t) year"},
	{"question":"年頃","answers":["としごろ"],"comment":"(adv,n) age/marriageable age/age of puberty/adolescence/for some years"},
	{"question":"年齢","answers":["ねんれい"],"comment":"(n) age/years"},
	{"question":"幸い","answers":["さいわい"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) happiness/blessedness"},
	{"question":"幸せ","answers":["しあわせ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) happiness/good fortune/luck/blessing"},
	{"question":"幸福","answers":["こうふく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) happiness/blessedness"},
	{"question":"幸運","answers":["こううん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) good luck/fortune"},
	{"question":"幹","answers":["みき"],"comment":"(n) (tree) trunk"},
	{"question":"幹線","answers":["かんせん"],"comment":"(n) main line/trunk line"},
	{"question":"幹部","answers":["かんぶ"],"comment":"(n) management/(executive) staff/leaders"},
	{"question":"幼い","answers":["おさない"],"comment":"(adj) very young/childish"},
	{"question":"幼児","answers":["ようじ"],"comment":"(n) infant/baby/child"},
	{"question":"幼稚園","answers":["ようちえん"],"comment":"(n) kindergarten"},
	{"question":"幽霊","answers":["ゆうれい"],"comment":"(n) ghost/specter/apparition/phantom"},
	{"question":"幾つ","answers":["いくつ"],"comment":"(n) how many?/how old?"},
	{"question":"幾ら","answers":["いくら"],"comment":"(adv,n) how much?/how many?"},
	{"question":"幾分","answers":["いくぶん"],"comment":"(adv,n) somewhat"},
	{"question":"幾多","answers":["いくた"],"comment":"(adv,n) many/numerous"},
	{"question":"広々","answers":["ひろびろ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) extensive/spacious"},
	{"question":"広い","answers":["ひろい"],"comment":"(adj) spacious/vast/wide"},
	{"question":"広がる","answers":["ひろがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to spread (out)/to extend/to stretch/to reach to/to get around"},
	{"question":"広げる","answers":["ひろげる"],"comment":"(v1) to spread/to extend/to expand/to enlarge/to widen/to broaden/to unfold/to open/to unroll"},
	{"question":"広さ","answers":["ひろさ"],"comment":"(n) extent"},
	{"question":"広まる","answers":["ひろまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to spread/to be propagated"},
	{"question":"広める","answers":["ひろめる"],"comment":"(v1) to broaden/to propagate"},
	{"question":"広告","answers":["こうこく"],"comment":"(n) advertisement"},
	{"question":"広場","answers":["ひろば"],"comment":"(n) plaza"},
	{"question":"庇う","answers":["かばう"],"comment":"(v5u) to protect someone/to take under one's wing/to plead for/to stick up for/to cover up for someone"},
	{"question":"床","answers":["ゆか"],"comment":"(n) floor"},
	{"question":"床の間","answers":["とこのま"],"comment":"(n) alcove"},
	{"question":"床屋","answers":["とこや"],"comment":"(n) barber"},
	{"question":"底","answers":["そこ"],"comment":"(n) bottom/sole"},
	{"question":"庖丁","answers":["ほうちょう"],"comment":"(n) kitchen knife/carving knife"},
	{"question":"店","answers":["みせ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) store/shop/establishment"},
	{"question":"店員","answers":["てんいん"],"comment":"(n) shop assistant/employee/clerk/salesperson"},
	{"question":"店屋","answers":["みせや"],"comment":"(n) store/shop"},
	{"question":"度","answers":["たび","ど"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) counter for occurrences"},
	{"question":"度忘れ","answers":["どわすれ"],"comment":"(n,vs) lapse of memory/forget for a moment"},
	{"question":"座る","answers":["すわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to sit"},
	{"question":"座布団","answers":["ざぶとん"],"comment":"(n) cushion (Japanese)/square cushion used when sitting on one's knees in a tatami-mat floor"},
	{"question":"座席","answers":["ざせき"],"comment":"(n) seat"},
	{"question":"座敷","answers":["ざしき"],"comment":"(n) tatami room"},
	{"question":"座標","answers":["ざひょう"],"comment":"(n) coordinate(s)"},
	{"question":"座談会","answers":["ざだんかい"],"comment":"(n) symposium/round-table discussion"},
	{"question":"庭","answers":["にわ"],"comment":"(n) garden"},
	{"question":"庶務","answers":["しょむ"],"comment":"(n) general affairs"},
	{"question":"庶民","answers":["しょみん"],"comment":"(n) masses/common people"},
	{"question":"廃棄","answers":["はいき"],"comment":"(n,vs) annullment/disposal/abandon/scrap/discarding/repeal"},
	{"question":"廃止","answers":["はいし"],"comment":"(n,vs) abolition/repeal"},
	{"question":"廊下","answers":["ろうか"],"comment":"(n) corridor"},
	{"question":"延ばす","answers":["のばす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to lengthen/to stretch/to reach out/to postpone/to prolong/to extend/to grow (beard)"},
	{"question":"延びる","answers":["のびる"],"comment":"(v1) to be prolonged"},
	{"question":"延べ","answers":["のべ"],"comment":"(n) futures/credit (buying)/stretching/total"},
	{"question":"延期","answers":["えんき"],"comment":"(n,vs) postponement/adjournment"},
	{"question":"延長","answers":["えんちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) extension/elongation/prolongation/lengthening"},
	{"question":"建つ","answers":["たつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to erect/to be erected/to be built"},
	{"question":"建てる","answers":["たてる"],"comment":"(v1) to build/to construct"},
	{"question":"建前","answers":["たてまえ"],"comment":"(n) face/official stance/public position or attitude (as opposed to private thoughts)"},
	{"question":"建物","answers":["たてもの"],"comment":"(n) building"},
	{"question":"建築","answers":["けんちく"],"comment":"(n,vs) construction/architecture"},
	{"question":"建設","answers":["けんせつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) construction/establishment"},
	{"question":"弁償","answers":["べんしょう"],"comment":"(n) next word/compensation/reparation/indemnity/reimbursement"},
	{"question":"弁当","answers":["べんとう"],"comment":"(n) box lunch"},
	{"question":"弁解","answers":["べんかい"],"comment":"(n) explanation/justification/defence/excuse"},
	{"question":"弁論","answers":["べんろん"],"comment":"(n) discussion/debate/argument"},
	{"question":"弁護","answers":["べんご"],"comment":"(n) defense/pleading/advocacy"},
	{"question":"式","answers":["しき"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) equation/formula/ceremony"},
	{"question":"式場","answers":["しきじょう"],"comment":"(n) ceremonial hall/place of ceremony (e.g. marriage)"},
	{"question":"弓","answers":["ゆみ"],"comment":"(n) bow (and arrow)"},
	{"question":"引きずる","answers":["ひきずる"],"comment":"(v5r) to seduce/to drag along/to pull/to prolong/to support"},
	{"question":"引き上げる","answers":["ひきあげる"],"comment":"(v1) to withdraw/to leave/to pull out/to retire"},
	{"question":"引き出し","answers":["ひきだし"],"comment":"(n) drawer/drawing out"},
	{"question":"引き止める","answers":["ひきとめる"],"comment":"(v1) to detain/to check/to restrain"},
	{"question":"引き起こす","answers":["ひきおこす"],"comment":"(v5s) to cause"},
	{"question":"引く","answers":["ひく"],"comment":"(v5k) minus/to pull/to play (string instr.)"},
	{"question":"引っ張る","answers":["ひっぱる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to pull/to draw/to stretch/to drag/(2) to pull the ball (baseball)"},
	{"question":"引っ掛かる","answers":["ひっかかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be caught in/to be stuck in/to be cheated"},
	{"question":"引っ掻く","answers":["ひっかく"],"comment":"(v5k) to scratch"},
	{"question":"引っ繰り返す","answers":["ひっくりかえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to turn over/to overturn/to knock over/to upset/to turn inside out"},
	{"question":"引っ繰り返る","answers":["ひっくりかえる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be overturned/to be upset/to topple over/to be reversed"},
	{"question":"引っ越す","answers":["ひっこす"],"comment":"(v5s) to move/to change residence"},
	{"question":"引っ込む","answers":["ひっこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to draw back/to sink/to cave in"},
	{"question":"引下げる","answers":["ひきさげる"],"comment":"(v1) to pull down/to lower/to reduce/to withdraw"},
	{"question":"引出す","answers":["ひきだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pull out/to take out/to draw out/to withdraw"},
	{"question":"引分け","answers":["ひきわけ"],"comment":"(n) a draw (in competition)/tie game"},
	{"question":"引力","answers":["いんりょく"],"comment":"(n) gravity"},
	{"question":"引取る","answers":["ひきとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to take charge of/to take over/to retire to a private place"},
	{"question":"引受る","answers":["ひきうける"],"comment":"(v1) to undertake/to take up/to take over/to be responsible for/to guarantee/to contract (disease)"},
	{"question":"引用","answers":["いんよう"],"comment":"(n) quotation/citation"},
	{"question":"引算","answers":["ひきざん"],"comment":"(n) subtraction"},
	{"question":"引越し","answers":["ひっこし"],"comment":"(io) (n) moving (dwelling, office, etc.)/changing residence"},
	{"question":"引返す","answers":["ひきかえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to repeat/to send back/to bring back/to retrace one's steps"},
	{"question":"引退","answers":["いんたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) retire"},
	{"question":"弛み","answers":["たるみ"],"comment":"(n) slack/slackening/dullness/letdown"},
	{"question":"弛む","answers":["たるむ"],"comment":"(v5m,vi) to slacken/to loosen/to relax"},
	{"question":"弟","answers":["おとうと"],"comment":"(n) younger brother/faithful service to those older/brotherly affection"},
	{"question":"弟子","answers":["でし"],"comment":"(n) pupil/disciple/adherent/follower/apprentice/young person/teacher's student-helper"},
	{"question":"弱","answers":["じゃく"],"comment":"weak/delicate/supple"},
	{"question":"弱い","answers":["よわい"],"comment":"(adj) weak/frail/delicate/tender/unskilled/weak (wine)"},
	{"question":"弱まる","answers":["よわまる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to abate/to weaken/to be emaciated/to be dejected/to be perplexed"},
	{"question":"弱める","answers":["よわめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to weaken"},
	{"question":"弱る","answers":["よわる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi,vt) to weaken/to be troubled/to be downcast/to be emaciated/to be dejected/to be perplexed/to impair"},
	{"question":"弱点","answers":["じゃくてん"],"comment":"(n) weak point/weakness"},
	{"question":"張り切る","answers":["はりきる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be in high spirits/to be full of vigor/to be enthusiastic/to be eager/to stretch to breaking point"},
	{"question":"張り紙","answers":["はりがみ"],"comment":"(n) paper patch/paper backing/poster"},
	{"question":"張る","answers":["はる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi,vt) to stick/to paste/to put/to affix/to stretch/to spread/to strain/to stick out/to slap/to be expensive/to tighten"},
	{"question":"強い","answers":["つよい"],"comment":"(adj) strong/powerful/mighty/potent"},
	{"question":"強いて","answers":["しいて"],"comment":"(adv) by force"},
	{"question":"強いる","answers":["しいる"],"comment":"(v1) to force/to compel/to coerce"},
	{"question":"強まる","answers":["つよまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to get strong/to gain strength"},
	{"question":"強める","answers":["つよめる"],"comment":"(v1) to strengthen/to emphasize"},
	{"question":"強制","answers":["きょうせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) obligation/coercion/compulsion/enforcement"},
	{"question":"強力","answers":["きょうりょく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) herculean strength/mountain carrier-guide"},
	{"question":"強化","answers":["きょうか"],"comment":"(n,vs) strengthen/intensify/reinforce/solidify"},
	{"question":"強引","answers":["ごういん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) overbearing/coercive/pushy/forcible/high-handed"},
	{"question":"強気","answers":["つよき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) firm/strong"},
	{"question":"強烈","answers":["きょうれつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) strong/intense/severe"},
	{"question":"強盗","answers":["ごうとう"],"comment":"(n) robbery/burglary"},
	{"question":"強硬","answers":["きょうこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) firm/vigorous/unbending/unyielding/strong/stubborn"},
	{"question":"強行","answers":["きょうこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) forcing/enforcement"},
	{"question":"強調","answers":["きょうちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) emphasis/stress/stressed point"},
	{"question":"弾","answers":["たま"],"comment":"(n) bullet/shot/shell"},
	{"question":"弾く","answers":["はじく","ひく"],"comment":"(v5k) to play (piano, guitar)"},
	{"question":"弾む","answers":["はずむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to spring/to bound/to bounce/to be stimulated/to be encouraged/to get lively/to treat oneself to/to splurge on"},
	{"question":"弾力","answers":["だんりょく"],"comment":"(n) elasticity/flexibility"},
	{"question":"当たる","answers":["あたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be hit/to be successful/to face (confront)/to lie (in the direction of)/to undertake/to treat/to be equivalent to/to apply to/to be applicable/to be assigned"},
	{"question":"当て","answers":["あて"],"comment":"(n) object/aim/end/hopes/expectations"},
	{"question":"当てる","answers":["あてる"],"comment":"(v1) to hit/to apply a patch"},
	{"question":"当て字","answers":["あてじ"],"comment":"(n) phonetic-equivalent character/substitute character"},
	{"question":"当り","answers":["あたり"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) hit/success/reaching the mark/per .../vicinity/neighborhood"},
	{"question":"当人","answers":["とうにん"],"comment":"(n) the one concerned/the said person"},
	{"question":"当日","answers":["とうじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) appointed day/very day"},
	{"question":"当時","answers":["とうじ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) at that time/in those days"},
	{"question":"当然","answers":["とうぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) naturally/as a matter of course"},
	{"question":"当番","answers":["とうばん"],"comment":"(n) being on duty"},
	{"question":"当選","answers":["とうせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) being elected/winning the prize"},
	{"question":"形","answers":["かたち"],"comment":"(n) form/shape/figure/type"},
	{"question":"形勢","answers":["けいせい"],"comment":"(n) condition/situation/prospects"},
	{"question":"形容動詞","answers":["けいようどうし"],"comment":"(n) adjectival noun/quasi-adjective"},
	{"question":"形容詞","answers":["けいようし"],"comment":"(n) 'true' adjective"},
	{"question":"形式","answers":["けいしき"],"comment":"(n) form/formality/format/math expression"},
	{"question":"形態","answers":["けいたい"],"comment":"(n) form/shape/figure"},
	{"question":"形成","answers":["けいせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) formation"},
	{"question":"彫る","answers":["ほる"],"comment":"(v5r) to carve/to engrave/to sculpture/to chisel"},
	{"question":"彫刻","answers":["ちょうこく"],"comment":"(n) carving/engraving/sculpture"},
	{"question":"影","answers":["かげ"],"comment":"(n) shade/shadow/other side"},
	{"question":"影響","answers":["えいきょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) influence/effect"},
	{"question":"役","answers":["やく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) use/service/role/position"},
	{"question":"役に立つ","answers":["やくにたつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to be helpful/to be useful"},
	{"question":"役人","answers":["やくにん"],"comment":"(n) government official"},
	{"question":"役割","answers":["やくわり"],"comment":"(n) part/assigning (allotment of) parts/role/duties"},
	{"question":"役場","answers":["やくば"],"comment":"(n) town hall"},
	{"question":"役所","answers":["やくしょ"],"comment":"(n) government office/public office"},
	{"question":"役目","answers":["やくめ"],"comment":"(n) duty/business"},
	{"question":"役者","answers":["やくしゃ"],"comment":"(n) actor/actress"},
	{"question":"役職","answers":["やくしょく"],"comment":"(n) post/managerial position/official position"},
	{"question":"彼","answers":["かれ"],"comment":"(n) he/boyfriend"},
	{"question":"彼ら","answers":["かれら"],"comment":"(n) they (usually male)"},
	{"question":"彼女","answers":["かのじょ"],"comment":"(n) she/girl friend/sweetheart"},
	{"question":"彼等","answers":["かれら"],"comment":"(n) they (usually male)"},
	{"question":"往復","answers":["おうふく"],"comment":"(n,vs) (col) round trip/coming and going/return ticket"},
	{"question":"往診","answers":["おうしん"],"comment":"(n) doctor's visit/house call"},
	{"question":"征服","answers":["せいふく"],"comment":"(n) conquest/subjugation/overcoming"},
	{"question":"待ち合わせ","answers":["まちあわせ"],"comment":"(n) appointment"},
	{"question":"待ち合わせる","answers":["まちあわせる"],"comment":"(v1) to rendezvous/to meet at a prearranged place and time"},
	{"question":"待ち望む","answers":["まちのぞむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to look anxiously for/to wait eagerly for"},
	{"question":"待ち遠しい","answers":["まちどおしい"],"comment":"(adj) looking forward to"},
	{"question":"待つ","answers":["まつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to wait"},
	{"question":"待合室","answers":["まちあいしつ"],"comment":"(n) waiting room"},
	{"question":"待望","answers":["たいぼう"],"comment":"(n) expectant waiting"},
	{"question":"待遇","answers":["たいぐう"],"comment":"(n) treatment/reception"},
	{"question":"後","answers":["あと","うしろ","ご","のち"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) afterwards/since then/in the future"},
	{"question":"後回し","answers":["あとまわし"],"comment":"(n) putting off/postponing"},
	{"question":"後悔","answers":["こうかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) regret/repentance"},
	{"question":"後者","answers":["こうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) the latter"},
	{"question":"後輩","answers":["こうはい"],"comment":"(n) junior (at work or school)"},
	{"question":"後退","answers":["こうたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) retreat/backspace (BS)"},
	{"question":"徐々に","answers":["じょじょに"],"comment":"(adv) slowly/little by little/gradually/steadily/quietly"},
	{"question":"徐行","answers":["じょこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) going slowly"},
	{"question":"徒歩","answers":["とほ"],"comment":"(n) walking/going on foot"},
	{"question":"従う","answers":["したがう"],"comment":"(v5u) to abide (by the rules)/to obey/to follow/to accompany"},
	{"question":"従事","answers":["じゅうじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) engaging/pursuing/following"},
	{"question":"従兄弟","answers":["いとこ"],"comment":"(n) (uk) cousin (male)"},
	{"question":"従姉妹","answers":["いとこ"],"comment":"(n) (uk) cousin (female)"},
	{"question":"従来","answers":["じゅうらい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) up to now/so far/traditional"},
	{"question":"従業員","answers":["じゅうぎょういん"],"comment":"(n) employee/worker"},
	{"question":"得る","answers":["うる","える"],"comment":"(v1) to get/to gain/to win"},
	{"question":"得意","answers":["とくい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pride/triumph/prosperity/one's strong point/one's forte/one's specialty/customer/client"},
	{"question":"得点","answers":["とくてん"],"comment":"(n) score/points made/marks obtained/runs"},
	{"question":"御","answers":["お"],"comment":"(pref) honourable"},
	{"question":"御世辞","answers":["おせじ"],"comment":"(n) flattery/compliment"},
	{"question":"御中","answers":["おんちゅう"],"comment":"(n) and Company/Messrs."},
	{"question":"御主人","answers":["ごしゅじん"],"comment":"(n) (hon) your husband/her husband"},
	{"question":"御免","answers":["ごめん"],"comment":"(int,n) your pardon/declining (something)/dismissal/permission"},
	{"question":"御手洗","answers":["おてあらい"],"comment":"(n) font of purifying water placed at the entrance of a shrine"},
	{"question":"御無沙汰","answers":["ごぶさた"],"comment":"(n,vs) not writing or contacting for a while"},
	{"question":"御覧","answers":["ごらん"],"comment":"(int,n) (hon) look/inspection/try"},
	{"question":"御辞儀","answers":["おじぎ"],"comment":"(n,vs) bow"},
	{"question":"御飯","answers":["ごはん"],"comment":"(n) rice (cooked)/meal"},
	{"question":"御馳走","answers":["ごちそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) feast/treating (someone)"},
	{"question":"復旧","answers":["ふっきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) restoration/restitution/rehabilitation"},
	{"question":"復活","answers":["ふっかつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) revival (e.g. musical)/restoration"},
	{"question":"復習","answers":["ふくしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) review/revision"},
	{"question":"復興","answers":["ふっこう"],"comment":"(n) revival/renaissance/reconstruction"},
	{"question":"循環","answers":["じゅんかん"],"comment":"(n) circulation/rotation/cycle"},
	{"question":"微か","answers":["かすか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) faint/dim/weak/indistinct/hazy/poor/wretched"},
	{"question":"微塵","answers":["みじん"],"comment":"(n) particle/atom"},
	{"question":"微妙","answers":["びみょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) delicate/subtle"},
	{"question":"微笑","answers":["びしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) smile"},
	{"question":"微笑む","answers":["ほほえむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to smile"},
	{"question":"微量","answers":["びりょう"],"comment":"(n) minuscule amount/extremely small quantity"},
	{"question":"徴収","answers":["ちょうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) collection/levy"},
	{"question":"徹する","answers":["てっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to sink in/to penetrate/to devote oneself/to believe in/to go through/to do intently and exclusively"},
	{"question":"徹夜","answers":["てつや"],"comment":"(n) all night/all night vigil/sleepless night"},
	{"question":"徹底","answers":["てってい"],"comment":"(n) thoroughness/completeness"},
	{"question":"心","answers":["こころ"],"comment":"(n) core/heart/wick/marrow"},
	{"question":"心中","answers":["しんじゅう"],"comment":"(n) in one's heart/true motives/mind"},
	{"question":"心地","answers":["ここち"],"comment":"(n) feeling/sensation/mood"},
	{"question":"心強い","answers":["こころづよい"],"comment":"(adj) heartening/reassuring"},
	{"question":"心当たり","answers":["こころあたり"],"comment":"(n) having some knowledge of/happening to know"},
	{"question":"心得","answers":["こころえ"],"comment":"(n) knowledge/information"},
	{"question":"心得る","answers":["こころえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be informed/to have thorough knowledge"},
	{"question":"心情","answers":["しんじょう"],"comment":"(n) mentality"},
	{"question":"心掛け","answers":["こころがけ"],"comment":"(n) readiness/intention/aim"},
	{"question":"心掛ける","answers":["こころがける"],"comment":"(v1) to bear in mind/to aim to do"},
	{"question":"心理","answers":["しんり"],"comment":"(n) mentality"},
	{"question":"心細い","answers":["こころぼそい"],"comment":"(adj) helpless/forlorn/hopeless/unpromising/lonely/discouraging/disheartening"},
	{"question":"心臓","answers":["しんぞう"],"comment":"(n) heart"},
	{"question":"心身","answers":["しんしん"],"comment":"(n) mind and body"},
	{"question":"心配","answers":["しんぱい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) worry/concern/anxiety/care"},
	{"question":"必ず","answers":["かならず"],"comment":"(adv) necessarily/certainly/without fail/positively/invariably"},
	{"question":"必ずしも","answers":["かならずしも"],"comment":"(adv) (not) always/(not) necessarily/(not) all/(not) entirely"},
	{"question":"必修","answers":["ひっしゅう"],"comment":"(n) required (subject)"},
	{"question":"必死","answers":["ひっし"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) inevitable death/desperation/frantic/inevitable result"},
	{"question":"必然","answers":["ひつぜん"],"comment":"(n) inevitable/necessary"},
	{"question":"必要","answers":["ひつよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) necessary/essential/indispensable"},
	{"question":"必需品","answers":["ひつじゅひん"],"comment":"(n) necessities/necessary article/requisite/essential"},
	{"question":"志","answers":["こころざし"],"comment":"(n) will/intention/motive"},
	{"question":"志す","answers":["こころざす"],"comment":"(v5s) to plan/to intend/to aspire to/to set aims (sights on)"},
	{"question":"志向","answers":["しこう"],"comment":"(n) intention/aim"},
	{"question":"志望","answers":["しぼう"],"comment":"(n) wish/desire/ambition"},
	{"question":"忘れる","answers":["わすれる"],"comment":"(v1) to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of/to forget about/to forget (an article)"},
	{"question":"忘れ物","answers":["わすれもの"],"comment":"(n) lost article/something forgotten"},
	{"question":"忙しい","answers":["いそがしい"],"comment":"(adj) busy/irritated"},
	{"question":"応じる","answers":["おうじる"],"comment":"(v1) to respond/to satisfy/to accept/to comply with/to apply for"},
	{"question":"応ずる","answers":["おうずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to answer/to respond/to meet/to satisfy/to accept"},
	{"question":"応募","answers":["おうぼ"],"comment":"(n,vs) subscription/application"},
	{"question":"応対","answers":["おうたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) receiving/dealing with"},
	{"question":"応急","answers":["おうきゅう"],"comment":"(n) emergency"},
	{"question":"応接","answers":["おうせつ"],"comment":"(n) reception"},
	{"question":"応接間","answers":["おうせつま"],"comment":"(n) reception room"},
	{"question":"応援","answers":["おうえん"],"comment":"(n,vs) aid/assistance/help/reinforcement/rooting/barracking/support/cheering"},
	{"question":"応用","answers":["おうよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) application/put to practical use"},
	{"question":"忠告","answers":["ちゅうこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) advice/warning"},
	{"question":"快い","answers":["こころよい"],"comment":"(adj) pleasant/agreeable"},
	{"question":"快晴","answers":["かいせい"],"comment":"(n) good weather"},
	{"question":"快適","answers":["かいてき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pleasant/agreeable/comfortable"},
	{"question":"念","answers":["ねん"],"comment":"(n) sense/idea/thought/feeling/desire/concern/attention/care"},
	{"question":"念願","answers":["ねんがん"],"comment":"(n) one's heart's desire/earnest petition"},
	{"question":"怒り","answers":["いかり"],"comment":"(n) anger/hatred"},
	{"question":"怒る","answers":["おこる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to get angry/to get mad/(2) to be angry"},
	{"question":"怖い","answers":["こわい"],"comment":"(adj) scary/frightening/eerie/dreadful"},
	{"question":"思い付き","answers":["おもいつき"],"comment":"(n) plan/idea/suggestion"},
	{"question":"思い付く","answers":["おもいつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to think of/to hit upon/to come into one's mind/to be struck with an idea"},
	{"question":"思い出","answers":["おもいで"],"comment":"(n) memories/recollections/reminiscence"},
	{"question":"思い出す","answers":["おもいだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to recall/to remember"},
	{"question":"思い切り","answers":["おもいきり"],"comment":"(adv,n) with all one's strength (heart)/resignation/resolution"},
	{"question":"思い掛けない","answers":["おもいがけない"],"comment":"(adj) unexpected/casual"},
	{"question":"思い込む","answers":["おもいこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be under impression that/to be convinced that/to imagine that/to set one's heart on/to be bent on"},
	{"question":"思う","answers":["おもう"],"comment":"(v5u) to think/to feel"},
	{"question":"思わず","answers":["おもわず"],"comment":"(adv) unintentional/spontaneous"},
	{"question":"思想","answers":["しそう"],"comment":"(n) thought/idea"},
	{"question":"思考","answers":["しこう"],"comment":"(n) thought"},
	{"question":"怠ける","answers":["なまける"],"comment":"(v1) to be idle/to neglect"},
	{"question":"怠る","answers":["おこたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to neglect/to be off guard/to be feeling better"},
	{"question":"怠慢","answers":["たいまん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) negligence/procrastination/carelessness"},
	{"question":"急","answers":["きゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) urgent/sudden/(2) steep"},
	{"question":"急かす","answers":["せかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to hurry/to urge on"},
	{"question":"急ぐ","answers":["いそぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to hurry/to rush"},
	{"question":"急激","answers":["きゅうげき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) sudden/precipitous/radical"},
	{"question":"急行","answers":["きゅうこう"],"comment":"(n) express (e.g. train that bypasses many stations)"},
	{"question":"急速","answers":["きゅうそく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) rapid (e.g. progress)"},
	{"question":"性","answers":["せい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) sex/gender"},
	{"question":"性別","answers":["せいべつ"],"comment":"(n) distinction by sex/sex/gender"},
	{"question":"性格","answers":["せいかく"],"comment":"(n) character/personality"},
	{"question":"性能","answers":["せいのう"],"comment":"(n) ability/efficiency"},
	{"question":"性質","answers":["せいしつ"],"comment":"(n) nature/property/disposition"},
	{"question":"怪しい","answers":["あやしい"],"comment":"(adj) suspicious/dubious/doubtful"},
	{"question":"怪我","answers":["けが"],"comment":"(n,vs) injury (to animate object)/hurt"},
	{"question":"怪獣","answers":["かいじゅう"],"comment":"(n) monster"},
	{"question":"怯える","answers":["おびえる"],"comment":"(v1) to become frightened/to have a nightmare"},
	{"question":"恋","answers":["こい"],"comment":"(n,vs) love/tender passion"},
	{"question":"恋しい","answers":["こいしい"],"comment":"(adj) (1) dear/beloved/darling/(2) yearned for"},
	{"question":"恋する","answers":["こいする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to fall in love with/to love"},
	{"question":"恋人","answers":["こいびと"],"comment":"(n) lover/sweetheart"},
	{"question":"恋愛","answers":["れんあい"],"comment":"(n) love/love-making/passion/emotion/affections"},
	{"question":"恐れ","answers":["おそれ"],"comment":"(n) fear/horror"},
	{"question":"恐れる","answers":["おそれる"],"comment":"(v1) to fear/to be afraid of"},
	{"question":"恐れ入る","answers":["おそれいる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be filled with awe/to feel small/to be amazed/to be surprised/to be disconcerted/to be sorry/to be grateful/to be defeated/to confess guilt"},
	{"question":"恐ろしい","answers":["おそろしい"],"comment":"(adj) terrible/dreadful"},
	{"question":"恐怖","answers":["きょうふ"],"comment":"(n,vs) be afraid/dread/dismay/terror"},
	{"question":"恐縮","answers":["きょうしゅく"],"comment":"(exp,n) shame/very kind of you/sorry to trouble"},
	{"question":"恥","answers":["はじ"],"comment":"(n) shame/embarrassment"},
	{"question":"恥じらう","answers":["はじらう"],"comment":"(v5u) to feel shy/to be bashful/to blush"},
	{"question":"恥じる","answers":["はじる"],"comment":"(v1) to feel ashamed"},
	{"question":"恥ずかしい","answers":["はずかしい"],"comment":"(adj) shy/ashamed/embarrassed"},
	{"question":"恨み","answers":["うらみ"],"comment":"(n) resentment"},
	{"question":"恨む","answers":["うらむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to curse/to feel bitter"},
	{"question":"恩","answers":["おん"],"comment":"(n) favour/obligation/debt of gratitude"},
	{"question":"恩恵","answers":["おんけい"],"comment":"(n) grace/favor/blessing/benefit"},
	{"question":"息","answers":["いき"],"comment":"(n) breath/tone"},
	{"question":"息子","answers":["むすこ"],"comment":"(n) (hum) son"},
	{"question":"恵まれる","answers":["めぐまれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be blessed with/to be rich in"},
	{"question":"恵み","answers":["めぐみ"],"comment":"(n) blessing"},
	{"question":"恵む","answers":["めぐむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to bless/to show mercy to"},
	{"question":"悔しい","answers":["くやしい"],"comment":"(adj) regrettable/mortifying/vexing"},
	{"question":"悔やむ","answers":["くやむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to mourn"},
	{"question":"悟る","answers":["さとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to attain enlightenment/to perceive/to understand/to discern"},
	{"question":"悠々","answers":["ゆうゆう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) quiet/calm/leisurely"},
	{"question":"患者","answers":["かんじゃ"],"comment":"(n) a patient"},
	{"question":"悩ましい","answers":["なやましい"],"comment":"(adj) seductive/melancholy/languid"},
	{"question":"悩ます","answers":["なやます"],"comment":"(v5s) to afflict/to torment/to harass/to molest"},
	{"question":"悩み","answers":["なやみ"],"comment":"(n) trouble(s)/worry/distress/anguish/agony/problem"},
	{"question":"悩む","answers":["なやむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be worried/to be troubled"},
	{"question":"悪","answers":["あく"],"comment":"(n) bad thing/bad person"},
	{"question":"悪い","answers":["わるい"],"comment":"(adj) bad/inferior"},
	{"question":"悪化","answers":["あっか"],"comment":"(n,vs) (suffer) deterioration/growing worse/aggravation/degeneration/corruption"},
	{"question":"悪口","answers":["わるくち"],"comment":"(n) abuse/insult/slander/evil speaking"},
	{"question":"悪者","answers":["わるもの"],"comment":"(n) bad fellow/rascal/ruffian/scoundrel"},
	{"question":"悪魔","answers":["あくま"],"comment":"(n) devil/demon/fiend/Satan/evil spirit"},
	{"question":"悲しい","answers":["かなしい"],"comment":"(adj) sad/sorrowful"},
	{"question":"悲しむ","answers":["かなしむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be sad/to mourn for/to regret"},
	{"question":"悲劇","answers":["ひげき"],"comment":"(n) tragedy"},
	{"question":"悲惨","answers":["ひさん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) tragedy/disaster/(2) misery/wretched/pitiful"},
	{"question":"悲観","answers":["ひかん"],"comment":"(n) pessimism/disappointment"},
	{"question":"悲鳴","answers":["ひめい"],"comment":"(n) shriek/scream"},
	{"question":"情","answers":["じょう"],"comment":"(n) feelings/emotion/passion"},
	{"question":"情け","answers":["なさけ"],"comment":"(n) sympathy/compassion"},
	{"question":"情勢","answers":["じょうせい"],"comment":"(n) state of things/condition/situation"},
	{"question":"情報","answers":["じょうほう"],"comment":"(n) information/(military) intelligence"},
	{"question":"情深い","answers":["なさけぶかい"],"comment":"(adj) tender-hearted/compassionate"},
	{"question":"情無い","answers":["なさけない"],"comment":"(adj) miserable/pitiable/shameful/deplorable"},
	{"question":"情熱","answers":["じょうねつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) passion/enthusiasm/zeal"},
	{"question":"情緒","answers":["じょうしょ","じょうちょ"],"comment":"(n) emotion/feeling"},
	{"question":"惑星","answers":["わくせい"],"comment":"(n) planet"},
	{"question":"惚ける","answers":["ぼける"],"comment":"(v1) to grow senile/to fade"},
	{"question":"惜しい","answers":["おしい"],"comment":"(adj) regrettable/disappointing/precious"},
	{"question":"惜しむ","answers":["おしむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be frugal/to value/to regret"},
	{"question":"想像","answers":["そうぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) imagination/guess"},
	{"question":"愉快","answers":["ゆかい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pleasant/happy"},
	{"question":"意向","answers":["いこう"],"comment":"(n) intention/idea/inclination"},
	{"question":"意味","answers":["いみ"],"comment":"(n,vs) meaning/significance"},
	{"question":"意図","answers":["いと"],"comment":"(n) intention/aim/design"},
	{"question":"意地","answers":["いじ"],"comment":"(n) disposition/spirit/willpower/obstinacy/backbone/appetite"},
	{"question":"意地悪","answers":["いじわる"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) malicious/ill-tempered/unkind"},
	{"question":"意外","answers":["いがい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) unexpected/surprising"},
	{"question":"意志","answers":["いし"],"comment":"(n) will/volition"},
	{"question":"意思","answers":["いし"],"comment":"(n) intention/purpose"},
	{"question":"意欲","answers":["いよく"],"comment":"(n) will/desire/ambition"},
	{"question":"意気込む","answers":["いきごむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be enthusiastic about"},
	{"question":"意義","answers":["いぎ"],"comment":"(n) meaning/significance"},
	{"question":"意見","answers":["いけん"],"comment":"(n) opinion/view"},
	{"question":"意識","answers":["いしき"],"comment":"(n,vs) consciousness/senses"},
	{"question":"愚か","answers":["おろか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) foolish/stupid"},
	{"question":"愚痴","answers":["ぐち"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) idle complaint/grumble"},
	{"question":"愛","answers":["あい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,vs) love"},
	{"question":"愛する","answers":["あいする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to love"},
	{"question":"愛情","answers":["あいじょう"],"comment":"(n) love/affection"},
	{"question":"愛想","answers":["あいそう"],"comment":"(n) civility/courtesy/compliments/sociability/graces"},
	{"question":"感じ","answers":["かんじ"],"comment":"(n) feeling/sense/impression"},
	{"question":"感じる","answers":["かんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to feel/to sense/to experience"},
	{"question":"感ずる","answers":["かんずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to feel/to sense"},
	{"question":"感動","answers":["かんどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) being deeply moved emotionally/excitement/impression/deep emotion"},
	{"question":"感度","answers":["かんど"],"comment":"(n) sensitivity/severity (quake)"},
	{"question":"感心","answers":["かんしん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) admiration/Well done!"},
	{"question":"感情","answers":["かんじょう"],"comment":"(n) emotion(s)/feeling(s)/sentiment"},
	{"question":"感想","answers":["かんそう"],"comment":"(n) impressions/thoughts"},
	{"question":"感染","answers":["かんせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) infection/contagion"},
	{"question":"感激","answers":["かんげき"],"comment":"(n) deep emotion/impression/inspiration"},
	{"question":"感無量","answers":["かんむりょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) deep feeling/inexpressible feeling/filled with emotion"},
	{"question":"感覚","answers":["かんかく"],"comment":"(n) sense/sensation"},
	{"question":"感触","answers":["かんしょく"],"comment":"(n) sense of touch/feeling/sensation"},
	{"question":"感謝","answers":["かんしゃ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) thanks/gratitude"},
	{"question":"態勢","answers":["たいせい"],"comment":"(n) attitude/conditions/preparations"},
	{"question":"態度","answers":["たいど"],"comment":"(n) attitude/manner"},
	{"question":"慎重","answers":["しんちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) discretion/prudence"},
	{"question":"慕う","answers":["したう"],"comment":"(v5u) to yearn for/to miss/to adore/to love dearly"},
	{"question":"慣らす","answers":["ならす"],"comment":"(v5s) to accustom"},
	{"question":"慣れ","answers":["なれ"],"comment":"(n,vs) practice/experience"},
	{"question":"慣れる","answers":["なれる"],"comment":"(v1) to grow accustomed to"},
	{"question":"慣例","answers":["かんれい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) custom/precedent/of convention"},
	{"question":"慣習","answers":["かんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) usual (historical) custom"},
	{"question":"慣行","answers":["かんこう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) customary practice/habit/traditional event"},
	{"question":"慰める","answers":["なぐさめる"],"comment":"(v1) to comfort/to console"},
	{"question":"慶び","answers":["よろこび"],"comment":"(oK) (n) (a) joy/(a) delight/rapture/pleasure/gratification/rejoicing/congratulations/felicitations"},
	{"question":"憂鬱","answers":["ゆううつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) depression/melancholy/dejection/gloom"},
	{"question":"憎い","answers":["にくい"],"comment":"(adj) hateful/abominable/poor-looking/detestable"},
	{"question":"憎しみ","answers":["にくしみ"],"comment":"(n) hatred"},
	{"question":"憎む","answers":["にくむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to hate/to detest"},
	{"question":"憎らしい","answers":["にくらしい"],"comment":"(adj) odious/hateful"},
	{"question":"憤慨","answers":["ふんがい"],"comment":"(n) indignation/resentment"},
	{"question":"憧れ","answers":["あこがれ"],"comment":"(n) yearning/longing/aspiration"},
	{"question":"憧れる","answers":["あこがれる"],"comment":"(v1) to long for/to yearn after/to admire/to be attracted by"},
	{"question":"憲法","answers":["けんぽう"],"comment":"(n) constitution"},
	{"question":"懐かしい","answers":["なつかしい"],"comment":"(adj) dear/desired/missed"},
	{"question":"懐く","answers":["なつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to become emotionally attached"},
	{"question":"懲りる","answers":["こりる"],"comment":"(v1) to learn by experience/to be disgusted with"},
	{"question":"懸命","answers":["けんめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) eagerness/earnestness/risking one's life"},
	{"question":"懸賞","answers":["けんしょう"],"comment":"(n) offering prizes/winning/reward"},
	{"question":"成り立つ","answers":["なりたつ"],"comment":"(v5t) (1) to consist of/(2) to be practical (logical, feasible, viable)/to be concluded/to hold true"},
	{"question":"成る","answers":["なる"],"comment":"(v5r) (uk) to become"},
	{"question":"成人","answers":["せいじん"],"comment":"(n) adult"},
	{"question":"成分","answers":["せいぶん"],"comment":"(n) ingredient/component/composition"},
	{"question":"成功","answers":["せいこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) success/hit"},
	{"question":"成年","answers":["せいねん"],"comment":"(n) majority/adult age"},
	{"question":"成果","answers":["せいか"],"comment":"(n) results/fruits"},
	{"question":"成熟","answers":["せいじゅく"],"comment":"(n) maturity/ripeness"},
	{"question":"成程","answers":["なるほど"],"comment":"(adv,exp) (uk) I see/That's right!/indeed"},
	{"question":"成立","answers":["せいりつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) coming into existence/arrangements/establishment/completion"},
	{"question":"成績","answers":["せいせき"],"comment":"(n) results/record"},
	{"question":"成育","answers":["せいいく"],"comment":"(n) growth/raising"},
	{"question":"成長","answers":["せいちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) growth/grow to adulthood"},
	{"question":"我","answers":["われ"],"comment":"(n) me/oneself/self/ego"},
	{"question":"我々","answers":["われわれ"],"comment":"(n) we"},
	{"question":"我慢","answers":["がまん"],"comment":"(n,vs) patience/endurance/perseverance/tolerance/self-control/self-denial"},
	{"question":"或","answers":["ある"],"comment":"(adj-pn) a certain.../some..."},
	{"question":"戦い","answers":["たたかい"],"comment":"(n) battle/fight/struggle/conflict"},
	{"question":"戦う","answers":["たたかう"],"comment":"(v5u) to fight/to battle/to combat/to struggle against/to wage war/to engage in contest"},
	{"question":"戦争","answers":["せんそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) war"},
	{"question":"戦力","answers":["せんりょく"],"comment":"(n) war potential"},
	{"question":"戦災","answers":["せんさい"],"comment":"(n) war damage"},
	{"question":"戦術","answers":["せんじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) tactics"},
	{"question":"戦闘","answers":["せんとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) battle/fight/combat"},
	{"question":"戯曲","answers":["ぎきょく"],"comment":"(n) play/drama"},
	{"question":"戸","answers":["と"],"comment":"(n) door (Japanese style)"},
	{"question":"戸棚","answers":["とだな"],"comment":"(n) cupboard/locker/closet/wardrobe"},
	{"question":"戸籍","answers":["こせき"],"comment":"(n) census/family register"},
	{"question":"戸締り","answers":["とじまり"],"comment":"(n) closing up/fastening the doors"},
	{"question":"戻す","answers":["もどす"],"comment":"(v5s) to restore/to put back/to return"},
	{"question":"戻る","answers":["もどる"],"comment":"(v5r) to turn back/to return"},
	{"question":"所","answers":["ところ"],"comment":"(n) place"},
	{"question":"所々","answers":["ところどころ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) here and there/some parts (of something)"},
	{"question":"所在","answers":["しょざい"],"comment":"(n) whereabouts"},
	{"question":"所定","answers":["しょてい"],"comment":"(n) fixed/prescribed"},
	{"question":"所属","answers":["しょぞく"],"comment":"(n) attached to/belong to"},
	{"question":"所得","answers":["しょとく"],"comment":"(n) income/earnings"},
	{"question":"所持","answers":["しょじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) possession/owning"},
	{"question":"所有","answers":["しょゆう"],"comment":"(n,vs) one's possessions/ownership"},
	{"question":"所為","answers":["せい"],"comment":"(n) cause/reason/fault"},
	{"question":"扇ぐ","answers":["あおぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to fan/to flap"},
	{"question":"扇子","answers":["せんす"],"comment":"(n) folding fan"},
	{"question":"扇風機","answers":["せんぷうき"],"comment":"(n) electric fan"},
	{"question":"扉","answers":["とびら"],"comment":"(n) door/opening"},
	{"question":"手","answers":["て"],"comment":"(n) hand"},
	{"question":"手伝い","answers":["てつだい"],"comment":"(n) help/helper/assistant"},
	{"question":"手伝う","answers":["てつだう"],"comment":"(v5u) to help/to assist/to take part in"},
	{"question":"手元","answers":["てもと"],"comment":"(n) (1) (money) on hand or at home/one's purse/(2) usual skill"},
	{"question":"手入れ","answers":["ていれ"],"comment":"(n) repairs/maintenance"},
	{"question":"手分け","answers":["てわけ"],"comment":"(n,vs) division of labour"},
	{"question":"手前","answers":["てまえ"],"comment":"(n) before/this side/we/you"},
	{"question":"手品","answers":["てじな"],"comment":"(n) sleight of hand/conjuring trick/magic/juggling"},
	{"question":"手回し","answers":["てまわし"],"comment":"(n) preparations/arrangements"},
	{"question":"手帳","answers":["てちょう"],"comment":"(n) notebook"},
	{"question":"手引","answers":["てびき"],"comment":"(n) guidance/guide/introduction"},
	{"question":"手当","answers":["てあて"],"comment":"(n) allowance/compensation/treatment/medical care"},
	{"question":"手拭い","answers":["てぬぐい"],"comment":"(n) (hand) towel"},
	{"question":"手掛かり","answers":["てがかり"],"comment":"(n) contact/trail/scent/on hand/hand hold/clue/key"},
	{"question":"手掛ける","answers":["てがける"],"comment":"(v1) to handle/to manage/to work with/to rear/to look after/to have experience with"},
	{"question":"手数","answers":["てかず","てすう"],"comment":"(n) trouble/labor/handling"},
	{"question":"手本","answers":["てほん"],"comment":"(n) model/pattern"},
	{"question":"手段","answers":["しゅだん"],"comment":"(n) means/way/measure"},
	{"question":"手法","answers":["しゅほう"],"comment":"(n) technique"},
	{"question":"手洗い","answers":["てあらい"],"comment":"(n) restroom/lavatory/hand-washing"},
	{"question":"手筈","answers":["てはず"],"comment":"(n) arrangement/plan/programme"},
	{"question":"手紙","answers":["てがみ"],"comment":"(n) letter"},
	{"question":"手続き","answers":["てつづき"],"comment":"(n,vs) procedure/(legal) process/formalities"},
	{"question":"手芸","answers":["しゅげい"],"comment":"(n) handicrafts"},
	{"question":"手術","answers":["しゅじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) surgical operation"},
	{"question":"手袋","answers":["てぶくろ"],"comment":"(n) glove"},
	{"question":"手軽","answers":["てがる"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) easy/simple/informal/offhand/cheap"},
	{"question":"手近","answers":["てぢか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) near/handy/familiar"},
	{"question":"手遅れ","answers":["ておくれ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) being (too) late/(2) belated treatment"},
	{"question":"手配","answers":["てはい"],"comment":"(n,vs) arrangement/search (by police)"},
	{"question":"手錠","answers":["てじょう"],"comment":"(n) handcuffs/manacles"},
	{"question":"手間","answers":["てま"],"comment":"(n) time/labour"},
	{"question":"手際","answers":["てぎわ"],"comment":"(n) performance/skill/tact"},
	{"question":"手頃","answers":["てごろ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) moderate/handy"},
	{"question":"手順","answers":["てじゅん"],"comment":"(n) process/procedure/protocol"},
	{"question":"手首","answers":["てくび"],"comment":"(n) wrist"},
	{"question":"才能","answers":["さいのう"],"comment":"(n) talent/ability"},
	{"question":"打ち切る","answers":["うちきる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stop/to abort/to discontinue/to close"},
	{"question":"打ち明ける","answers":["うちあける"],"comment":"(v1) to be frank/to speak one's mind/to open one's heart"},
	{"question":"打ち消し","answers":["うちけし"],"comment":"(n) (gram) negation/denial/negative"},
	{"question":"打ち消す","answers":["うちけす"],"comment":"(v5s) to deny/to negate/to contradict"},
	{"question":"打ち込む","answers":["うちこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to drive in (e.g. nail, stake)/to devote oneself to/to shoot into/to smash/to throw into/to cast into"},
	{"question":"打つ","answers":["うつ","ぶつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to hit/to strike"},
	{"question":"打合せ","answers":["うちあわせ"],"comment":"(n) business meeting/previous arrangement/appointment"},
	{"question":"打撃","answers":["だげき"],"comment":"(n) (1) blow/shock/strike/damage/(2) batting (baseball)"},
	{"question":"打開","answers":["だかい"],"comment":"(n) break in the deadlock"},
	{"question":"払い戻す","answers":["はらいもどす"],"comment":"(v5s) to repay/to pay back"},
	{"question":"払い込む","answers":["はらいこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to deposit/to pay in"},
	{"question":"払う","answers":["はらう"],"comment":"(v5u) (1) to pay/(2) to brush/to wipe"},
	{"question":"扱い","answers":["あつかい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,vs) treatment/service"},
	{"question":"扱う","answers":["あつかう"],"comment":"(v5u) to handle/to deal with/to treat"},
	{"question":"扶養","answers":["ふよう"],"comment":"(n) support/maintenance"},
	{"question":"批判","answers":["ひはん"],"comment":"(n) criticism/judgement/comment"},
	{"question":"批評","answers":["ひひょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) criticism/review/commentary"},
	{"question":"承る","answers":["うけたまわる"],"comment":"(v5r) (hum) to hear/to be told/to know"},
	{"question":"承知","answers":["しょうち"],"comment":"(n,vs) consent/acceptance/assent/admitting/acknowledgment/compliance/agreement/awareness"},
	{"question":"承認","answers":["しょうにん"],"comment":"(n) recognition/acknowledgement/approval/consent/agreement"},
	{"question":"承諾","answers":["しょうだく"],"comment":"(n,vs) consent/acquiescence/agreement"},
	{"question":"技","answers":["わざ"],"comment":"(n) art/technique"},
	{"question":"技師","answers":["ぎし"],"comment":"(n) engineer/technician"},
	{"question":"技能","answers":["ぎのう"],"comment":"(n) technical skill/ability/capacity"},
	{"question":"技術","answers":["ぎじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) art/technique/technology/skill"},
	{"question":"把握","answers":["はあく"],"comment":"(n,vs) grasp/catch/understanding"},
	{"question":"抑制","answers":["よくせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) control/restraint/suppression"},
	{"question":"抑圧","answers":["よくあつ"],"comment":"(n) check/restraint/oppression/suppression"},
	{"question":"投げる","answers":["なげる"],"comment":"(v1) to throw/to cast away"},
	{"question":"投げ出す","answers":["なげだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to throw down/to abandon/to sacrifice/to throw out"},
	{"question":"投入","answers":["とうにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) throw/investment/making (an electrical circuit)"},
	{"question":"投書","answers":["とうしょ"],"comment":"(n) letter to the editor/letter from a reader/contribution"},
	{"question":"投票","answers":["とうひょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) voting/poll"},
	{"question":"投資","answers":["とうし"],"comment":"(n) investment"},
	{"question":"抗争","answers":["こうそう"],"comment":"(n) dispute/resistance"},
	{"question":"抗議","answers":["こうぎ"],"comment":"(n,vs) protest/objection"},
	{"question":"折","answers":["おり"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) chance/suitable time"},
	{"question":"折り返す","answers":["おりかえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to turn up/to fold back"},
	{"question":"折る","answers":["おる"],"comment":"(v5r) to break/to fold/to pick flower"},
	{"question":"折れる","answers":["おれる"],"comment":"(v1,vi,vt) to break/to be folded/to give in/to turn (a corner)"},
	{"question":"折衷","answers":["せっちゅう"],"comment":"(n) compromise/cross/blending/eclecticism"},
	{"question":"折角","answers":["せっかく"],"comment":"(adv,n) with trouble/at great pains/long-awaited"},
	{"question":"抜かす","answers":["ぬかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to omit/to leave out"},
	{"question":"抜く","answers":["ぬく"],"comment":"(v5k) to extract/to omit/to surpass/to draw out/to unplug"},
	{"question":"抜ける","answers":["ぬける"],"comment":"(v1) to come out/to fall out/to be omitted/to be missing/to escape"},
	{"question":"抜け出す","answers":["ぬけだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to slip out/to sneak away/to excel"},
	{"question":"抱える","answers":["かかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to hold or carry under or in the arms"},
	{"question":"抱く","answers":["いだく","だく"],"comment":"(v5k) (sl) to embrace/to hug/to harbour/to entertain/`to sleep with'"},
	{"question":"抱っこ","answers":["だっこ"],"comment":"(n,vs) (child's) hug"},
	{"question":"抵抗","answers":["ていこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) electrical resistance/resistance/opposition"},
	{"question":"押える","answers":["おさえる"],"comment":"(v1) to stop/to restrain/to seize/to repress/to suppress/to press down"},
	{"question":"押し入れ","answers":["おしいれ"],"comment":"(n) closet"},
	{"question":"押し切る","answers":["おしきる"],"comment":"(v5r) to have one's own way"},
	{"question":"押し寄せる","answers":["おしよせる"],"comment":"(v1) to push aside/to advance on"},
	{"question":"押し込む","answers":["おしこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to push into/to crowd into"},
	{"question":"押す","answers":["おす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to push/to press/to stamp (i.e. a passport)"},
	{"question":"抽象","answers":["ちゅうしょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) abstract"},
	{"question":"抽選","answers":["ちゅうせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) lottery/raffle/drawing (of lots)"},
	{"question":"担う","answers":["になう"],"comment":"(v5u) to carry on shoulder/to bear (burden)/to shoulder (gun)"},
	{"question":"担ぐ","answers":["かつぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to shoulder/to carry on shoulder"},
	{"question":"担当","answers":["たんとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) (in) charge"},
	{"question":"担架","answers":["たんか"],"comment":"(n) stretcher/litter"},
	{"question":"拍手","answers":["はくしゅ"],"comment":"(n) clapping hands/applause"},
	{"question":"拒否","answers":["きょひ"],"comment":"(n) denial/veto/rejection/refusal"},
	{"question":"拒絶","answers":["きょぜつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) refusal/rejection"},
	{"question":"拘束","answers":["こうそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) restriction/restraint"},
	{"question":"招き","answers":["まねき"],"comment":"(n) invitation"},
	{"question":"招く","answers":["まねく"],"comment":"(v5k) to invite"},
	{"question":"招待","answers":["しょうたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) invitation"},
	{"question":"拝む","answers":["おがむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to worship/to beg/to make a supplication"},
	{"question":"拝借","answers":["はいしゃく"],"comment":"(n,vs) (hum) (pol) borrowing"},
	{"question":"拝啓","answers":["はいけい"],"comment":"(int,n) Dear (so and so)"},
	{"question":"拝見","answers":["はいけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (hum) (pol) seeing/look at"},
	{"question":"拡充","answers":["かくじゅう"],"comment":"(n) expansion"},
	{"question":"拡大","answers":["かくだい"],"comment":"(n,vs) magnification/enlargement"},
	{"question":"拡張","answers":["かくちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) expansion/extension/enlargement/escape (ESC)"},
	{"question":"拡散","answers":["かくさん"],"comment":"(n) scattering/diffusion"},
	{"question":"括弧","answers":["かっこ"],"comment":"(n) parenthesis/brackets"},
	{"question":"拭く","answers":["ふく"],"comment":"(v5k) to wipe/to dry"},
	{"question":"拾う","answers":["ひろう"],"comment":"(v5u) to pick up/to find/to gather"},
	{"question":"持ち上げる","answers":["もちあげる"],"comment":"(v1) to raise/to lift up/to flatter"},
	{"question":"持ち切り","answers":["もちきり"],"comment":"(n) hot topic/talk of the town"},
	{"question":"持つ","answers":["もつ"],"comment":"(v5t) (1) to hold/to carry/(2) to possess"},
	{"question":"持参","answers":["じさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) bringing/taking/carrying"},
	{"question":"持続","answers":["じぞく"],"comment":"(n) continuation"},
	{"question":"指","answers":["ゆび"],"comment":"(n) finger"},
	{"question":"指す","answers":["さす"],"comment":"(v5s) to point/to put up umbrella/to play"},
	{"question":"指令","answers":["しれい"],"comment":"(n) orders/instructions/directive"},
	{"question":"指図","answers":["さしず"],"comment":"(n) instruction/mandate"},
	{"question":"指定","answers":["してい"],"comment":"(n,vs) designation/specification/assignment/pointing at"},
	{"question":"指導","answers":["しどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) leadership/guidance/coaching"},
	{"question":"指差す","answers":["ゆびさす"],"comment":"(v5s) to point at"},
	{"question":"指揮","answers":["しき"],"comment":"(n) command/direction"},
	{"question":"指摘","answers":["してき"],"comment":"(n,vs) pointing out/identification"},
	{"question":"指輪","answers":["ゆびわ"],"comment":"(n) (finger) ring"},
	{"question":"挑む","answers":["いどむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to challenge/to contend for/to make love to"},
	{"question":"挑戦","answers":["ちょうせん"],"comment":"(n) challenge/defiance"},
	{"question":"挟まる","answers":["はさまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to get between/to be caught in"},
	{"question":"挟む","answers":["はさむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to interpose/to hold between/to insert"},
	{"question":"挨拶","answers":["あいさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) greeting/salutation"},
	{"question":"振り","answers":["ふり"],"comment":"(suf) style/manner"},
	{"question":"振り仮名","answers":["ふりがな"],"comment":"furigana (hiragana over kanji)/pronunciation key"},
	{"question":"振り出し","answers":["ふりだし"],"comment":"(n) outset/starting point/drawing or issuing (draft)"},
	{"question":"振り向く","answers":["ふりむく"],"comment":"(v5k) to turn one's face/to turn around"},
	{"question":"振り返る","answers":["ふりかえる"],"comment":"(v5r) to turn head/to look over one's shoulder/to turn around/to look back"},
	{"question":"振る","answers":["ふる"],"comment":"(v5r,vt) (1) to wave/to shake/to swing/(2) to sprinkle/(3) to cast (actor)/to allocate (work)"},
	{"question":"振動","answers":["しんどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) oscillation/vibration"},
	{"question":"振興","answers":["しんこう"],"comment":"(n) promotion/encouragement"},
	{"question":"振舞う","answers":["ふるまう"],"comment":"(v5u) to behave/to conduct oneself/to entertain (vt)"},
	{"question":"挿す","answers":["さす"],"comment":"(v5s) to insert/to put in/to graft/to wear in belt"},
	{"question":"捕える","answers":["とらえる"],"comment":"(v1) to seize/to grasp/to capture/to arrest"},
	{"question":"捕まえる","answers":["つかまえる"],"comment":"(v1) to catch/to arrest/to seize"},
	{"question":"捕まる","answers":["つかまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be caught/to be arrested"},
	{"question":"捕る","answers":["とる"],"comment":"(v5r) to take/to catch (fish)/to capture"},
	{"question":"捕獲","answers":["ほかく"],"comment":"(n,vs) capture/seizure"},
	{"question":"捕虜","answers":["ほりょ"],"comment":"(n) prisoner (of war)"},
	{"question":"捕鯨","answers":["ほげい"],"comment":"(n) whaling/whale fishing"},
	{"question":"捗る","answers":["はかどる"],"comment":"(v5r) to make progress/to move right ahead (with the work)/to advance"},
	{"question":"捜す","answers":["さがす"],"comment":"(v5s) to search/to seek/to look for"},
	{"question":"捜査","answers":["そうさ"],"comment":"(n,vs) search (esp. in criminal investigations)/investigation"},
	{"question":"捜索","answers":["そうさく"],"comment":"(n) search (esp. for someone or something missing)/investigation"},
	{"question":"捧げる","answers":["ささげる"],"comment":"(v1) to lift up/to give/to offer/to consecrate/to devote/to sacrifice/to dedicate"},
	{"question":"捨てる","answers":["すてる"],"comment":"(v1) to throw away/to cast aside/to abandon/to resign"},
	{"question":"捩る","answers":["ねじる"],"comment":"(v5r) to twist"},
	{"question":"据える","answers":["すえる"],"comment":"(v1) to set (table)/to lay (foundation)/to place (gun)/to apply (moxa)"},
	{"question":"据え付ける","answers":["すえつける"],"comment":"(v1) to install/to equip/to mount"},
	{"question":"捲る","answers":["めくる"],"comment":"(v5r) to turn over/to turn pages of a book/to tear off/to strip off"},
	{"question":"捻る","answers":["ひねる"],"comment":"(v5r) to turn (a switch) on or off/to twist/to puzzle over"},
	{"question":"掃く","answers":["はく"],"comment":"(v5k) to sweep/to brush/to gather up"},
	{"question":"掃除","answers":["そうじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) cleaning/sweeping"},
	{"question":"授ける","answers":["さずける"],"comment":"(v1) to grant/to award/to teach"},
	{"question":"授業","answers":["じゅぎょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) lesson/class work"},
	{"question":"掌","answers":["てのひら"],"comment":"(n) the palm"},
	{"question":"掏摸","answers":["すり"],"comment":"(n) pickpocket"},
	{"question":"排水","answers":["はいすい"],"comment":"(n) drainage"},
	{"question":"排除","answers":["はいじょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) exclusion/removal/rejection"},
	{"question":"掘る","answers":["ほる"],"comment":"(v5r) to dig/to excavate"},
	{"question":"掛かる","answers":["かかる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to take (e.g. time, money, etc)/to hang"},
	{"question":"掛ける","answers":["かける"],"comment":"(aux-v,v1) (1) to wear/to put on/to hang/to begin to/to cover/to multiply/to turn on (a switch)/to play (a record)/to pour (water)/(2) to sit down/(3) to make a phone call"},
	{"question":"掛け算","answers":["かけざん"],"comment":"(n) multiplication"},
	{"question":"採る","answers":["とる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to adopt (measure, proposal)/(2) to pick (fruit)/(3) to assume (attitude)"},
	{"question":"採択","answers":["さいたく"],"comment":"(n,vs) adoption/selection/choice"},
	{"question":"採掘","answers":["さいくつ"],"comment":"(n) mining"},
	{"question":"採決","answers":["さいけつ"],"comment":"(n) vote/roll call"},
	{"question":"採点","answers":["さいてん"],"comment":"(n,vs) marking/grading/looking over"},
	{"question":"採用","answers":["さいよう"],"comment":"(n) use/adopt"},
	{"question":"採算","answers":["さいさん"],"comment":"(n) profit"},
	{"question":"採集","answers":["さいしゅう"],"comment":"(n) collecting/gathering"},
	{"question":"探す","answers":["さがす"],"comment":"(v5s) to search/to seek/to look for"},
	{"question":"探る","answers":["さぐる"],"comment":"(v5r) to search/to look for/to sound out"},
	{"question":"探検","answers":["たんけん"],"comment":"(n) exploration/expedition"},
	{"question":"接ぐ","answers":["つぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) (1) to join/(2) to piece together/(3) to set (bones)/(4) to graft (trees)"},
	{"question":"接する","answers":["せっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to come in contact with/to connect/to attend/to receive"},
	{"question":"接続","answers":["せつぞく"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) connection/union/join/link/(2) changing trains"},
	{"question":"接続詞","answers":["せつぞくし"],"comment":"(n) conjunction"},
	{"question":"接触","answers":["せっしょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) touch/contact"},
	{"question":"接近","answers":["せっきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) getting closer/drawing nearer/approaching"},
	{"question":"控える","answers":["ひかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to draw in/to hold back/to make notes/to be temperate in"},
	{"question":"控室","answers":["ひかえしつ"],"comment":"(n) waiting room"},
	{"question":"控除","answers":["こうじょ"],"comment":"(n) subsidy/deduction"},
	{"question":"推定","answers":["すいてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) presumption/assumption/estimation"},
	{"question":"推測","answers":["すいそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) guess/conjecture"},
	{"question":"推理","answers":["すいり"],"comment":"(n) reasoning/inference/mystery or detective genre (movie, novel, etc.)"},
	{"question":"推薦","answers":["すいせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) recommendation"},
	{"question":"推進","answers":["すいしん"],"comment":"(n) propulsion/driving force"},
	{"question":"措置","answers":["そち"],"comment":"(n) measure/step"},
	{"question":"掲げる","answers":["かかげる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to publish/to print/to carry (an article)/(2) to put up/to hang out/to hoist/to fly (a sail)/to float (a flag)"},
	{"question":"掲示","answers":["けいじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) notice/bulletin"},
	{"question":"掲載","answers":["けいさい"],"comment":"(n,vs) appearance (e.g. article in paper)"},
	{"question":"掴む","answers":["つかむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to seize/to catch/to grasp/to grip/to grab/to hold/to catch hold of/to lay one's hands on"},
	{"question":"掻き回す","answers":["かきまわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to stir up/to churn/to ransack/to disturb"},
	{"question":"掻く","answers":["かく"],"comment":"(v5k) (uk) to scratch/to perspire"},
	{"question":"揃い","answers":["そろい"],"comment":"(n) set/suit/uniform"},
	{"question":"揃う","answers":["そろう"],"comment":"(v5u) to become complete/to be equal/to be all present/to gather"},
	{"question":"揃える","answers":["そろえる"],"comment":"(v1) to put things in order/to arrange/to make uniform/to get something ready"},
	{"question":"揉む","answers":["もむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to rub/to crumple (up)/to wrinkle/to massage/to be troubled about/to worry over/to train/to coach"},
	{"question":"描く","answers":["えがく"],"comment":"(v5k) to draw/to paint/to sketch/to depict/to describe"},
	{"question":"描写","answers":["びょうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) depiction/description/portrayal"},
	{"question":"提供","answers":["ていきょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) offer/tender/program sponsoring/furnishing"},
	{"question":"提出","answers":["ていしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) presentation/submission/filing"},
	{"question":"提携","answers":["ていけい"],"comment":"(n) cooperation/tie-up/joint business/link-up"},
	{"question":"提案","answers":["ていあん"],"comment":"(n,vs) proposal/proposition/suggestion"},
	{"question":"提示","answers":["ていじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) presentation/exhibit/suggest/citation"},
	{"question":"換える","answers":["かえる"],"comment":"(v1) to exchange/to interchange/to substitute/to replace"},
	{"question":"換気","answers":["かんき"],"comment":"(n) ventilation"},
	{"question":"換算","answers":["かんさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) conversion/change/exchange"},
	{"question":"握る","answers":["にぎる"],"comment":"(v5r) to grasp/to seize/to mould sushi"},
	{"question":"握手","answers":["あくしゅ"],"comment":"(n,vs) handshake"},
	{"question":"援助","answers":["えんじょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) assistance/aid/support"},
	{"question":"揺さぶる","answers":["ゆさぶる"],"comment":"(v5r) to shake/to jolt/to rock/to swing"},
	{"question":"揺らぐ","answers":["ゆらぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to swing/to sway/to shake/to tremble"},
	{"question":"揺れる","answers":["ゆれる"],"comment":"(v1) to shake/to sway"},
	{"question":"損","answers":["そん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,n-suf,vs) loss/disadvantage"},
	{"question":"損う","answers":["そこなう"],"comment":"(io) (suf,v5u) to harm/to hurt/to injure/to damage/to fail in doing"},
	{"question":"損失","answers":["そんしつ"],"comment":"(n) loss"},
	{"question":"損害","answers":["そんがい"],"comment":"(n) damage/injury/loss"},
	{"question":"損得","answers":["そんとく"],"comment":"(n) loss and gain/advantage and disadvantage"},
	{"question":"携わる","answers":["たずさわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to participate/to take part"},
	{"question":"携帯","answers":["けいたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) carrying something/(2) mobile telephone (abbr)"},
	{"question":"摘む","answers":["つむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to pluck/to pick/to trim"},
	{"question":"摩する","answers":["さする"],"comment":"(vs-s) (1) to rub/to scrub/(2) to draw near/to press"},
	{"question":"摩擦","answers":["まさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) friction/rubbing/rubdown/chafe"},
	{"question":"撃つ","answers":["うつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to attack/to defeat/to destroy"},
	{"question":"撒く","answers":["まく"],"comment":"(v5k) to scatter/to sprinkle/to sow"},
	{"question":"撫でる","answers":["なでる"],"comment":"(v1) to brush gently/to stroke"},
	{"question":"撮る","answers":["とる"],"comment":"(v5r) to take (a photo)/to make (a film)"},
	{"question":"撮影","answers":["さつえい"],"comment":"(n,vs) photographing"},
	{"question":"操る","answers":["あやつる"],"comment":"(v5r) to manipulate/to operate/to pull strings"},
	{"question":"操作","answers":["そうさ"],"comment":"(n,vs) operation/management/processing"},
	{"question":"操縦","answers":["そうじゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) management/handling/control/manipulation"},
	{"question":"擦る","answers":["かする","こする","する"],"comment":"(v5r) to rub/to chafe/to file/to frost (glass)/to strike (match)"},
	{"question":"擦れる","answers":["すれる"],"comment":"(v1) to rub/to chafe/to wear/to become sophisticated"},
	{"question":"支える","answers":["ささえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be blocked/to choke/to be obstructed/to feel a pressure on one's chest"},
	{"question":"支出","answers":["ししゅつ"],"comment":"(n) expenditure/expenses"},
	{"question":"支店","answers":["してん"],"comment":"(n) branch store (office)"},
	{"question":"支度","answers":["したく"],"comment":"(n,vs) preparation"},
	{"question":"支払","answers":["しはらい"],"comment":"(n) payment"},
	{"question":"支払う","answers":["しはらう"],"comment":"(v5u) to pay"},
	{"question":"支持","answers":["しじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) support/maintenance"},
	{"question":"支給","answers":["しきゅう"],"comment":"(n) payment/allowance"},
	{"question":"支配","answers":["しはい"],"comment":"(n,vs) rule/control/direction"},
	{"question":"改まる","answers":["あらたまる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to be renewed/(2) to stand on ceremony/to be formal/(3) to take a turn for the worse"},
	{"question":"改めて","answers":["あらためて"],"comment":"(adv) another time/again/over again/anew/formally"},
	{"question":"改める","answers":["あらためる"],"comment":"(v1) to change/to alter/to reform/to revise"},
	{"question":"改修","answers":["かいしゅう"],"comment":"(n) repair/improvement"},
	{"question":"改善","answers":["かいぜん"],"comment":"(n,vs) betterment/improvement/incremental and continuous improvement"},
	{"question":"改定","answers":["かいてい"],"comment":"(n) reform"},
	{"question":"改悪","answers":["かいあく"],"comment":"(n) deterioration/changing for the worse"},
	{"question":"改札","answers":["かいさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) examination of tickets"},
	{"question":"改正","answers":["かいせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) revision/amendment/alteration"},
	{"question":"改良","answers":["かいりょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) improvement/reform"},
	{"question":"改訂","answers":["かいてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) revision"},
	{"question":"改造","answers":["かいぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) remodeling/(2) modding (comp)"},
	{"question":"改革","answers":["かいかく"],"comment":"(n) reform/reformation/innovation"},
	{"question":"攻め","answers":["せめ"],"comment":"(n) attack/offence"},
	{"question":"攻める","answers":["せめる"],"comment":"(v1) to attack/to assault"},
	{"question":"攻撃","answers":["こうげき"],"comment":"(n,vs) attack/strike/offensive/criticism/censure"},
	{"question":"放す","answers":["はなす"],"comment":"(v5s) to separate/to set free"},
	{"question":"放り出す","answers":["ほうりだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to throw out/to fire/to expel/to give up/to abandon/to neglect"},
	{"question":"放り込む","answers":["ほうりこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to throw into"},
	{"question":"放る","answers":["ほうる"],"comment":"(v5r) to let go"},
	{"question":"放れる","answers":["はなれる"],"comment":"(v1) to leave/to get free/to cut oneself off"},
	{"question":"放出","answers":["ほうしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) release/emit"},
	{"question":"放射","answers":["ほうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) radiation/emission"},
	{"question":"放射能","answers":["ほうしゃのう"],"comment":"(n) radioactivity"},
	{"question":"放置","answers":["ほうち"],"comment":"(n,vs) leave as is/leave to chance/leave alone/neglect"},
	{"question":"放送","answers":["ほうそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) broadcast/broadcasting"},
	{"question":"政党","answers":["せいとう"],"comment":"(n) (member of) political party"},
	{"question":"政府","answers":["せいふ"],"comment":"(n) government/administration"},
	{"question":"政権","answers":["せいけん"],"comment":"(n) (political) administration/political power"},
	{"question":"政治","answers":["せいじ"],"comment":"(n) politics/government"},
	{"question":"政策","answers":["せいさく"],"comment":"(n) political measures/policy"},
	{"question":"故","answers":["ゆえ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) reason/cause/circumstances"},
	{"question":"故人","answers":["こじん"],"comment":"(n) the deceased/old friend"},
	{"question":"故郷","answers":["こきょう","ふるさと"],"comment":"(n) home town/birthplace/old village/historic village/native place/one's old home"},
	{"question":"故障","answers":["こしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) break-down/failure/accident/out of order"},
	{"question":"敏感","answers":["びんかん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) sensibility/susceptibility/sensitive (to)/well attuned to"},
	{"question":"救い","answers":["すくい"],"comment":"(n) help/aid/relief"},
	{"question":"救う","answers":["すくう"],"comment":"(v5u) to rescue from/to help out of"},
	{"question":"救助","answers":["きゅうじょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) relief/aid/rescue"},
	{"question":"救援","answers":["きゅうえん"],"comment":"(n) relief/rescue/reinforcement"},
	{"question":"救済","answers":["きゅうさい"],"comment":"(n) relief/aid/rescue/salvation/help"},
	{"question":"敗北","answers":["はいぼく"],"comment":"(n,vs) defeat (as a verb it means 'to be defeated')"},
	{"question":"敗戦","answers":["はいせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) defeat/losing a war"},
	{"question":"教え","answers":["おしえ"],"comment":"(n) teachings/precept/lesson/doctrine"},
	{"question":"教える","answers":["おしえる"],"comment":"(v1) to teach/to inform/to instruct"},
	{"question":"教わる","answers":["おそわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be taught"},
	{"question":"教会","answers":["きょうかい"],"comment":"(n) church"},
	{"question":"教室","answers":["きょうしつ"],"comment":"(n) classroom"},
	{"question":"教師","answers":["きょうし"],"comment":"(n) teacher (classroom)"},
	{"question":"教授","answers":["きょうじゅ"],"comment":"(n) teaching/instruction/professor"},
	{"question":"教材","answers":["きょうざい"],"comment":"(n) teaching materials"},
	{"question":"教科","answers":["きょうか"],"comment":"(n) subject/curriculum"},
	{"question":"教科書","answers":["きょうかしょ"],"comment":"(n) text book"},
	{"question":"教習","answers":["きょうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) training/instruction"},
	{"question":"教職","answers":["きょうしょく"],"comment":"(n) teaching certificate/the teaching profession"},
	{"question":"教育","answers":["きょういく"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) training/education"},
	{"question":"教訓","answers":["きょうくん"],"comment":"(n) lesson/precept/moral instruction"},
	{"question":"教養","answers":["きょうよう"],"comment":"(n) culture/education/refinement/cultivation"},
	{"question":"敢えて","answers":["あえて"],"comment":"(adv) dare (to do)/challenge (to do)"},
	{"question":"散らかす","answers":["ちらかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to scatter around/to leave untidy"},
	{"question":"散らかる","answers":["ちらかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be in disorder/to lie scattered around"},
	{"question":"散らす","answers":["ちらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to scatter/to disperse/to distribute"},
	{"question":"散る","answers":["ちる"],"comment":"(v5r) to fall/to scatter (e.g. blossoms)"},
	{"question":"散歩","answers":["さんぽ"],"comment":"(n,vs) walk/stroll"},
	{"question":"敬う","answers":["うやまう"],"comment":"(v5u) to show respect/to honour"},
	{"question":"敬具","answers":["けいぐ"],"comment":"(int,n) Sincerely yours"},
	{"question":"敬意","answers":["けいい"],"comment":"(n) respect/honour"},
	{"question":"敬語","answers":["けいご"],"comment":"(n) honorific/term of respect"},
	{"question":"数","answers":["かず","すう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) number/figure"},
	{"question":"数える","answers":["かぞえる"],"comment":"(v1) to count"},
	{"question":"数字","answers":["すうじ"],"comment":"(n) numeral/figure"},
	{"question":"数学","answers":["すうがく"],"comment":"(n) mathematics/arithmetic"},
	{"question":"数詞","answers":["すうし"],"comment":"(n) numeral"},
	{"question":"整う","answers":["ととのう"],"comment":"(v5u) to be prepared/to be in order/to be put in order/to be arranged"},
	{"question":"整える","answers":["ととのえる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to put in order/to arrange/to adjust/(2) to get ready/to prepare/(3) to raise money"},
	{"question":"整備","answers":["せいび"],"comment":"(n,vs) adjustment/completion/consolidation"},
	{"question":"整列","answers":["せいれつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) stand in a row/form a line"},
	{"question":"整数","answers":["せいすう"],"comment":"(n) integer"},
	{"question":"整然","answers":["せいぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) orderly/regular/well-organized/trim/accurate"},
	{"question":"整理","answers":["せいり"],"comment":"(n,vs) sorting/arrangement/adjustment/regulation"},
	{"question":"敵","answers":["てき"],"comment":"(n) enemy/rival"},
	{"question":"敷く","answers":["しく"],"comment":"(v5k) to spread out/to lay out"},
	{"question":"敷地","answers":["しきち"],"comment":"(n) site"},
	{"question":"文","answers":["ぶん"],"comment":"(n) sentence"},
	{"question":"文体","answers":["ぶんたい"],"comment":"(n) literary style"},
	{"question":"文化","answers":["ぶんか"],"comment":"(n) culture/civilization"},
	{"question":"文化財","answers":["ぶんかざい"],"comment":"(n) cultural assets/cultural property"},
	{"question":"文句","answers":["もんく"],"comment":"(n) phrase/complaint"},
	{"question":"文字","answers":["もじ","もんじ"],"comment":"(n) letter (of alphabet)/character"},
	{"question":"文学","answers":["ぶんがく"],"comment":"(n) literature"},
	{"question":"文房具","answers":["ぶんぼうぐ"],"comment":"(n) stationery"},
	{"question":"文明","answers":["ぶんめい"],"comment":"(n) civilization/culture"},
	{"question":"文書","answers":["ぶんしょ"],"comment":"(n) document/writing/letter/note/records/archives"},
	{"question":"文法","answers":["ぶんぽう"],"comment":"(n) grammar"},
	{"question":"文献","answers":["ぶんけん"],"comment":"(n) literature/books (reference)"},
	{"question":"文章","answers":["ぶんしょう"],"comment":"(n) sentence/article"},
	{"question":"文脈","answers":["ぶんみゃく"],"comment":"(n) context"},
	{"question":"文芸","answers":["ぶんげい"],"comment":"(n) literature/art and literature/belles-lettres"},
	{"question":"文語","answers":["ぶんご"],"comment":"(n) written language/literary language"},
	{"question":"斑","answers":["むら"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (uk) unevenness/inconsistancy/erraticness/irregularity"},
	{"question":"料理","answers":["りょうり"],"comment":"(n,vs) cooking/cookery/cuisine"},
	{"question":"料金","answers":["りょうきん"],"comment":"(n) fee/charge/fare"},
	{"question":"斜め","answers":["ななめ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) obliqueness"},
	{"question":"斜面","answers":["しゃめん"],"comment":"(n) slope/slanting surface/bevel"},
	{"question":"斡旋","answers":["あっせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) kind offices/mediation"},
	{"question":"斬る","answers":["きる"],"comment":"(oK) (v5r) to behead/to murder"},
	{"question":"断つ","answers":["たつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to sever/to cut off/to suppress/to abstain (from)"},
	{"question":"断る","answers":["ことわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to refuse/to inform/to ask leave/to decline/to dismiss"},
	{"question":"断定","answers":["だんてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) conclusion/decision"},
	{"question":"断水","answers":["だんすい"],"comment":"(n) water outage"},
	{"question":"断然","answers":["だんぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) firmly/absolutely/definitely"},
	{"question":"断言","answers":["だんげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) assertion/declaration/affirmation"},
	{"question":"断面","answers":["だんめん"],"comment":"(n) cross section"},
	{"question":"新しい","answers":["あたらしい"],"comment":"(adj) new"},
	{"question":"新た","answers":["あらた"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) new/fresh/novel"},
	{"question":"新人","answers":["しんじん"],"comment":"(n) new face/newcomer"},
	{"question":"新入生","answers":["しんにゅうせい"],"comment":"(n) freshman/first-year student"},
	{"question":"新婚","answers":["しんこん"],"comment":"(n) newly-wed"},
	{"question":"新幹線","answers":["しんかんせん"],"comment":"(n) bullet train (very high speed)/shinkansen"},
	{"question":"新築","answers":["しんちく"],"comment":"(n) new building/new construction"},
	{"question":"新聞","answers":["しんぶん"],"comment":"(n) newspaper"},
	{"question":"新聞社","answers":["しんぶんしゃ"],"comment":"(n) newspaper company"},
	{"question":"新興","answers":["しんこう"],"comment":"(n) rising/developing/emergent"},
	{"question":"新鮮","answers":["しんせん"],"comment":"(adj-na) fresh"},
	{"question":"方","answers":["かた","ほう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) side"},
	{"question":"方々","answers":["かたがた","ほうぼう"],"comment":"(adv,conj,n-adv,n-t) persons/this and that/here and there/everywhere/any way/all sides/all gentlemen/all people"},
	{"question":"方向","answers":["ほうこう"],"comment":"(n) direction/course/way"},
	{"question":"方式","answers":["ほうしき"],"comment":"(n) form/method/system"},
	{"question":"方法","answers":["ほうほう"],"comment":"(n) method/manner/way/means/technique"},
	{"question":"方程式","answers":["ほうていしき"],"comment":"(n) equation"},
	{"question":"方策","answers":["ほうさく"],"comment":"(n) plan/policy"},
	{"question":"方角","answers":["ほうがく"],"comment":"(n) direction/way/compass point"},
	{"question":"方言","answers":["ほうげん"],"comment":"(n) dialect"},
	{"question":"方針","answers":["ほうしん"],"comment":"(n) objective/plan/policy"},
	{"question":"方面","answers":["ほうめん"],"comment":"(n) direction/district/field (e.g., of study)"},
	{"question":"於いて","answers":["おいて"],"comment":"(uk) at/in/on"},
	{"question":"施す","answers":["ほどこす"],"comment":"(v5s) to donate/to give/to conduct/to apply/to perform"},
	{"question":"施行","answers":["しこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) execution/enforcing/carrying out"},
	{"question":"施設","answers":["しせつ"],"comment":"(n) institution/establishment/facility/(army) engineer"},
	{"question":"旅","answers":["たび"],"comment":"(n,vs) travel/trip/journey"},
	{"question":"旅券","answers":["りょけん"],"comment":"(n) passport"},
	{"question":"旅客","answers":["りょかく"],"comment":"(n) passenger (transport)"},
	{"question":"旅行","answers":["りょこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) travel/trip"},
	{"question":"旅館","answers":["りょかん"],"comment":"(n) Japanese hotel/inn"},
	{"question":"旗","answers":["はた"],"comment":"(n) flag"},
	{"question":"既に","answers":["すでに"],"comment":"(adv) already/too late"},
	{"question":"既婚","answers":["きこん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) marriage/married"},
	{"question":"日","answers":["にち","ひ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) sun/sunshine/day"},
	{"question":"日の丸","answers":["ひのまる"],"comment":"(n) the Japanese flag"},
	{"question":"日の入り","answers":["ひのいり"],"comment":"(n) sunset"},
	{"question":"日の出","answers":["ひので"],"comment":"(n) sunrise"},
	{"question":"日中","answers":["にっちゅう"],"comment":"(n-t) daytime/broad daylight"},
	{"question":"日付","answers":["ひづけ"],"comment":"(n) date/dating"},
	{"question":"日光","answers":["にっこう"],"comment":"(n) sunlight"},
	{"question":"日取り","answers":["ひどり"],"comment":"(n) fixed date/appointed day"},
	{"question":"日向","answers":["ひなた"],"comment":"(n) sunny place/in the sun"},
	{"question":"日夜","answers":["にちや"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) day and night/always"},
	{"question":"日帰り","answers":["ひがえり"],"comment":"(n) day trip"},
	{"question":"日常","answers":["にちじょう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) ordinary/regular/everyday/usual"},
	{"question":"日当たり","answers":["ひあたり"],"comment":"(n) exposure to the sun/sunny place"},
	{"question":"日日","answers":["ひにち"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every day/daily/day after day"},
	{"question":"日時","answers":["にちじ"],"comment":"(n) date and time"},
	{"question":"日曜","answers":["にちよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Sunday"},
	{"question":"日曜日","answers":["にちようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Sunday"},
	{"question":"日本","answers":["にっぽん","にほん"],"comment":"Japan"},
	{"question":"日焼け","answers":["ひやけ"],"comment":"(n) sunburn"},
	{"question":"日用品","answers":["にちようひん"],"comment":"(n) daily necessities"},
	{"question":"日程","answers":["にってい"],"comment":"(n) agenda"},
	{"question":"日記","answers":["にっき"],"comment":"(n) diary/journal"},
	{"question":"日課","answers":["にっか"],"comment":"(n) daily lesson/daily work/daily routine"},
	{"question":"日陰","answers":["ひかげ"],"comment":"(n) shadow"},
	{"question":"日頃","answers":["ひごろ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) normally/habitually"},
	{"question":"旦那","answers":["だんな"],"comment":"(n) master (of house)/husband (informal)"},
	{"question":"旧","answers":["きゅう"],"comment":"(n,pref) ex-"},
	{"question":"旧知","answers":["きゅうち"],"comment":"(n) old friend/old friendship"},
	{"question":"早い","answers":["はやい"],"comment":"(adj) early"},
	{"question":"早める","answers":["はやめる"],"comment":"(v1) to hasten/to quicken/to expedite/to precipitate/to accelerate"},
	{"question":"早口","answers":["はやくち"],"comment":"(n) fast-talking"},
	{"question":"早急","answers":["さっきゅう","そうきゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) urgent"},
	{"question":"早速","answers":["さっそく"],"comment":"(adv) at once/immediately/without delay/promptly"},
	{"question":"昆虫","answers":["こんちゅう"],"comment":"(n) insect/bug"},
	{"question":"昇る","answers":["のぼる"],"comment":"(v5r) to arise/to ascend/to go up"},
	{"question":"昇進","answers":["しょうしん"],"comment":"(n) promotion"},
	{"question":"明い","answers":["あかるい"],"comment":"(adj) bright/cheerful"},
	{"question":"明かす","answers":["あかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pass/spend/to reveal/to divulge"},
	{"question":"明かり","answers":["あかり"],"comment":"(n) lamplight/light (in general)/brightness"},
	{"question":"明き","answers":["あき"],"comment":"(n) room/time to spare/emptiness/vacant"},
	{"question":"明ける","answers":["あける"],"comment":"(v1) to dawn/to become daylight"},
	{"question":"明け方","answers":["あけがた"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) dawn"},
	{"question":"明らか","answers":["あきらか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) obvious/evident/clear/plain"},
	{"question":"明後日","answers":["みょうごにち"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) day after tomorrow"},
	{"question":"明日","answers":["あす"],"comment":"(n-t) tomorrow"},
	{"question":"明朗","answers":["めいろう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) bright/clear/cheerful"},
	{"question":"明白","answers":["めいはく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (uk) obvious/overt/plainly/frankly"},
	{"question":"明瞭","answers":["めいりょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) clarity"},
	{"question":"明確","answers":["めいかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) clear up/clarify/define"},
	{"question":"易しい","answers":["やさしい"],"comment":"(adj) easy/plain/simple"},
	{"question":"昔","answers":["むかし"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) olden days/former"},
	{"question":"星","answers":["ほし"],"comment":"(n) star"},
	{"question":"星座","answers":["せいざ"],"comment":"(n) constellation"},
	{"question":"映える","answers":["はえる"],"comment":"(v1) to shine/to look attractive/to look pretty"},
	{"question":"映す","answers":["うつす"],"comment":"(v5s) to project/to reflect/to cast (shadow)"},
	{"question":"映る","answers":["うつる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be reflected/to harmonize with/to come out (photo)"},
	{"question":"映像","answers":["えいぞう"],"comment":"(n) reflection/image"},
	{"question":"映写","answers":["えいしゃ"],"comment":"(n) projection"},
	{"question":"映画","answers":["えいが"],"comment":"(n) movie/film"},
	{"question":"映画館","answers":["えいがかん"],"comment":"(n) movie theatre (theater)/cinema"},
	{"question":"春","answers":["はる"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) spring"},
	{"question":"昨","answers":["さく"],"comment":"(pref) last (year)/yesterday"},
	{"question":"昨日","answers":["きのう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) yesterday"},
	{"question":"是正","answers":["ぜせい"],"comment":"(n) correction/revision"},
	{"question":"是非","answers":["ぜひ"],"comment":"(adv,n) (uk) certainly/without fail"},
	{"question":"昼","answers":["ひる"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) noon/daytime"},
	{"question":"昼休み","answers":["ひるやすみ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) lunch break/noon recess/noon rest period"},
	{"question":"昼寝","answers":["ひるね"],"comment":"(n,vs) nap (at home)/siesta"},
	{"question":"昼御飯","answers":["ひるごはん"],"comment":"(n) lunch/midday meal"},
	{"question":"昼間","answers":["ひるま"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) daytime/during the day"},
	{"question":"昼食","answers":["ちゅうしょく"],"comment":"(n) lunch/midday meal"},
	{"question":"昼飯","answers":["ひるめし"],"comment":"(n) lunch (masc.)/midday meal"},
	{"question":"時","answers":["とき"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) (1) time/hour/(2) occasion/moment"},
	{"question":"時々","answers":["ときどき"],"comment":"(adv,n) sometimes"},
	{"question":"時代","answers":["じだい"],"comment":"(n-t) period/epoch/era"},
	{"question":"時刻","answers":["じこく"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) instant/time/moment"},
	{"question":"時刻表","answers":["じこくひょう"],"comment":"(n) table/diagram/chart/timetable/schedule"},
	{"question":"時差","answers":["じさ"],"comment":"(n) time difference"},
	{"question":"時折","answers":["ときおり"],"comment":"(n-adv) sometimes"},
	{"question":"時期","answers":["じき"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) time/season/period"},
	{"question":"時計","answers":["とけい"],"comment":"(n) watch/clock"},
	{"question":"時速","answers":["じそく"],"comment":"(n) speed (per hour)"},
	{"question":"時間","answers":["じかん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) time"},
	{"question":"時間割","answers":["じかんわり"],"comment":"(n) timetable/schedule"},
	{"question":"晩","answers":["ばん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) evening"},
	{"question":"晩年","answers":["ばんねん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) (one's) last years"},
	{"question":"晩御飯","answers":["ばんごはん"],"comment":"(n) dinner/evening meal"},
	{"question":"普及","answers":["ふきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) diffusion/spread"},
	{"question":"普段","answers":["ふだん"],"comment":"(adj-no,adj-na,n-adv,n) usually/habitually/ordinarily/always"},
	{"question":"普通","answers":["ふつう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,adv,n) (1) generally/ordinarily/usually/(2) train that stops at every station"},
	{"question":"普遍","answers":["ふへん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) universality/ubiquity/omnipresence"},
	{"question":"景気","answers":["けいき"],"comment":"(n) condition/state/business (condition)"},
	{"question":"景色","answers":["けしき"],"comment":"(n) scenery/scene/landscape"},
	{"question":"晴れ","answers":["はれ"],"comment":"(n) clear weather"},
	{"question":"晴れる","answers":["はれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be sunny/to clear away/to stop raining"},
	{"question":"晴天","answers":["せいてん"],"comment":"(n) fine weather"},
	{"question":"暇","answers":["ひま"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) free time/leisure/leave/spare time/(2) farewell"},
	{"question":"暑い","answers":["あつい"],"comment":"(adj) hot/warm"},
	{"question":"暖かい","answers":["あたたかい"],"comment":"(adj) warm/mild/genial"},
	{"question":"暖まる","answers":["あたたまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to warm oneself/to sun oneself/to warm up/to get warm"},
	{"question":"暖める","answers":["あたためる"],"comment":"(v1) to warm/to heat"},
	{"question":"暖房","answers":["だんぼう"],"comment":"(n) heating"},
	{"question":"暗い","answers":["くらい"],"comment":"(adj) (uk) dark/gloomy"},
	{"question":"暗殺","answers":["あんさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) assassination"},
	{"question":"暗示","answers":["あんじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) hint/suggestion"},
	{"question":"暗算","answers":["あんざん"],"comment":"(n,vs) mental arithmetic"},
	{"question":"暗記","answers":["あんき"],"comment":"(n,vs) memorization/learning by heart"},
	{"question":"暦","answers":["こよみ"],"comment":"(n) calendar/almanac"},
	{"question":"暮らし","answers":["くらし"],"comment":"(n) living/livelihood/subsistence/circumstances"},
	{"question":"暮らす","answers":["くらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to live/to get along"},
	{"question":"暮れ","answers":["くれ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) year end/sunset/nightfall/end"},
	{"question":"暮れる","answers":["くれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get dark/to end/to come to an end/to close/to run out"},
	{"question":"暴れる","answers":["あばれる"],"comment":"(v1) to act violently/to rage/to struggle/to be riotous"},
	{"question":"暴力","answers":["ぼうりょく"],"comment":"(n) violence/mayhem"},
	{"question":"暴動","answers":["ぼうどう"],"comment":"(n) insurrection/rebellion/revolt/riot/uprising"},
	{"question":"暴露","answers":["ばくろ"],"comment":"(n,vs) disclosure/exposure/revelation"},
	{"question":"暴風","answers":["ぼうふう"],"comment":"(n) storm/windstorm/gale"},
	{"question":"曇","answers":["くもり"],"comment":"(n) cloudiness/cloudy weather/shadow"},
	{"question":"曇る","answers":["くもる"],"comment":"(v5r) to become cloudy/to become dim"},
	{"question":"曜日","answers":["ようび"],"comment":"(n) day of the week"},
	{"question":"曲げる","answers":["まげる"],"comment":"(v1) to bend/to crook/to lean"},
	{"question":"曲る","answers":["まがる"],"comment":"(uv) to turn/to bend"},
	{"question":"曲線","answers":["きょくせん"],"comment":"(n) curve"},
	{"question":"更ける","answers":["ふける"],"comment":"(v1) to get late/to advance/to wear on"},
	{"question":"更に","answers":["さらに"],"comment":"(adv,conj) (uk) furthermore/again/after all/more and more/moreover"},
	{"question":"書き取る","answers":["かきとる"],"comment":"(v5r) to write down/to take dictation/to take notes"},
	{"question":"書く","answers":["かく"],"comment":"(v5k) to write"},
	{"question":"書取","answers":["かきとり"],"comment":"(n) dictation"},
	{"question":"書店","answers":["しょてん"],"comment":"(n) bookshop"},
	{"question":"書斎","answers":["しょさい"],"comment":"(n) study"},
	{"question":"書物","answers":["しょもつ"],"comment":"(n) books"},
	{"question":"書留","answers":["かきとめ"],"comment":"(n,vs) writing down/putting on record/recording/making a note of/registration (of mail)"},
	{"question":"書籍","answers":["しょせき"],"comment":"(n) book/publication"},
	{"question":"書評","answers":["しょひょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) book review"},
	{"question":"書道","answers":["しょどう"],"comment":"(n) calligraphy"},
	{"question":"書類","answers":["しょるい"],"comment":"(n) documents/official papers"},
	{"question":"替える","answers":["かえる"],"comment":"(v1) to exchange/to interchange/to substitute/to replace"},
	{"question":"最も","answers":["もっとも"],"comment":"(adv) most/extremely"},
	{"question":"最中","answers":["さいちゅう","さなか"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) in the middle of; height of; in course of; midst"},
	{"question":"最低","answers":["さいてい"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) (1) least/lowest/worst/(2) nasty/disgusting/horrible/yuck!"},
	{"question":"最初","answers":["さいしょ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) beginning/outset/first/onset"},
	{"question":"最善","answers":["さいぜん"],"comment":"(n) the very best"},
	{"question":"最後","answers":["さいご"],"comment":"(n) last/end/conclusion"},
	{"question":"最終","answers":["さいしゅう"],"comment":"(n) last/final/closing"},
	{"question":"最近","answers":["さいきん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) latest/most recent/nowadays"},
	{"question":"最高","answers":["さいこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) highest/supreme/the most"},
	{"question":"月","answers":["つき","つき"],"comment":"(n-t) moon/month"},
	{"question":"月並","answers":["つきなみ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) every month/(2) trite/common"},
	{"question":"月日","answers":["つきひ"],"comment":"(n) time/years/days"},
	{"question":"月曜","answers":["げつよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) Monday"},
	{"question":"月曜日","answers":["げつようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Monday"},
	{"question":"月末","answers":["げつまつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) end of the month"},
	{"question":"月給","answers":["げっきゅう"],"comment":"(n) monthly salary"},
	{"question":"月謝","answers":["げっしゃ"],"comment":"(n) monthly tuition fee"},
	{"question":"月賦","answers":["げっぷ"],"comment":"(n) monthly installment"},
	{"question":"有する","answers":["ゆうする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to own/to be endowed with"},
	{"question":"有る","answers":["ある"],"comment":"(v5r-i) (uk) to be/to have"},
	{"question":"有利","answers":["ゆうり"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) advantageous/better/profitable/lucrative"},
	{"question":"有力","answers":["ゆうりょく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) influence/prominence/(2) potent"},
	{"question":"有効","answers":["ゆうこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) validity/availability/effectiveness"},
	{"question":"有名","answers":["ゆうめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) fame"},
	{"question":"有料","answers":["ゆうりょう"],"comment":"(n) admission-paid/toll"},
	{"question":"有望","answers":["ゆうぼう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) good prospects/full of hope/promising"},
	{"question":"有様","answers":["ありさま"],"comment":"(n) state/condition/circumstances/the way things are or should be/truth"},
	{"question":"有機","answers":["ゆうき"],"comment":"(n) organic"},
	{"question":"有無","answers":["うむ"],"comment":"(n) yes or no/existence/flag indicator (comp)/presence or absence marker"},
	{"question":"有益","answers":["ゆうえき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) beneficial/profitable"},
	{"question":"有能","answers":["ゆうのう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) able/capable/efficient/skill"},
	{"question":"有難い","answers":["ありがたい"],"comment":"(adj) grateful/thankful/welcome/appreciated/evoking gratitude"},
	{"question":"服","answers":["ふく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) clothes"},
	{"question":"服装","answers":["ふくそう"],"comment":"(n) garments"},
	{"question":"朗らか","answers":["ほがらか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) brightness/cheerfulness/melodious"},
	{"question":"朗読","answers":["ろうどく"],"comment":"(n) reading aloud/recitation"},
	{"question":"望ましい","answers":["のぞましい"],"comment":"(adj) desirable/hoped for"},
	{"question":"望み","answers":["のぞみ"],"comment":"(n) wish/desire/(a) hope"},
	{"question":"望む","answers":["のぞむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to desire/to wish for/to see/to command (a view of)"},
	{"question":"望遠鏡","answers":["ぼうえんきょう"],"comment":"(n) telescope"},
	{"question":"朝","answers":["あさ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) morning"},
	{"question":"朝寝坊","answers":["あさねぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) oversleeping/late riser"},
	{"question":"朝御飯","answers":["あさごはん"],"comment":"(n) breakfast"},
	{"question":"期待","answers":["きたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) expectation/anticipation/hope"},
	{"question":"期日","answers":["きじつ"],"comment":"(n) fixed date/settlement date"},
	{"question":"期間","answers":["きかん"],"comment":"(n) period/term"},
	{"question":"期限","answers":["きげん"],"comment":"(n) term/period"},
	{"question":"木","answers":["き"],"comment":"(n) tree/wood/timber"},
	{"question":"木曜","answers":["もくよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Thursday"},
	{"question":"木曜日","answers":["もくようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Thursday"},
	{"question":"木材","answers":["もくざい"],"comment":"(n) lumber/timber/wood"},
	{"question":"木綿","answers":["もめん"],"comment":"(n) cotton"},
	{"question":"未だ","answers":["いまだ","まだ"],"comment":"(adv) yet/still/more/besides"},
	{"question":"未婚","answers":["みこん"],"comment":"(n) unmarried"},
	{"question":"未定","answers":["みてい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) not yet fixed/undecided/pending"},
	{"question":"未来","answers":["みらい"],"comment":"(n) future (life, tense)"},
	{"question":"未満","answers":["みまん"],"comment":"(n-suf) less than/insufficient"},
	{"question":"未熟","answers":["みじゅく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) inexperience/unripeness/raw/unskilled/immature/inexperienced"},
	{"question":"未知","answers":["みち"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) not yet known"},
	{"question":"未練","answers":["みれん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) lingering affection/attachment/regret(s)/reluctance"},
	{"question":"未開","answers":["みかい"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) savage land/backward region/uncivilized"},
	{"question":"末","answers":["すえ","まつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) the end of/powder"},
	{"question":"末っ子","answers":["すえっこ"],"comment":"(n) youngest child"},
	{"question":"末期","answers":["まっき"],"comment":"(n) deathbed/hour of death"},
	{"question":"本","answers":["ほん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,n-t) (1) origin/original"},
	{"question":"本人","answers":["ほんにん"],"comment":"(n) the person himself"},
	{"question":"本体","answers":["ほんたい"],"comment":"(n) substance/real form/object of worship"},
	{"question":"本名","answers":["ほんみょう"],"comment":"(n) real name"},
	{"question":"本国","answers":["ほんごく"],"comment":"(n) one's own country"},
	{"question":"本場","answers":["ほんば"],"comment":"(n) home/habitat/center/best place/genuine"},
	{"question":"本当","answers":["ほんと","ほんとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) truth/reality"},
	{"question":"本文","answers":["ほんぶん"],"comment":"(n) text (of document)/body (of letter)"},
	{"question":"本来","answers":["ほんらい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t,adj-no) essentially/naturally/by nature/in (and of) itself/originally"},
	{"question":"本格","answers":["ほんかく"],"comment":"(n) propriety/fundamental rules"},
	{"question":"本棚","answers":["ほんだな"],"comment":"(n) bookshelves"},
	{"question":"本気","answers":["ほんき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) seriousness/truth/sanctity"},
	{"question":"本物","answers":["ほんもの"],"comment":"(n) genuine article"},
	{"question":"本能","answers":["ほんのう"],"comment":"(n) instinct"},
	{"question":"本質","answers":["ほんしつ"],"comment":"(n) essence/true nature/reality"},
	{"question":"本部","answers":["ほんぶ"],"comment":"(n) headquarters"},
	{"question":"本音","answers":["ほんね"],"comment":"(n) real intention/motive"},
	{"question":"本館","answers":["ほんかん"],"comment":"(n) main building"},
	{"question":"札","answers":["さつ","ふだ"],"comment":"(n) (1) token/label/(2) ticket/card/(3) charm/talisman"},
	{"question":"机","answers":["つくえ"],"comment":"(n) desk"},
	{"question":"朽ちる","answers":["くちる"],"comment":"(v1) to rot"},
	{"question":"杉","answers":["すぎ"],"comment":"(n) Japanese cedar"},
	{"question":"材料","answers":["ざいりょう"],"comment":"(n) ingredients/material"},
	{"question":"材木","answers":["ざいもく"],"comment":"(n) lumber/timber"},
	{"question":"村","answers":["むら"],"comment":"(n) village"},
	{"question":"杖","answers":["つえ"],"comment":"(n) cane"},
	{"question":"束","answers":["たば"],"comment":"(n) handbreadth/bundle"},
	{"question":"束ねる","answers":["たばねる"],"comment":"(v1) to tie up in a bundle/to govern/to manage/to control/to fold (one's arms)/to administer"},
	{"question":"束縛","answers":["そくばく"],"comment":"(n,vs) restraint/shackles/restriction/confinement/binding"},
	{"question":"条件","answers":["じょうけん"],"comment":"(n) conditions/terms"},
	{"question":"条約","answers":["じょうやく"],"comment":"(n) treaty/pact"},
	{"question":"来","answers":["らい"],"comment":"since (last month)/for (10 days)/next (year)"},
	{"question":"来る","answers":["きたる","くる"],"comment":"(vk) to come/to come to hand/to arrive/to approach/to call on/to come on (rain)/to set in/to be due/to become/to grow/to get/to come from/to be caused by/to derive from"},
	{"question":"来場","answers":["らいじょう"],"comment":"(n) attendance"},
	{"question":"来年","answers":["らいねん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) next year"},
	{"question":"来日","answers":["らいにち"],"comment":"(n) arrival in Japan/coming to Japan/visit to Japan"},
	{"question":"来月","answers":["らいげつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) next month"},
	{"question":"来週","answers":["らいしゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) next week"},
	{"question":"杯","answers":["さかずき"],"comment":"(n) wine cups"},
	{"question":"東","answers":["ひがし"],"comment":"(n) east"},
	{"question":"東洋","answers":["とうよう"],"comment":"(n) Orient"},
	{"question":"東西","answers":["とうざい"],"comment":"(n) East and West/whole country/Orient and Occident/Your attention please"},
	{"question":"松","answers":["まつ"],"comment":"(n) (1) pine tree/(2) highest (of a three-tier ranking system)"},
	{"question":"板","answers":["いた"],"comment":"(n) board/plank"},
	{"question":"枕","answers":["まくら"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) pillow/bolster"},
	{"question":"林","answers":["はやし"],"comment":"(n) woods/forest"},
	{"question":"林業","answers":["りんぎょう"],"comment":"(n) forestry"},
	{"question":"枚数","answers":["まいすう"],"comment":"(n) the number of flat things"},
	{"question":"果して","answers":["はたして"],"comment":"(adv) as was expected/really"},
	{"question":"果たす","answers":["はたす"],"comment":"(v5s) to accomplish/to fulfill/to carry out/to achieve"},
	{"question":"果て","answers":["はて"],"comment":"(n) the end/the extremity/the limit(s)/the result"},
	{"question":"果てる","answers":["はてる"],"comment":"(v1) to end/to be finished/to be exhausted/to die/to perish"},
	{"question":"果実","answers":["かじつ"],"comment":"(n) fruit/nut/berry."},
	{"question":"果物","answers":["くだもの"],"comment":"(n) fruit"},
	{"question":"枝","answers":["えだ"],"comment":"(n) branch/bow/twig/limb"},
	{"question":"枠","answers":["わく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) frame/slide"},
	{"question":"枯れる","answers":["かれる"],"comment":"(v1) to wither/to die (plant)/to be blasted (plant)"},
	{"question":"架空","answers":["かくう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) aerial/overhead/fiction/fanciful"},
	{"question":"柄","answers":["え","がら"],"comment":"(n) hilt (of a sword)/haft (of a dagger)/handgrip"},
	{"question":"染まる","answers":["そまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to dye"},
	{"question":"染みる","answers":["しみる"],"comment":"(aux-v,v1) to have a touch of/to look like"},
	{"question":"染める","answers":["そめる"],"comment":"(v1) to dye/to colour"},
	{"question":"柔らかい","answers":["やわらかい"],"comment":"(adj) soft/tender/limp"},
	{"question":"柔軟","answers":["じゅうなん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) flexible/lithe"},
	{"question":"柔道","answers":["じゅうどう"],"comment":"(n) judo"},
	{"question":"柵","answers":["さく"],"comment":"(n) fence/paling"},
	{"question":"栄える","answers":["さかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to shine/to look attractive/to look pretty"},
	{"question":"栄養","answers":["えいよう"],"comment":"(n) nutrition/nourishment"},
	{"question":"栓","answers":["せん"],"comment":"(n) stopper/cork/stopcock"},
	{"question":"校庭","answers":["こうてい"],"comment":"(n) campus"},
	{"question":"校舎","answers":["こうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) school building"},
	{"question":"校長","answers":["こうちょう"],"comment":"(n) principal/headmaster"},
	{"question":"株","answers":["かぶ"],"comment":"(n) share/stock/stump (of tree)"},
	{"question":"株式","answers":["かぶしき"],"comment":"(n) stock (company)"},
	{"question":"核","answers":["かく"],"comment":"(n) nucleus/kernel"},
	{"question":"根","answers":["ね"],"comment":"(n) root"},
	{"question":"根回し","answers":["ねまわし"],"comment":"(n) making necessary arrangements"},
	{"question":"根底","answers":["こんてい"],"comment":"(n) root/basis/foundation"},
	{"question":"根拠","answers":["こんきょ"],"comment":"(n) basis/foundation"},
	{"question":"根本","answers":["こんぽん"],"comment":"(n) origin/source/foundation/root/base/principle"},
	{"question":"根気","answers":["こんき"],"comment":"(n) (1) patience/(2) perseverance/energy"},
	{"question":"格","answers":["かく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) status/character/case"},
	{"question":"格別","answers":["かくべつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) exceptional"},
	{"question":"格好","answers":["かっこう"],"comment":"(adj-no,adj-na,n) shape/form/posture/suitability/moderateness (in price)/appearance/manner"},
	{"question":"格差","answers":["かくさ"],"comment":"(n) qualitative difference/disparity"},
	{"question":"栽培","answers":["さいばい"],"comment":"(n) cultivation"},
	{"question":"桁","answers":["けた"],"comment":"(n) column/beam/digit"},
	{"question":"案","answers":["あん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) plan/suffix meaning draft"},
	{"question":"案じる","answers":["あんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to be anxious/to ponder"},
	{"question":"案内","answers":["あんない"],"comment":"(n,vs) information/guidance/leading"},
	{"question":"案外","answers":["あんがい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv) unexpectedly"},
	{"question":"桜","answers":["さくら"],"comment":"(n) cherry blossom/cherry tree"},
	{"question":"桟橋","answers":["さんばし"],"comment":"(n) wharf/bridge/jetty/pier"},
	{"question":"梅","answers":["うめ"],"comment":"(n) plum/plum-tree/lowest (of a three-tier ranking system)"},
	{"question":"梅干し","answers":["うめぼし"],"comment":"(n) dried plum"},
	{"question":"梅雨","answers":["つゆ","ばいう"],"comment":"(n) rainy season/rain during the rainy season"},
	{"question":"梢","answers":["こずえ"],"comment":"(n) treetop"},
	{"question":"梯子","answers":["はしご"],"comment":"(n) ladder/stairs"},
	{"question":"棄権","answers":["きけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) abstain from voting/renunciation of a right"},
	{"question":"棒","answers":["ぼう"],"comment":"(n) pole/rod/stick"},
	{"question":"棚","answers":["たな"],"comment":"(n) shelves/rack"},
	{"question":"棟","answers":["とう"],"comment":"(n) ridge (of roof)"},
	{"question":"森","answers":["もり"],"comment":"(n) forest"},
	{"question":"森林","answers":["しんりん"],"comment":"(n) forest/woods"},
	{"question":"椀","answers":["わん"],"comment":"(n) Japanese soup bowl/wooden bowl"},
	{"question":"椅子","answers":["いす"],"comment":"(n) chair"},
	{"question":"植える","answers":["うえる"],"comment":"(v1) to plant/to grow"},
	{"question":"植わる","answers":["うわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be planted"},
	{"question":"植木","answers":["うえき"],"comment":"(n) garden shrubs/trees/potted plant"},
	{"question":"植民地","answers":["しょくみんち"],"comment":"(n) colony"},
	{"question":"植物","answers":["しょくぶつ"],"comment":"(n) plant/vegetation"},
	{"question":"検事","answers":["けんじ"],"comment":"(n) public prosecutor"},
	{"question":"検査","answers":["けんさ"],"comment":"(n,vs) inspection (e.g. customs, factory)/examination"},
	{"question":"検討","answers":["けんとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) consideration/examination/investigation/study/scrutiny"},
	{"question":"楕円","answers":["だえん"],"comment":"(n) ellipse"},
	{"question":"業務","answers":["ぎょうむ"],"comment":"(n) business/affairs/duties/work"},
	{"question":"業績","answers":["ぎょうせき"],"comment":"(n) achievement/performance/results/work/contribution"},
	{"question":"業者","answers":["ぎょうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) trader/merchant"},
	{"question":"極","answers":["ごく"],"comment":"(adv,n) quite/very"},
	{"question":"極めて","answers":["きわめて"],"comment":"(adv) exceedingly/extremely"},
	{"question":"極楽","answers":["ごくらく"],"comment":"(n) paradise"},
	{"question":"極端","answers":["きょくたん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) extreme/extremity"},
	{"question":"楽","answers":["らく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,n-suf) comfort/ease"},
	{"question":"楽しい","answers":["たのしい"],"comment":"(adj) enjoyable/fun"},
	{"question":"楽しみ","answers":["たのしみ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) enjoyment/pleasure"},
	{"question":"楽器","answers":["がっき"],"comment":"(n) musical instrument"},
	{"question":"楽観","answers":["らっかん"],"comment":"(n) optimism"},
	{"question":"楽譜","answers":["がくふ"],"comment":"(n) score (music)"},
	{"question":"概念","answers":["がいねん"],"comment":"(n) general idea/concept/notion"},
	{"question":"概略","answers":["がいりゃく"],"comment":"(n-t) outline/summary/gist/in brief"},
	{"question":"概説","answers":["がいせつ"],"comment":"(n) general statement/outline"},
	{"question":"概論","answers":["がいろん"],"comment":"(n) intro/outline/general remarks"},
	{"question":"構う","answers":["かまう"],"comment":"(v5u) to mind/to care about/to be concerned about"},
	{"question":"構える","answers":["かまえる"],"comment":"(v1) to set up"},
	{"question":"構想","answers":["こうそう"],"comment":"(n) plan/plot/idea/conception"},
	{"question":"構成","answers":["こうせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) organization/composition"},
	{"question":"構造","answers":["こうぞう"],"comment":"(n) structure/construction"},
	{"question":"様","answers":["さま","よう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n) way/manner/kind/sort/appearance/like/such as/so as to/in order to/so that/yang"},
	{"question":"様々","answers":["さまざま"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) varied/various"},
	{"question":"様子","answers":["ようす"],"comment":"(n) aspect/state/appearance"},
	{"question":"様式","answers":["ようしき"],"comment":"(n) style/form/pattern"},
	{"question":"様相","answers":["ようそう"],"comment":"(n) aspect"},
	{"question":"標本","answers":["ひょうほん"],"comment":"(n) example/specimen"},
	{"question":"標準","answers":["ひょうじゅん"],"comment":"(n) standard/level"},
	{"question":"標語","answers":["ひょうご"],"comment":"(n) motto/slogan/catchword"},
	{"question":"標識","answers":["ひょうしき"],"comment":"(n) sign/mark"},
	{"question":"模倣","answers":["もほう"],"comment":"(n,vs) imitation/copying"},
	{"question":"模型","answers":["もけい"],"comment":"(n) model/dummy/maquette"},
	{"question":"模様","answers":["もよう"],"comment":"(n) pattern/figure/design"},
	{"question":"模範","answers":["もはん"],"comment":"(n) exemplar/exemplification/exemplum/model/example"},
	{"question":"模索","answers":["もさく"],"comment":"(n) groping (for)"},
	{"question":"権利","answers":["けんり"],"comment":"(n) right/privilege"},
	{"question":"権力","answers":["けんりょく"],"comment":"(n) (political) power/authority/influence"},
	{"question":"権威","answers":["けんい"],"comment":"(n) authority/power/influence"},
	{"question":"権限","answers":["けんげん"],"comment":"(n) power/authority/jurisdiction"},
	{"question":"横","answers":["よこ"],"comment":"(n) beside/side/width"},
	{"question":"横切る","answers":["よこぎる"],"comment":"(v5r) to cross (e.g. arms)/to traverse"},
	{"question":"横断","answers":["おうだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) crossing"},
	{"question":"横綱","answers":["よこづな"],"comment":"(n) sumo grand champion"},
	{"question":"樹木","answers":["じゅもく"],"comment":"(n) trees and shrubs/arbour"},
	{"question":"樹立","answers":["じゅりつ"],"comment":"(n) establish/create"},
	{"question":"橋","answers":["はし"],"comment":"(n) bridge"},
	{"question":"橋渡し","answers":["はしわたし"],"comment":"(n) 'bridge building'/mediation"},
	{"question":"機会","answers":["きかい"],"comment":"(n) chance/opportunity"},
	{"question":"機嫌","answers":["きげん"],"comment":"(n) humour/temper/mood"},
	{"question":"機械","answers":["きかい"],"comment":"(n) machine/mechanism"},
	{"question":"機構","answers":["きこう"],"comment":"(n) mechanism/organization"},
	{"question":"機能","answers":["きのう"],"comment":"(n) function/faculty"},
	{"question":"機関","answers":["きかん"],"comment":"(n) organ/mechanism/facility/engine"},
	{"question":"機関車","answers":["きかんしゃ"],"comment":"(n) locomotive/engine"},
	{"question":"檻","answers":["おり"],"comment":"(n) cage/pen/jail cell"},
	{"question":"櫛","answers":["くし"],"comment":"(n) comb"},
	{"question":"欄","answers":["らん"],"comment":"(n) column of text (e.g. as in a newspaper)"},
	{"question":"欠く","answers":["かく"],"comment":"(v5k) to lack/to break/to crack/to chip"},
	{"question":"欠ける","answers":["かける"],"comment":"(v1) to be lacking"},
	{"question":"欠乏","answers":["けつぼう"],"comment":"(n) want/shortage/famine"},
	{"question":"欠席","answers":["けっせき"],"comment":"(n,vs) absence/non-attendance"},
	{"question":"欠点","answers":["けってん"],"comment":"(n) faults/defect/weakness"},
	{"question":"欠陥","answers":["けっかん"],"comment":"(n) defect/fault/deficiency"},
	{"question":"次","answers":["つぎ"],"comment":"(n) next/stage station/stage/subsequent"},
	{"question":"次々","answers":["つぎつぎ"],"comment":"(adv,n) in succession/one by one"},
	{"question":"次ぐ","answers":["つぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to rank next to/to come after"},
	{"question":"次第","answers":["しだい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) (1) order/precedence/(2) circumstances/(3) immediate(ly)/as soon as/dependent upon"},
	{"question":"欧米","answers":["おうべい"],"comment":"Europe and America/the West"},
	{"question":"欲","answers":["よく"],"comment":"(n) greed/wants"},
	{"question":"欲しい","answers":["ほしい"],"comment":"(adj) wanted/wished for/in need of/desired"},
	{"question":"欲張り","answers":["よくばり"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) avarice/covetousness/greed"},
	{"question":"欲望","answers":["よくぼう"],"comment":"(n) desire/appetite"},
	{"question":"欲深い","answers":["よくふかい"],"comment":"(adj) greedy"},
	{"question":"欺く","answers":["あざむく"],"comment":"(v5k) to deceive"},
	{"question":"歌","answers":["うた"],"comment":"(n) song/poetry"},
	{"question":"歌う","answers":["うたう"],"comment":"(v5u) to sing"},
	{"question":"歌手","answers":["かしゅ"],"comment":"(n) singer"},
	{"question":"歌謡","answers":["かよう"],"comment":"(n) song/ballad"},
	{"question":"歓声","answers":["かんせい"],"comment":"(n) cheer/shout of joy"},
	{"question":"歓迎","answers":["かんげい"],"comment":"(n,vs) welcome/reception"},
	{"question":"止す","answers":["よす"],"comment":"(v5s) to cease/to abolish/to resign/to give up"},
	{"question":"止まる","answers":["とまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to come to a halt"},
	{"question":"止む","answers":["やむ"],"comment":"(v5m,vi) to cease/to stop/to be over"},
	{"question":"止める","answers":["とどめる","とめる","やめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to end/to stop/to cease/to resign"},
	{"question":"正","answers":["せい"],"comment":"(n) (logical) true/regular"},
	{"question":"正しい","answers":["ただしい"],"comment":"(adj) right/just/correct/righteous/honest/truthful/proper/straightforward/perfect"},
	{"question":"正体","answers":["しょうたい"],"comment":"(n) natural shape/one's true colors/true character/consciousness/senses"},
	{"question":"正午","answers":["しょうご"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) noon/mid-day"},
	{"question":"正味","answers":["しょうみ"],"comment":"(n) net (weight)"},
	{"question":"正常","answers":["せいじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) normalcy/normality/normal"},
	{"question":"正式","answers":["せいしき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) due form/official/formality"},
	{"question":"正当","answers":["せいとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) just/justifiable/right/due/proper/equitable/reasonable/legitimate/lawful"},
	{"question":"正方形","answers":["せいほうけい"],"comment":"(n) square"},
	{"question":"正月","answers":["しょうがつ"],"comment":"(n) New Year/New Year's Day/the first month/January"},
	{"question":"正直","answers":["しょうじき"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) honesty/integrity/frankness"},
	{"question":"正確","answers":["せいかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) accurate/punctuality/exactness/authenticity/veracity"},
	{"question":"正義","answers":["せいぎ"],"comment":"(n) justice/right/righteousness/correct meaning"},
	{"question":"正規","answers":["せいき"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) regular/legal/formal/established/legitimate"},
	{"question":"正解","answers":["せいかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) correct/right/correct interpretation (answer, solution)"},
	{"question":"正門","answers":["せいもん"],"comment":"(n) main gate/main entrance"},
	{"question":"正面","answers":["しょうめん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) the front/honesty"},
	{"question":"武力","answers":["ぶりょく"],"comment":"(n) armed might/military power/the sword/force"},
	{"question":"武器","answers":["ぶき"],"comment":"(n) weapon/arms/ordinance"},
	{"question":"武士","answers":["ぶし"],"comment":"(n) warrior/samurai"},
	{"question":"武装","answers":["ぶそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) arms/armament/armed"},
	{"question":"歩く","answers":["あるく"],"comment":"(v5k) to walk"},
	{"question":"歩み","answers":["あゆみ"],"comment":"(n) walking"},
	{"question":"歩む","answers":["あゆむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to walk/to go on foot"},
	{"question":"歩道","answers":["ほどう"],"comment":"(n) footpath/walkway/sidewalk"},
	{"question":"歪む","answers":["ひずむ","ゆがむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to warp/to swerve/to deflect/to be crooked/to be distorted/to be bent/to incline/to slant/to be perverted/to be gross-grained/to get bent/to be strained"},
	{"question":"歯","answers":["は"],"comment":"(n) tooth"},
	{"question":"歯医者","answers":["はいしゃ"],"comment":"(n) dentist"},
	{"question":"歯磨き","answers":["はみがき"],"comment":"(n) dentifrice/toothpaste"},
	{"question":"歯科","answers":["しか"],"comment":"(n) dentistry"},
	{"question":"歯車","answers":["はぐるま"],"comment":"(n) gear/cog-wheel"},
	{"question":"歴史","answers":["れきし"],"comment":"(n) history"},
	{"question":"死","answers":["し"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) death/decease"},
	{"question":"死ぬ","answers":["しぬ"],"comment":"(v5n) to die"},
	{"question":"死亡","answers":["しぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) death/mortality"},
	{"question":"死体","answers":["したい"],"comment":"(n) corpse"},
	{"question":"死刑","answers":["しけい"],"comment":"(n) death penalty/capital punishment"},
	{"question":"殊に","answers":["ことに"],"comment":"(adv) especially/above all"},
	{"question":"残す","answers":["のこす"],"comment":"(v5s) to leave (behind, over)/to bequeath/to save/to reserve"},
	{"question":"残らず","answers":["のこらず"],"comment":"(adv) all/entirely/completely/without exception"},
	{"question":"残り","answers":["のこり"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) remnant/residue/remaining/left-over"},
	{"question":"残る","answers":["のこる"],"comment":"(v5r) to remain/to be left"},
	{"question":"残念","answers":["ざんねん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) deplorable/bad luck/regret/disappointment"},
	{"question":"残酷","answers":["ざんこく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cruelty/harshness"},
	{"question":"残金","answers":["ざんきん"],"comment":"(n) remaining money"},
	{"question":"残高","answers":["ざんだか"],"comment":"(n) (bank) balance/remainder"},
	{"question":"殖える","answers":["ふえる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to increase/to multiply"},
	{"question":"殖やす","answers":["ふやす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to increase/to add to/to augment"},
	{"question":"段","answers":["だん"],"comment":"(n) step/stair/flight of steps/grade/rank/level"},
	{"question":"段階","answers":["だんかい"],"comment":"(n) gradation/grade/stage"},
	{"question":"殺す","answers":["ころす"],"comment":"(v5s) to kill"},
	{"question":"殺人","answers":["さつじん"],"comment":"(n) murder"},
	{"question":"殻","answers":["から"],"comment":"(n) shell/husk/hull/chaff"},
	{"question":"殿様","answers":["とのさま"],"comment":"(n) feudal lord"},
	{"question":"母","answers":["はは"],"comment":"(n) (hum) mother"},
	{"question":"母国","answers":["ぼこく"],"comment":"(n) one's homeland"},
	{"question":"母校","answers":["ぼこう"],"comment":"(n) alma mater"},
	{"question":"母親","answers":["ははおや"],"comment":"(n) mother"},
	{"question":"毎年","answers":["まいとし","まいねん"],"comment":"(n-t) every year/yearly/annually"},
	{"question":"毎度","answers":["まいど"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) each time/common service-sector greeting"},
	{"question":"毎日","answers":["まいにち"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every day"},
	{"question":"毎晩","answers":["まいばん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every night"},
	{"question":"毎月","answers":["まいげつ","まいつき"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) every month/each month/monthly"},
	{"question":"毎朝","answers":["まいあさ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every morning"},
	{"question":"毎週","answers":["まいしゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every week"},
	{"question":"毒","answers":["どく"],"comment":"(n) poison/toxicant"},
	{"question":"比べる","answers":["くらべる"],"comment":"(v1) to compare"},
	{"question":"比例","answers":["ひれい"],"comment":"(n) proportion"},
	{"question":"比率","answers":["ひりつ"],"comment":"(n) ratio/proportion/percentage"},
	{"question":"比較","answers":["ひかく"],"comment":"(n,vs) comparison"},
	{"question":"比較的","answers":["ひかくてき"],"comment":"(adv) comparatively/relatively"},
	{"question":"比重","answers":["ひじゅう"],"comment":"(n) specific gravity"},
	{"question":"毛","answers":["け"],"comment":"(n) hair/fur"},
	{"question":"毛布","answers":["もうふ"],"comment":"(n) blanket"},
	{"question":"毛皮","answers":["けがわ"],"comment":"(n) fur/skin/pelt"},
	{"question":"毛糸","answers":["けいと"],"comment":"(n) knitting wool"},
	{"question":"氏","answers":["し"],"comment":"(n) family name/lineage/birth"},
	{"question":"氏名","answers":["しめい"],"comment":"(n) full name/identity"},
	{"question":"民俗","answers":["みんぞく"],"comment":"(n) people/race/nation/racial customs/folk customs"},
	{"question":"民宿","answers":["みんしゅく"],"comment":"(n) private home providing lodging for travelers"},
	{"question":"民族","answers":["みんぞく"],"comment":"(n) people/race/nation/racial customs/folk customs"},
	{"question":"民謡","answers":["みんよう"],"comment":"(n) folk song/popular song"},
	{"question":"民間","answers":["みんかん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) private/civilian/civil/popular/folk/unofficial"},
	{"question":"気","answers":["き"],"comment":"(n) spirit/mood"},
	{"question":"気に入る","answers":["きにいる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be pleased with/to suit"},
	{"question":"気の毒","answers":["きのどく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pitiful/a pity"},
	{"question":"気を付ける","answers":["きをつける"],"comment":"(exp) to be careful/to pay attention/to take care"},
	{"question":"気付く","answers":["きづく"],"comment":"(v5k) to notice/to recognize/to become aware of/to perceive/to realize"},
	{"question":"気体","answers":["きたい"],"comment":"(n) vapour/gas"},
	{"question":"気候","answers":["きこう"],"comment":"(n) climate"},
	{"question":"気兼ね","answers":["きがね"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) hesitance/diffidence/feeling constraint/fear of troubling someone/having scruples about doing something"},
	{"question":"気分","answers":["きぶん"],"comment":"(n) feeling/mood"},
	{"question":"気味","answers":["きみ"],"comment":"(n-suf) -like/-looking/-looked"},
	{"question":"気品","answers":["きひん"],"comment":"(n) aroma"},
	{"question":"気圧","answers":["きあつ"],"comment":"(n) atmospheric pressure"},
	{"question":"気持ち","answers":["きもち"],"comment":"(n) feeling/sensation/mood"},
	{"question":"気流","answers":["きりゅう"],"comment":"(n) atmospheric current"},
	{"question":"気温","answers":["きおん"],"comment":"(n) temperature"},
	{"question":"気象","answers":["きしょう"],"comment":"(n) weather/climate"},
	{"question":"気質","answers":["きしつ"],"comment":"(n) spirit/character/trait/temperament/disposition"},
	{"question":"気軽","answers":["きがる"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cheerful/buoyant/lighthearted"},
	{"question":"気配","answers":["けはい"],"comment":"(n) indication/market trend/worry"},
	{"question":"気障","answers":["きざ"],"comment":"(adj-na) affectation/conceit/snobbery"},
	{"question":"気風","answers":["きふう"],"comment":"(n) character/traits/ethos"},
	{"question":"水","answers":["みず"],"comment":"(n) water"},
	{"question":"水分","answers":["すいぶん"],"comment":"(n) moisture"},
	{"question":"水平","answers":["すいへい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) water level/horizon"},
	{"question":"水平線","answers":["すいへいせん"],"comment":"(n) horizon"},
	{"question":"水曜","answers":["すいよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Wednesday"},
	{"question":"水曜日","answers":["すいようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Wednesday"},
	{"question":"水気","answers":["みずけ"],"comment":"(n) (1) moisture/dampness/vapor"},
	{"question":"水泳","answers":["すいえい"],"comment":"(n,vs) swimming"},
	{"question":"水洗","answers":["すいせん"],"comment":"(n) flushing"},
	{"question":"水源","answers":["すいげん"],"comment":"(n) source of river/fountainhead"},
	{"question":"水準","answers":["すいじゅん"],"comment":"(n) (1) water level/(2) level/standard"},
	{"question":"水滴","answers":["すいてき"],"comment":"(n) drop of water"},
	{"question":"水産","answers":["すいさん"],"comment":"(n) marine products/fisheries"},
	{"question":"水田","answers":["すいでん"],"comment":"(n) (water-filled) paddy field"},
	{"question":"水着","answers":["みずぎ"],"comment":"(n) bathing suit (woman's)"},
	{"question":"水筒","answers":["すいとう"],"comment":"(n) canteen/flask/water bottle"},
	{"question":"水素","answers":["すいそ"],"comment":"(n) hydrogen"},
	{"question":"水蒸気","answers":["すいじょうき"],"comment":"(n) water vapour/steam"},
	{"question":"水道","answers":["すいどう"],"comment":"(n) water service/water supply"},
	{"question":"水面","answers":["すいめん"],"comment":"(n) water's surface"},
	{"question":"氷","answers":["こおり"],"comment":"ice/hail"},
	{"question":"永い","answers":["ながい"],"comment":"(adj) long/lengthy"},
	{"question":"永久","answers":["えいきゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) eternity/perpetuity/immortality"},
	{"question":"永遠","answers":["えいえん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) eternity/perpetuity/immortality/permanence"},
	{"question":"氾濫","answers":["はんらん"],"comment":"(n,vs) overflowing/flood"},
	{"question":"汁","answers":["しる"],"comment":"(n) juice/sap/soup/broth"},
	{"question":"求める","answers":["もとめる"],"comment":"(v1) to seek/to request/to demand/to want/to wish for/to search for/to pursue (pleasure)/to hunt (a job)/to buy"},
	{"question":"汗","answers":["あせ"],"comment":"(n) sweat/perspiration"},
	{"question":"汚い","answers":["きたない"],"comment":"(adj) dirty/unclean/filthy"},
	{"question":"汚す","answers":["よごす"],"comment":"(v5s) (1) to disgrace/to dishonour/(2) to pollute/to contaminate/to soil/to make dirty/to stain"},
	{"question":"汚れ","answers":["よごれ"],"comment":"(n) dirt/filth"},
	{"question":"汚れる","answers":["よごれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get dirty/to become dirty"},
	{"question":"汚染","answers":["おせん"],"comment":"(n) pollution/contamination"},
	{"question":"池","answers":["いけ"],"comment":"(n) pond"},
	{"question":"汲む","answers":["くむ"],"comment":"(v5m) (1) to draw (water)/to ladle/to dip/to scoop/to pump/(2) to have a drink together/(3) to consider/to sympathize with"},
	{"question":"決","answers":["けつ"],"comment":"(n) decision/vote"},
	{"question":"決して","answers":["けっして"],"comment":"(adv) never/by no means"},
	{"question":"決まり","answers":["きまり"],"comment":"(n) settlement/conclusion/regulation/rule/custom"},
	{"question":"決める","answers":["きめる"],"comment":"(v1) to decide"},
	{"question":"決る","answers":["きまる"],"comment":"(io) (v5r) to be decided/to be settled/to look good in (clothes)"},
	{"question":"決勝","answers":["けっしょう"],"comment":"(n) decision of a contest/finals (in sports)"},
	{"question":"決定","answers":["けってい"],"comment":"(n) decision/determination"},
	{"question":"決心","answers":["けっしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) determination/resolution"},
	{"question":"決意","answers":["けつい"],"comment":"(n) decision/determination"},
	{"question":"決断","answers":["けつだん"],"comment":"(n) decision/determination"},
	{"question":"決算","answers":["けっさん"],"comment":"(n) balance sheet/settlement of accounts"},
	{"question":"決行","answers":["けっこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) doing (with resolve)/carrying out (i.e. a plan)"},
	{"question":"決議","answers":["けつぎ"],"comment":"(n) resolution/vote/decision"},
	{"question":"汽船","answers":["きせん"],"comment":"(n) steamship"},
	{"question":"汽車","answers":["きしゃ"],"comment":"(n) train (steam)"},
	{"question":"沈む","answers":["しずむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to sink/to feel depressed"},
	{"question":"沈める","answers":["しずめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to sink/to submerge"},
	{"question":"沈殿","answers":["ちんでん"],"comment":"(n,vs) precipitation/deposition/settlement (e.g. of sediment)"},
	{"question":"沈没","answers":["ちんぼつ"],"comment":"(n) sinking/foundering"},
	{"question":"沈黙","answers":["ちんもく"],"comment":"(n) silence/reticence"},
	{"question":"沖","answers":["おき"],"comment":"(n) open sea"},
	{"question":"没収","answers":["ぼっしゅう"],"comment":"(n) forfeited"},
	{"question":"没落","answers":["ぼつらく"],"comment":"(n) ruin/fall/collapse"},
	{"question":"河","answers":["かわ"],"comment":"(n) river/stream"},
	{"question":"河川","answers":["かせん"],"comment":"(n) rivers"},
	{"question":"沸かす","answers":["わかす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to boil/to heat"},
	{"question":"沸く","answers":["わく"],"comment":"(v5k) to boil/to grow hot/to get excited/to gush forth"},
	{"question":"沸騰","answers":["ふっとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) boiling/seething"},
	{"question":"油","answers":["あぶら"],"comment":"(n) oil"},
	{"question":"油断","answers":["ゆだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) negligence/unpreparedness"},
	{"question":"油絵","answers":["あぶらえ"],"comment":"(n) oil painting"},
	{"question":"治す","answers":["なおす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to cure/to heal/to fix/to correct/to repair"},
	{"question":"治まる","answers":["おさまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be at peace/to clamp down/to lessen (storm, terror, anger)"},
	{"question":"治める","answers":["おさめる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to govern/to manage/(2) to subdue"},
	{"question":"治る","answers":["なおる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be cured/to heal/to get mended/to get well/to be repaired/to be fixed"},
	{"question":"治安","answers":["ちあん"],"comment":"(n) public order"},
	{"question":"治療","answers":["ちりょう"],"comment":"(n) medical treatment"},
	{"question":"沼","answers":["ぬま"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) swamp/bog/pond/lake"},
	{"question":"沿う","answers":["そう"],"comment":"(v5u) to run along/to follow"},
	{"question":"沿岸","answers":["えんがん"],"comment":"(n) coast/shore"},
	{"question":"沿線","answers":["えんせん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) along railway line"},
	{"question":"泉","answers":["いずみ"],"comment":"(n) spring/fountain"},
	{"question":"泊まる","answers":["とまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stay at (e.g. hotel)"},
	{"question":"泊める","answers":["とめる"],"comment":"(v1) to give shelter to/to lodge"},
	{"question":"法","answers":["ほう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) Act (law: the X Act)"},
	{"question":"法則","answers":["ほうそく"],"comment":"(n) law/rule"},
	{"question":"法学","answers":["ほうがく"],"comment":"(n) law/jurisprudence"},
	{"question":"法廷","answers":["ほうてい"],"comment":"(n) courtroom"},
	{"question":"法律","answers":["ほうりつ"],"comment":"(n) law"},
	{"question":"法案","answers":["ほうあん"],"comment":"(n) bill (law)"},
	{"question":"泡","answers":["あわ"],"comment":"(n) bubble/foam/froth/head on beer"},
	{"question":"波","answers":["なみ"],"comment":"(n) wave"},
	{"question":"泣く","answers":["なく"],"comment":"(v5k) to cry/to sing (bird)"},
	{"question":"泥","answers":["どろ"],"comment":"(n) mud"},
	{"question":"泥棒","answers":["どろぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) thief/burglar/robber/theft"},
	{"question":"注","answers":["ちゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) annotation/explanatory note"},
	{"question":"注ぐ","answers":["そそぐ","つぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to pour (into)/to irrigate/to pay/to fill/to feed (e.g. a fire)"},
	{"question":"注す","answers":["さす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pour (drink)/to serve (drinks)"},
	{"question":"注射","answers":["ちゅうしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) injection"},
	{"question":"注意","answers":["ちゅうい"],"comment":"(n,vs) caution/being careful/attention (heed)/warning/advice"},
	{"question":"注文","answers":["ちゅうもん"],"comment":"(n,vs) order/request"},
	{"question":"注目","answers":["ちゅうもく"],"comment":"(n,vs) notice/attention/observation"},
	{"question":"泳ぎ","answers":["およぎ"],"comment":"(n) swimming"},
	{"question":"泳ぐ","answers":["およぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to swim"},
	{"question":"洋品店","answers":["ようひんてん"],"comment":"(n) shop which handles Western-style apparel and accessories"},
	{"question":"洋服","answers":["ようふく"],"comment":"(n) Western-style clothes"},
	{"question":"洋風","answers":["ようふう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) western style"},
	{"question":"洒落","answers":["しゃれ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) joke/pun/witticism"},
	{"question":"洒落る","answers":["しゃれる"],"comment":"(v1) to joke/to play on words/to dress stylishly"},
	{"question":"洗う","answers":["あらう"],"comment":"(v5u) to wash"},
	{"question":"洗剤","answers":["せんざい"],"comment":"(n) detergent/washing material"},
	{"question":"洗濯","answers":["せんたく"],"comment":"(n,vs) washing/laundry"},
	{"question":"洗面","answers":["せんめん"],"comment":"(n,vs) wash up (one's face)/have a wash"},
	{"question":"津波","answers":["つなみ"],"comment":"(n) tsunami/tidal wave"},
	{"question":"洪水","answers":["こうずい"],"comment":"(n) flood"},
	{"question":"活力","answers":["かつりょく"],"comment":"(n) vitality/energy"},
	{"question":"活動","answers":["かつどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) action/activity"},
	{"question":"活字","answers":["かつじ"],"comment":"(n) printing type"},
	{"question":"活気","answers":["かっき"],"comment":"(n) energy/liveliness"},
	{"question":"活用","answers":["かつよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) conjugation/practical use"},
	{"question":"活発","answers":["かっぱつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) vigor/active"},
	{"question":"活躍","answers":["かつやく"],"comment":"(n) activity"},
	{"question":"派手","answers":["はで"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) showy/loud/gay/flashy/gaudy"},
	{"question":"派遣","answers":["はけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) dispatch/send"},
	{"question":"流し","answers":["ながし"],"comment":"(n) sink"},
	{"question":"流す","answers":["ながす"],"comment":"(v5s) to drain/to float/to shed (blood, tears)/to cruise (e.g. taxi)"},
	{"question":"流れ","answers":["ながれ"],"comment":"(n) stream/current"},
	{"question":"流れる","answers":["ながれる"],"comment":"(v1) to stream/to flow/to run (ink)/to be washed away"},
	{"question":"流域","answers":["りゅういき"],"comment":"(n) (river) basin"},
	{"question":"流石","answers":["さすが"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) (uk) clever/adept/good/expectations/as one would expect"},
	{"question":"流行","answers":["りゅうこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) fashionable/fad/in vogue/prevailing"},
	{"question":"流行る","answers":["はやる"],"comment":"(v5r) to flourish/to thrive/to be popular/to come into fashion"},
	{"question":"流通","answers":["りゅうつう"],"comment":"(n) circulation of money or goods/flow of water or air/distribution"},
	{"question":"浅い","answers":["あさい"],"comment":"(adj) shallow/superficial"},
	{"question":"浜","answers":["はま"],"comment":"(n) beach/seashore"},
	{"question":"浜辺","answers":["はまべ"],"comment":"(n) beach/foreshore"},
	{"question":"浪費","answers":["ろうひ"],"comment":"(n) waste/extravagance"},
	{"question":"浮かべる","answers":["うかべる"],"comment":"(v1) to float/to express/to look (sad, glad)"},
	{"question":"浮く","answers":["うく"],"comment":"(v5k) to float/to become merry/to become loose"},
	{"question":"浮ぶ","answers":["うかぶ"],"comment":"(io) (v5b) to float/to rise to surface/to come to mind"},
	{"question":"浮力","answers":["ふりょく"],"comment":"(n) buoyancy/floating power"},
	{"question":"浮気","answers":["うわき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) flighty/fickle/wanton/unfaithful"},
	{"question":"浴びる","answers":["あびる"],"comment":"(v1) to bathe/to bask in the sun/to shower"},
	{"question":"浴室","answers":["よくしつ"],"comment":"(n) bathroom/bath"},
	{"question":"浴衣","answers":["ゆかた"],"comment":"(n) bathrobe/informal summer kimono/yukata"},
	{"question":"海","answers":["うみ"],"comment":"(n) sea/beach"},
	{"question":"海外","answers":["かいがい"],"comment":"(n) foreign/abroad/overseas"},
	{"question":"海岸","answers":["かいがん"],"comment":"(n) coast/beach"},
	{"question":"海峡","answers":["かいきょう"],"comment":"(n) channel"},
	{"question":"海抜","answers":["かいばつ"],"comment":"(n) height above sea level"},
	{"question":"海水浴","answers":["かいすいよく"],"comment":"(n) sea bathing/seawater bath"},
	{"question":"海洋","answers":["かいよう"],"comment":"(n) ocean"},
	{"question":"海流","answers":["かいりゅう"],"comment":"(n) ocean current"},
	{"question":"海路","answers":["かいろ"],"comment":"(n-t) sea route"},
	{"question":"海運","answers":["かいうん"],"comment":"(n) maritime/marine transportation"},
	{"question":"浸ける","answers":["つける"],"comment":"(v1) to dip in/to soak"},
	{"question":"浸す","answers":["ひたす"],"comment":"(v5s) to soak/to dip/to drench"},
	{"question":"消える","answers":["きえる"],"comment":"(v1) to go out/to vanish/to disappear"},
	{"question":"消しゴム","answers":["けしゴム"],"comment":"(n) eraser/India rubber"},
	{"question":"消す","answers":["けす"],"comment":"(v5s) to erase/to delete/to turn off power"},
	{"question":"消化","answers":["しょうか"],"comment":"(n,vs) digestion"},
	{"question":"消去","answers":["しょうきょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) elimination/erasing/dying out/melting away"},
	{"question":"消息","answers":["しょうそく"],"comment":"(n) news/letter/circumstances"},
	{"question":"消極的","answers":["しょうきょくてき"],"comment":"(adj-na) passive"},
	{"question":"消毒","answers":["しょうどく"],"comment":"(n,vs) disinfection/sterilization"},
	{"question":"消耗","answers":["しょうもう"],"comment":"(n,vs) exhaustion/consumption"},
	{"question":"消費","answers":["しょうひ"],"comment":"(n,vs) consumption/expenditure"},
	{"question":"消防","answers":["しょうぼう"],"comment":"(n) fire fighting/fire department"},
	{"question":"消防署","answers":["しょうぼうしょ"],"comment":"(n) fire station"},
	{"question":"涙","answers":["なみだ"],"comment":"(n) tear"},
	{"question":"液","answers":["えき"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) liquid/fluid"},
	{"question":"液体","answers":["えきたい"],"comment":"(n) liquid/fluid"},
	{"question":"涼しい","answers":["すずしい"],"comment":"(adj) cool/refreshing"},
	{"question":"涼む","answers":["すずむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to cool oneself/to cool off/to enjoy evening cool"},
	{"question":"淑やか","answers":["しとやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) graceful"},
	{"question":"淡水","answers":["たんすい"],"comment":"(n) fresh water"},
	{"question":"深い","answers":["ふかい"],"comment":"(adj) deep/profound/thick/close"},
	{"question":"深まる","answers":["ふかまる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to deepen/to heighten/to intensify"},
	{"question":"深める","answers":["ふかめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to deepen/to heighten/to intensify"},
	{"question":"深刻","answers":["しんこく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) serious"},
	{"question":"深夜","answers":["しんや"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) late at night"},
	{"question":"混ざる","answers":["まざる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to join"},
	{"question":"混じる","answers":["まじる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be mixed/to be blended with/to associate with/to mingle with/to interest/to join"},
	{"question":"混ぜる","answers":["まぜる"],"comment":"(v1) to mix/to stir"},
	{"question":"混乱","answers":["こんらん"],"comment":"(n,vs) disorder/chaos/confusion/mayhem"},
	{"question":"混合","answers":["こんごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) mixing/mixture"},
	{"question":"混同","answers":["こんどう"],"comment":"(n) confusion/mixing/merger"},
	{"question":"混血","answers":["こんけつ"],"comment":"(n) mixed race/mixed parentage"},
	{"question":"混雑","answers":["こんざつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) confusion/congestion"},
	{"question":"添う","answers":["そう"],"comment":"(v5u) to accompany/to become married/to comply with"},
	{"question":"添える","answers":["そえる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to add to/to attach/to append/to accompany/to garnish/to imitate/to annex"},
	{"question":"清い","answers":["きよい"],"comment":"(adj) clear/pure/noble"},
	{"question":"清らか","answers":["きよらか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) clean/pure/chaste"},
	{"question":"清掃","answers":["せいそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) cleaning"},
	{"question":"清書","answers":["せいしょ"],"comment":"(n) clean copy"},
	{"question":"清潔","answers":["せいけつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) clean"},
	{"question":"清濁","answers":["せいだく"],"comment":"(n) good and evil/purity and impurity"},
	{"question":"清純","answers":["せいじゅん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) purity/innocence"},
	{"question":"渇く","answers":["かわく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be thirsty"},
	{"question":"済ます","answers":["すます"],"comment":"(v5s) (1) to finish/to get it over with/to conclude/(2) to settle/to pay back/(3) to get along (without something)"},
	{"question":"済ませる","answers":["すませる"],"comment":"(v1) to be finished"},
	{"question":"済む","answers":["すむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to finish/to end/to be completed"},
	{"question":"渋滞","answers":["じゅうたい"],"comment":"(n,vs) congestion (e.g. traffic)/delay/stagnation"},
	{"question":"渚","answers":["なぎさ"],"comment":"(n) water's edge/beach/shore"},
	{"question":"減らす","answers":["へらす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to abate/to decrease/to diminish/to shorten"},
	{"question":"減る","answers":["へる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to decrease (in size or number)/to diminish/to abate"},
	{"question":"減少","answers":["げんしょう"],"comment":"(n) decrease/reduction/decline"},
	{"question":"渡す","answers":["わたす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pass over/to hand over"},
	{"question":"渡り鳥","answers":["わたりどり"],"comment":"(n) migratory bird/bird of passage"},
	{"question":"渡る","answers":["わたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to cross over/to go across"},
	{"question":"渦","answers":["うず"],"comment":"(n) swirl"},
	{"question":"温い","answers":["ぬるい"],"comment":"(adj) (uk) lukewarm/tepid"},
	{"question":"温かい","answers":["あたたかい"],"comment":"(adj) warm/mild/genial"},
	{"question":"温まる","answers":["あたたまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to warm oneself/to sun oneself/to warm up/to get warm"},
	{"question":"温める","answers":["あたためる"],"comment":"(v1) to warm/to heat"},
	{"question":"温和","answers":["おんわ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) gentle/mild/moderate"},
	{"question":"温室","answers":["おんしつ"],"comment":"(n) greenhouse"},
	{"question":"温帯","answers":["おんたい"],"comment":"(n) temperate zone"},
	{"question":"温度","answers":["おんど"],"comment":"(n) temperature"},
	{"question":"温暖","answers":["おんだん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) warmth"},
	{"question":"温泉","answers":["おんせん"],"comment":"(n) spa/hot spring/onsen"},
	{"question":"測る","answers":["はかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to measure/to weigh/to survey/to time (sound, gauge, estimate)"},
	{"question":"測定","answers":["そくてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) measurement"},
	{"question":"測量","answers":["そくりょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) measurement/surveying"},
	{"question":"港","answers":["みなと"],"comment":"(n) harbour/port"},
	{"question":"湖","answers":["みずうみ"],"comment":"(n) lake"},
	{"question":"湧く","answers":["わく"],"comment":"(v5k) to boil/to grow hot/to get excited/to gush forth"},
	{"question":"湯","answers":["ゆ"],"comment":"(n) hot water"},
	{"question":"湯気","answers":["ゆげ"],"comment":"(n) steam/vapour"},
	{"question":"湯飲み","answers":["ゆのみ"],"comment":"(n) teacup"},
	{"question":"湾","answers":["わん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) bay/gulf/inlet"},
	{"question":"湿る","answers":["しめる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be wet/to become wet/to be damp"},
	{"question":"湿度","answers":["しつど"],"comment":"(n) level of humidity"},
	{"question":"湿気","answers":["しっき","しっけ"],"comment":"(n) moisture/humidity/dampness"},
	{"question":"湿気る","answers":["しける"],"comment":"(v5r) to be damp/to be moist"},
	{"question":"満たす","answers":["みたす"],"comment":"(v5s) to satisfy/to ingratiate/to fill/to fulfill"},
	{"question":"満ちる","answers":["みちる"],"comment":"(v1) to be full/to rise (tide)/to mature/to expire"},
	{"question":"満員","answers":["まんいん"],"comment":"(n) full house/no vacancy/sold out/standing room only/full (of people)/crowded"},
	{"question":"満場","answers":["まんじょう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) unanimous/whole audience"},
	{"question":"満月","answers":["まんげつ"],"comment":"(n) full moon"},
	{"question":"満点","answers":["まんてん"],"comment":"(n) perfect score"},
	{"question":"満足","answers":["まんぞく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) satisfaction"},
	{"question":"源","answers":["みなもと"],"comment":"(n) source/origin"},
	{"question":"準じる","answers":["じゅんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to follow/to conform/to apply to"},
	{"question":"準備","answers":["じゅんび"],"comment":"(n,vs) preparation/arrangements/provision/reserve"},
	{"question":"準急","answers":["じゅんきゅう"],"comment":"(n) local express (train, slower than an express)"},
	{"question":"溜まり","answers":["たまり"],"comment":"collected things/gathering place/arrears"},
	{"question":"溜まる","answers":["たまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to collect/to gather/to save"},
	{"question":"溜める","answers":["ためる"],"comment":"(v1) to amass/to accumulate"},
	{"question":"溜息","answers":["ためいき"],"comment":"(io) (n) (uk) a sigh"},
	{"question":"溝","answers":["どぶ","みぞ"],"comment":"(n) ditch/drain/gutter/gap"},
	{"question":"溶かす","answers":["とかす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to melt/to dissolve"},
	{"question":"溶く","answers":["とく"],"comment":"(v5k,vt) to dissolve (paint)"},
	{"question":"溶ける","answers":["とける"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to melt/to thaw/to fuse/to dissolve"},
	{"question":"溶け込む","answers":["とけこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to melt into"},
	{"question":"溶岩","answers":["ようがん"],"comment":"(n) lava"},
	{"question":"溶液","answers":["ようえき"],"comment":"(n) solution (liquid)"},
	{"question":"溺れる","answers":["おぼれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be drowned/to indulge in"},
	{"question":"滅びる","answers":["ほろびる"],"comment":"(v1) to be ruined/to go under/to perish/to be destroyed"},
	{"question":"滅ぼす","answers":["ほろぼす"],"comment":"(v5s) to destroy/to overthrow/to wreck/to ruin"},
	{"question":"滅亡","answers":["めつぼう"],"comment":"(n) downfall/ruin/collapse/destruction"},
	{"question":"滅多に","answers":["めったに"],"comment":"(adv) rarely (with neg. verb)/seldom"},
	{"question":"滑らか","answers":["なめらか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) smoothness/glassiness"},
	{"question":"滑る","answers":["すべる"],"comment":"(v5r) to glide/to slide/to slip"},
	{"question":"滑稽","answers":["こっけい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) funny/humorous/comical/laughable/ridiculous/joking"},
	{"question":"滝","answers":["たき"],"comment":"(n) waterfall"},
	{"question":"滞る","answers":["とどこおる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stagnate/to be delayed"},
	{"question":"滞在","answers":["たいざい"],"comment":"(n,vs) stay/sojourn"},
	{"question":"滞納","answers":["たいのう"],"comment":"(n) non-payment/default"},
	{"question":"滲む","answers":["にじむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to run/to blur/to spread/to blot/to ooze"},
	{"question":"漁師","answers":["りょうし"],"comment":"(n) fisherman"},
	{"question":"漁村","answers":["ぎょそん"],"comment":"(n) fishing village"},
	{"question":"漁業","answers":["ぎょぎょう"],"comment":"(n) fishing (industry)"},
	{"question":"漁船","answers":["ぎょせん"],"comment":"(n) fishing boat"},
	{"question":"漂う","answers":["ただよう"],"comment":"(v5u) to drift about/to float/to hang in air"},
	{"question":"漏らす","answers":["もらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to let leak/to reveal"},
	{"question":"漏る","answers":["もる"],"comment":"(v5r) to leak/to run out"},
	{"question":"漏れる","answers":["もれる"],"comment":"(v1) to leak out/to escape/to come through/to shine through/to filter out/to be omitted"},
	{"question":"演じる","answers":["えんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to perform (a play)/to play (a part)/to act (a part)/to commit (a blunder)"},
	{"question":"演ずる","answers":["えんずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to perform/to play"},
	{"question":"演出","answers":["えんしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) production (e.g. play)/direction"},
	{"question":"演劇","answers":["えんげき"],"comment":"(n) play (theatrical)"},
	{"question":"演奏","answers":["えんそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) musical performance"},
	{"question":"演技","answers":["えんぎ"],"comment":"(n) acting/performance"},
	{"question":"演説","answers":["えんぜつ"],"comment":"(n) speech/address"},
	{"question":"漠然","answers":["ばくぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) obscure/vague/equivocal"},
	{"question":"漢和","answers":["かんわ"],"comment":"(n) Chinese Character-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)"},
	{"question":"漢字","answers":["かんじ"],"comment":"(n) Chinese characters/kanji"},
	{"question":"漢語","answers":["かんご"],"comment":"(n) Chinese word/Sino-Japanese word"},
	{"question":"漫画","answers":["まんが"],"comment":"(n) comic/cartoon"},
	{"question":"漬ける","answers":["つける"],"comment":"(v1) to soak/to moisten/to pickle"},
	{"question":"漸く","answers":["ようやく"],"comment":"(adv) gradually/finally/hardly"},
	{"question":"潜る","answers":["もぐる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to drive/to pass through/(2) to evade/to hide/(3) to dive (into or under water)/to go underground"},
	{"question":"潜入","answers":["せんにゅう"],"comment":"(n) infiltration/sneaking in"},
	{"question":"潜水","answers":["せんすい"],"comment":"(n) diving"},
	{"question":"潤う","answers":["うるおう"],"comment":"(v5u) to be moist/to be damp/to get wet/to profit by/to be watered/to receive benefits/to favor/to charm/to steepen"},
	{"question":"潮","answers":["しお"],"comment":"(n) tide/ebb and flood/salt water/opportunity"},
	{"question":"潰す","answers":["つぶす"],"comment":"(v5s) to smash/to waste"},
	{"question":"潰れる","answers":["つぶれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be smashed/to go bankrupt"},
	{"question":"澄ます","answers":["すます"],"comment":"(v5s) to clear/to make clear/to be unruffled/to look unconcerned/to look demure/look prim/put on airs"},
	{"question":"澄む","answers":["すむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to clear (e.g. weather)/to become transparent"},
	{"question":"激しい","answers":["はげしい"],"comment":"(adj) violent/vehement/intense/furious/tempestuous"},
	{"question":"激励","answers":["げきれい"],"comment":"(n,vs) encouragement"},
	{"question":"激増","answers":["げきぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) sudden increase"},
	{"question":"濁る","answers":["にごる"],"comment":"(v5r) to become muddy/to get impure"},
	{"question":"濃い","answers":["こい"],"comment":"(adj) thick (as of color, liquid)/dense/strong"},
	{"question":"濃度","answers":["のうど"],"comment":"(n) concentration/brightness"},
	{"question":"濠","answers":["ほり"],"comment":"(n) moat"},
	{"question":"濡らす","answers":["ぬらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to wet/to soak/to dip"},
	{"question":"濡れる","answers":["ぬれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get wet"},
	{"question":"濫用","answers":["らんよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) abuse/misuse/misappropriation/using to excess"},
	{"question":"濯ぐ","answers":["すすぐ","ゆすぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to rinse/to wash out"},
	{"question":"瀬戸物","answers":["せともの"],"comment":"(n) earthenware/crockery/china"},
	{"question":"灌漑","answers":["かんがい"],"comment":"(n) irrigation"},
	{"question":"火","answers":["ひ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) fire/flame/blaze"},
	{"question":"火事","answers":["かじ"],"comment":"(n) fire/conflagration"},
	{"question":"火傷","answers":["やけど"],"comment":"(n) burn/scald"},
	{"question":"火口","answers":["かこう"],"comment":"(n) a burner/origin of a fire"},
	{"question":"火山","answers":["かざん"],"comment":"(n) volcano"},
	{"question":"火星","answers":["かせい"],"comment":"(n) Mars (planet)"},
	{"question":"火曜","answers":["かよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) (abbr) Tuesday"},
	{"question":"火曜日","answers":["かようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Tuesday"},
	{"question":"火災","answers":["かさい"],"comment":"(n) conflagration/fire"},
	{"question":"火花","answers":["ひばな"],"comment":"(n) spark"},
	{"question":"灯","answers":["ひ"],"comment":"(n) light"},
	{"question":"灯台","answers":["とうだい"],"comment":"(n) lighthouse"},
	{"question":"灯油","answers":["とうゆ"],"comment":"(n) lamp oil/kerosene"},
	{"question":"灰","answers":["はい"],"comment":"(n) ash"},
	{"question":"灰皿","answers":["はいざら"],"comment":"(n) ashtray"},
	{"question":"灰色","answers":["はいいろ"],"comment":"(n) grey/gray/ashen"},
	{"question":"災害","answers":["さいがい"],"comment":"(n) calamity/disaster/misfortune"},
	{"question":"災難","answers":["さいなん"],"comment":"(n) calamity/misfortune"},
	{"question":"炊く","answers":["たく"],"comment":"(v5k) to boil/to cook"},
	{"question":"炊事","answers":["すいじ"],"comment":"(n) cooking/culinary arts"},
	{"question":"炎","answers":["ほのお"],"comment":"(n) flame"},
	{"question":"炒める","answers":["いためる"],"comment":"(v1) to stir-fry"},
	{"question":"炭素","answers":["たんそ"],"comment":"(n) carbon (C)"},
	{"question":"炭鉱","answers":["たんこう"],"comment":"(n) coal mine/coal pit"},
	{"question":"点","answers":["てん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) spot/mark/point/dot"},
	{"question":"点々","answers":["てんてん"],"comment":"(adv,n) here and there/little by little/sporadically/scattered in drops/dot/spot"},
	{"question":"点く","answers":["つく"],"comment":"(v5k) to catch fire/(electricity) comes on"},
	{"question":"点ける","answers":["つける"],"comment":"(v1) (uk) to turn on/to switch on/to light up"},
	{"question":"点数","answers":["てんすう"],"comment":"(n) marks/points/score/runs/number of items/credits"},
	{"question":"点検","answers":["てんけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) inspection/examination/checking"},
	{"question":"点線","answers":["てんせん"],"comment":"(n) dotted line/perforated line"},
	{"question":"為","answers":["ため"],"comment":"(n) good/advantage/benefit/welfare/sake/to/in order to/because of/as a result of"},
	{"question":"為す","answers":["なす"],"comment":"(v5s) to accomplish/to do"},
	{"question":"為る","answers":["する","なる"],"comment":"(v5r) to change/to be of use/to reach to"},
	{"question":"為替","answers":["かわせ"],"comment":"(n) money order/exchange"},
	{"question":"焚く","answers":["たく"],"comment":"(v5k) to burn/to kindle/to build a fire"},
	{"question":"焚火","answers":["たきび"],"comment":"(n) (open) fire"},
	{"question":"無","answers":["ぶ","む"],"comment":"(n) nothing/naught/nil/zero"},
	{"question":"無い","answers":["ない"],"comment":"(adj) there isn't/doesn't have"},
	{"question":"無くす","answers":["なくす"],"comment":"(v5s) to lose something/to get rid of"},
	{"question":"無くなる","answers":["なくなる"],"comment":"(v5r) to disappear/to get lost"},
	{"question":"無し","answers":["なし"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) without"},
	{"question":"無事","answers":["ぶじ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) safety/peace/quietness"},
	{"question":"無効","answers":["むこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) invalid/no effect/unavailable"},
	{"question":"無口","answers":["むくち"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) reticence"},
	{"question":"無地","answers":["むじ"],"comment":"(n) plain/unfigured"},
	{"question":"無念","answers":["むねん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) chagrin/regret"},
	{"question":"無意味","answers":["むいみ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) nonsense/no meaning"},
	{"question":"無数","answers":["むすう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) countless number/infinite number"},
	{"question":"無料","answers":["むりょう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) free/no charge"},
	{"question":"無断","answers":["むだん"],"comment":"(n) without permission/without notice"},
	{"question":"無沙汰","answers":["ぶさた"],"comment":"(n) neglecting to stay in contact"},
	{"question":"無理","answers":["むり"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) unreasonable/impossible/overdoing"},
	{"question":"無用","answers":["むよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) useless/futility/needlessness/unnecessariness"},
	{"question":"無知","answers":["むち"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) ignorance"},
	{"question":"無礼","answers":["ぶれい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) impolite/rude"},
	{"question":"無線","answers":["むせん"],"comment":"(n) wireless/radio"},
	{"question":"無能","answers":["むのう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) inefficiency/incompetence"},
	{"question":"無茶","answers":["むちゃ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) absurd/unreasonable/excessive/rash/absurdity/nonsense"},
	{"question":"無茶苦茶","answers":["むちゃくちゃ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (uk) confused/jumbled/mixed up/unreasonable"},
	{"question":"無視","answers":["むし"],"comment":"(n,vs) disregard/ignore"},
	{"question":"無言","answers":["むごん"],"comment":"(n) silence"},
	{"question":"無論","answers":["むろん"],"comment":"(adv) of course/naturally"},
	{"question":"無邪気","answers":["むじゃき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) innocence/simple-mindedness"},
	{"question":"無闇に","answers":["むやみに"],"comment":"(uk) unreasonably/absurdly/recklessly/indiscreetly/at random"},
	{"question":"無限","answers":["むげん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) infinite"},
	{"question":"無難","answers":["ぶなん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) safety/security"},
	{"question":"無駄","answers":["むだ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) futility/uselessness"},
	{"question":"無駄遣い","answers":["むだづかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) waste money on/squander money on/flog a dead horse"},
	{"question":"焦がす","answers":["こがす"],"comment":"(v5s) to burn/to scorch/to singe/to char"},
	{"question":"焦げる","answers":["こげる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to burn/to be burned"},
	{"question":"焦げ茶","answers":["こげちゃ"],"comment":"(n) black tea"},
	{"question":"焦る","answers":["あせる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be in a hurry/to be impatient"},
	{"question":"焦点","answers":["しょうてん"],"comment":"(n) focus/point"},
	{"question":"焼く","answers":["やく"],"comment":"(v5k) to bake/to grill"},
	{"question":"焼ける","answers":["やける"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to burn/to be roasted/to be sunburnt"},
	{"question":"煉瓦","answers":["れんが"],"comment":"(n) brick"},
	{"question":"煌々と","answers":["こうこうと"],"comment":"brilliantly/brightly"},
	{"question":"煎る","answers":["いる"],"comment":"(v5r) to parch/to fry/to fire/to broil/to roast/to boil down (in oil)"},
	{"question":"煙","answers":["けむり"],"comment":"(n) smoke/fumes"},
	{"question":"煙い","answers":["けむい"],"comment":"(adj) smoky"},
	{"question":"煙たい","answers":["けむたい"],"comment":"(adj) smoky/feeling awkward"},
	{"question":"煙る","answers":["けむる"],"comment":"(v5r) to smoke (e.g. fire)"},
	{"question":"煙突","answers":["えんとつ"],"comment":"(n) chimney"},
	{"question":"照らす","answers":["てらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to shine on/to illuminate"},
	{"question":"照り返す","answers":["てりかえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to reflect/to throw back light"},
	{"question":"照る","answers":["てる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to shine"},
	{"question":"照合","answers":["しょうごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) collation/comparison"},
	{"question":"照明","answers":["しょうめい"],"comment":"(n) illumination"},
	{"question":"煩わしい","answers":["わずらわしい"],"comment":"(adj) troublesome/annoying/complicated"},
	{"question":"煮える","answers":["にえる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to boil/to cook/to be cooked"},
	{"question":"煮る","answers":["にる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to boil/to cook"},
	{"question":"熟語","answers":["じゅくご"],"comment":"(n) idiom/idiomatic phrase/kanji compound"},
	{"question":"熱","answers":["ねつ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) fever/temperature"},
	{"question":"熱い","answers":["あつい"],"comment":"(adj) hot (thing)"},
	{"question":"熱する","answers":["ねっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to heat"},
	{"question":"熱中","answers":["ねっちゅう"],"comment":"(n) nuts!/enthusiasm/zeal/mania"},
	{"question":"熱帯","answers":["ねったい"],"comment":"(n) tropics"},
	{"question":"熱心","answers":["ねっしん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) zeal/enthusiasm"},
	{"question":"熱意","answers":["ねつい"],"comment":"(n) zeal/enthusiasm"},
	{"question":"熱湯","answers":["ねっとう"],"comment":"(n) boiling water"},
	{"question":"熱量","answers":["ねつりょう"],"comment":"(n) temperature"},
	{"question":"燃える","answers":["もえる"],"comment":"(v1) to burn"},
	{"question":"燃やす","answers":["もやす"],"comment":"(v5s) to burn"},
	{"question":"燃料","answers":["ねんりょう"],"comment":"(n) fuel"},
	{"question":"燃焼","answers":["ねんしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) burning/combustion"},
	{"question":"爆弾","answers":["ばくだん"],"comment":"(n) bomb"},
	{"question":"爆発","answers":["ばくはつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) explosion/detonation/eruption"},
	{"question":"爆破","answers":["ばくは"],"comment":"(n,vs) blast/explosion/blow up"},
	{"question":"爪","answers":["つめ"],"comment":"(n) fingernail or toenail/claw/talon/hoof"},
	{"question":"父","answers":["ちち"],"comment":"(n) (hum) father"},
	{"question":"父母","answers":["ふぼ"],"comment":"(n) father and mother/parents"},
	{"question":"父親","answers":["ちちおや"],"comment":"(n) father"},
	{"question":"片付く","answers":["かたづく"],"comment":"(v5k) to put in order/to dispose of/to solve/to finish/to get married"},
	{"question":"片付け","answers":["かたづけ"],"comment":"(n) tidying up/finishing"},
	{"question":"片付ける","answers":["かたづける"],"comment":"(v1) to tidy up/to put in order/to straighten up/to put away"},
	{"question":"片仮名","answers":["かたかな"],"comment":"(n) katakana"},
	{"question":"片寄る","answers":["かたよる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be one-sided/to incline/to be partial/to be prejudiced/to lean/to be biased"},
	{"question":"片言","answers":["かたこと"],"comment":"(n) brief remark/few words"},
	{"question":"片道","answers":["かたみち"],"comment":"(n) one-way (trip)"},
	{"question":"版","answers":["はん"],"comment":"(n) edition"},
	{"question":"版画","answers":["はんが"],"comment":"(n) art print"},
	{"question":"牛","answers":["うし"],"comment":"(n) cattle/cow"},
	{"question":"牛乳","answers":["ぎゅうにゅう"],"comment":"(n) (cow's) milk"},
	{"question":"牛肉","answers":["ぎゅうにく"],"comment":"(n) beef"},
	{"question":"牧場","answers":["ぼくじょう"],"comment":"(n) (1) farm (livestock)/(2) pasture land/meadow/grazing land"},
	{"question":"牧師","answers":["ぼくし"],"comment":"(n) pastor/minister/clergyman"},
	{"question":"牧畜","answers":["ぼくちく"],"comment":"(n) stock-farming"},
	{"question":"物","answers":["もの"],"comment":"(n) thing/object"},
	{"question":"物事","answers":["ものごと"],"comment":"(n) things/everything"},
	{"question":"物体","answers":["ぶったい"],"comment":"(n) (1) superior airs/air of importance/(2) overemphasis"},
	{"question":"物価","answers":["ぶっか"],"comment":"(n) prices of commodities/prices (in general)"},
	{"question":"物凄い","answers":["ものすごい"],"comment":"(adj) earth-shattering/staggering/to a very great extent"},
	{"question":"物好き","answers":["ものずき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (idle) curiosity"},
	{"question":"物差し","answers":["ものさし"],"comment":"(n) ruler/measure"},
	{"question":"物理","answers":["ぶつり"],"comment":"(n) physics"},
	{"question":"物置","answers":["ものおき"],"comment":"(n) storage room"},
	{"question":"物語","answers":["ものがたり"],"comment":"(n) tale/story/legend"},
	{"question":"物語る","answers":["ものがたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to tell/to indicate"},
	{"question":"物議","answers":["ぶつぎ"],"comment":"(n) public discussion (criticism)"},
	{"question":"物資","answers":["ぶっし"],"comment":"(n) goods/materials"},
	{"question":"物質","answers":["ぶっしつ"],"comment":"(n) material/substance"},
	{"question":"物足りない","answers":["ものたりない"],"comment":"(adj) unsatisfied/unsatisfactory"},
	{"question":"物音","answers":["ものおと"],"comment":"(n) sounds"},
	{"question":"物騒","answers":["ぶっそう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) dangerous/disturbed/insecure"},
	{"question":"特に","answers":["とくに"],"comment":"(adv) particularly/especially"},
	{"question":"特別","answers":["とくべつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) special"},
	{"question":"特売","answers":["とくばい"],"comment":"(n,vs) special sale"},
	{"question":"特定","answers":["とくてい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) specific/special/particular"},
	{"question":"特徴","answers":["とくちょう"],"comment":"(n) feature/characteristic"},
	{"question":"特急","answers":["とっきゅう"],"comment":"(n) limited express (train, faster than an express)"},
	{"question":"特技","answers":["とくぎ"],"comment":"(n) special skill"},
	{"question":"特有","answers":["とくゆう"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) characteristic (of)/peculiar (to)"},
	{"question":"特権","answers":["とっけん"],"comment":"(n) privilege/special right"},
	{"question":"特殊","answers":["とくしゅ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) special/unique"},
	{"question":"特派","answers":["とくは"],"comment":"(n,vs) send specially/special envoy"},
	{"question":"特産","answers":["とくさん"],"comment":"(n) specialty/special product"},
	{"question":"特色","answers":["とくしょく"],"comment":"(n) characteristic/feature"},
	{"question":"特許","answers":["とっきょ"],"comment":"(n) special permission/patent"},
	{"question":"特長","answers":["とくちょう"],"comment":"(n) forte/merit"},
	{"question":"特集","answers":["とくしゅう"],"comment":"(n) feature (e.g. newspaper)/special edition/report"},
	{"question":"犠牲","answers":["ぎせい"],"comment":"(n) sacrifice"},
	{"question":"犬","answers":["いぬ"],"comment":"(n) dog"},
	{"question":"犯す","answers":["おかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to commit/to perpetrate/to violate/to rape"},
	{"question":"犯人","answers":["はんにん"],"comment":"(n) offender/criminal"},
	{"question":"犯罪","answers":["はんざい"],"comment":"(n) crime"},
	{"question":"状態","answers":["じょうたい"],"comment":"(n) condition/situation/circumstances/state"},
	{"question":"状況","answers":["じょうきょう"],"comment":"(n) state of affairs/situation/circumstances"},
	{"question":"狂う","answers":["くるう"],"comment":"(v5u) to go mad/to get out of order"},
	{"question":"狙い","answers":["ねらい"],"comment":"(n) aim"},
	{"question":"狙う","answers":["ねらう"],"comment":"(v5u) to aim at"},
	{"question":"狡い","answers":["ずるい"],"comment":"(adj) (uk) sly/cunning"},
	{"question":"狩り","answers":["かり"],"comment":"(n) hunting"},
	{"question":"独り","answers":["ひとり"],"comment":"(adv,n) alone/unmarried"},
	{"question":"独り言","answers":["ひとりごと"],"comment":"(n) a soliloquy/a monologue/speaking to oneself"},
	{"question":"独創","answers":["どくそう"],"comment":"(n) originality"},
	{"question":"独占","answers":["どくせん"],"comment":"(n) monopoly"},
	{"question":"独特","answers":["どくとく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) peculiarity/uniqueness/characteristic"},
	{"question":"独立","answers":["どくりつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) independence (e.g. Ind. Day)/self-support"},
	{"question":"独自","answers":["どくじ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) original/peculiar/characteristic"},
	{"question":"独裁","answers":["どくさい"],"comment":"(n) dictatorship/despotism"},
	{"question":"独身","answers":["どくしん"],"comment":"(n) bachelorhood/single/unmarried/celibate"},
	{"question":"狭い","answers":["せまい"],"comment":"(adj) narrow/confined/small"},
	{"question":"猛烈","answers":["もうれつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) violent/vehement/rage"},
	{"question":"猫","answers":["ねこ"],"comment":"(n) cat"},
	{"question":"献立","answers":["こんだて"],"comment":"(n) menu/program/schedule"},
	{"question":"猿","answers":["さる"],"comment":"(n) monkey"},
	{"question":"獣","answers":["けだもの","けもの"],"comment":"(n) beast/brute"},
	{"question":"獲得","answers":["かくとく"],"comment":"(n,vs) acquisition/possession"},
	{"question":"獲物","answers":["えもの"],"comment":"(n) game/spoils/trophy"},
	{"question":"玄人","answers":["くろうと"],"comment":"(n) expert/professional/geisha/prostitute"},
	{"question":"玄関","answers":["げんかん"],"comment":"(n) entranceway/entry hall"},
	{"question":"率","answers":["りつ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) rate/ratio/proportion/percentage"},
	{"question":"率いる","answers":["ひきいる"],"comment":"(v1) to lead/to spearhead (a group)/to command (troops)"},
	{"question":"玉","answers":["たま"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) ball/sphere/coin"},
	{"question":"王","answers":["おう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) (1) king/ruler/sovereign/monarch/(2) king (for senior player) (shogi)"},
	{"question":"王女","answers":["おうじょ"],"comment":"(n) princess"},
	{"question":"王子","answers":["おうじ"],"comment":"(n) prince"},
	{"question":"王様","answers":["おうさま"],"comment":"(n) king"},
	{"question":"玩具","answers":["がんぐ"],"comment":"(n) (uk) toy"},
	{"question":"珍しい","answers":["めずらしい"],"comment":"(adj) unusual/rare"},
	{"question":"班","answers":["はん"],"comment":"(n,suf) group/party/section (mil)"},
	{"question":"現す","answers":["あらわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to show/to indicate/to display"},
	{"question":"現に","answers":["げんに"],"comment":"(adv) actually/really"},
	{"question":"現れ","answers":["あらわれ"],"comment":"(n) embodiment/materialization"},
	{"question":"現れる","answers":["あらわれる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to appear/to come in sight/to become visible/to come out/to embody/to materialize/(2) to express oneself"},
	{"question":"現代","answers":["げんだい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n) nowadays/modern times/present-day"},
	{"question":"現像","answers":["げんぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) developing (film)"},
	{"question":"現在","answers":["げんざい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) present/up to now/nowadays/modern times/current"},
	{"question":"現地","answers":["げんち"],"comment":"(n) actual place/local"},
	{"question":"現場","answers":["げんば"],"comment":"(n) actual spot/scene/scene of the crime"},
	{"question":"現実","answers":["げんじつ"],"comment":"(n) reality"},
	{"question":"現状","answers":["げんじょう"],"comment":"(n) present condition/existing state/status quo"},
	{"question":"現行","answers":["げんこう"],"comment":"(n) present/current/in operation"},
	{"question":"現象","answers":["げんしょう"],"comment":"(n) phenomenon"},
	{"question":"現金","answers":["げんきん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cash/ready money/mercenary/self-interested"},
	{"question":"球","answers":["きゅう","たま"],"comment":"(n) globe/sphere/ball"},
	{"question":"球根","answers":["きゅうこん"],"comment":"(n) (plant) bulb"},
	{"question":"理屈","answers":["りくつ"],"comment":"(n) theory/reason"},
	{"question":"理性","answers":["りせい"],"comment":"(n) reason/sense"},
	{"question":"理想","answers":["りそう"],"comment":"(n) ideal"},
	{"question":"理由","answers":["りゆう"],"comment":"(n) reason/pretext/motive"},
	{"question":"理科","answers":["りか"],"comment":"(n) science"},
	{"question":"理解","answers":["りかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) understanding/comprehension"},
	{"question":"理論","answers":["りろん"],"comment":"(n) theory"},
	{"question":"琴","answers":["こと"],"comment":"(n) Koto (Japanese harp)"},
	{"question":"環境","answers":["かんきょう"],"comment":"(n) environment/circumstance"},
	{"question":"瓦","answers":["かわら"],"comment":"(n) roof tile"},
	{"question":"瓶","answers":["びん"],"comment":"(n) bottle"},
	{"question":"瓶詰","answers":["びんづめ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) bottling/bottled"},
	{"question":"甘い","answers":["あまい"],"comment":"(adj) delicious"},
	{"question":"甘える","answers":["あまえる"],"comment":"(v1) to behave like a spoiled child/to fawn on"},
	{"question":"甘やかす","answers":["あまやかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pamper/to spoil"},
	{"question":"甘口","answers":["あまくち"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) sweet flavour/mildness/flattery/stupidity"},
	{"question":"甚だ","answers":["はなはだ"],"comment":"(adv) very/greatly/exceedingly"},
	{"question":"甚だしい","answers":["はなはだしい"],"comment":"(adj) extreme/excessive/terrible/intense/severe/serious/tremendous/heavy (damage)"},
	{"question":"生","answers":["せい","なま"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) (1) draft (beer)/(2) raw/unprocessed"},
	{"question":"生える","answers":["はえる"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to grow/to spring up/(2) to cut (teeth)"},
	{"question":"生かす","answers":["いかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to revive/to resuscitate/to make use of"},
	{"question":"生きる","answers":["いきる"],"comment":"(v1) to live/to exist"},
	{"question":"生き物","answers":["いきもの"],"comment":"(n) living thing/animal"},
	{"question":"生き生き","answers":["いきいき"],"comment":"(adv,n) vividly/lively"},
	{"question":"生き甲斐","answers":["いきがい"],"comment":"(n) something one lives for, very important"},
	{"question":"生け花","answers":["いけばな"],"comment":"(n) (1) flower arrangement"},
	{"question":"生じる","answers":["しょうじる"],"comment":"(v1) to produce/to yield/to result from/to arise/to be generated"},
	{"question":"生ずる","answers":["しょうずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to cause/to arise/to be generated"},
	{"question":"生まれ","answers":["うまれ"],"comment":"(n) birth/birth-place"},
	{"question":"生まれる","answers":["うまれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be born"},
	{"question":"生やす","answers":["はやす"],"comment":"(v5s) to grow/to cultivate/to wear beard"},
	{"question":"生る","answers":["なる"],"comment":"(v5r) to bear fruit"},
	{"question":"生命","answers":["せいめい"],"comment":"(n) life/existence"},
	{"question":"生地","answers":["きじ"],"comment":"(n) birthplace"},
	{"question":"生存","answers":["せいぞん"],"comment":"(n) existence/being/survival"},
	{"question":"生年月日","answers":["せいねんがっぴ"],"comment":"(n) birth date"},
	{"question":"生徒","answers":["せいと"],"comment":"(n) pupil"},
	{"question":"生意気","answers":["なまいき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) impertinent/saucy/cheeky/conceit/audacious/brazen"},
	{"question":"生死","answers":["せいし"],"comment":"(n) life and death"},
	{"question":"生活","answers":["せいかつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) living/life (one's daily existence)/livelihood"},
	{"question":"生涯","answers":["しょうがい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) one's lifetime (i.e., one's existance until death)"},
	{"question":"生温い","answers":["なまぬるい"],"comment":"(adj) lukewarm/halfhearted"},
	{"question":"生物","answers":["せいぶつ"],"comment":"(n) raw food"},
	{"question":"生理","answers":["せいり"],"comment":"(n) physiology/menses"},
	{"question":"生産","answers":["せいさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) production/manufacture"},
	{"question":"生真面目","answers":["きまじめ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) too serious/person who is too serious/honesty/sincerity"},
	{"question":"生育","answers":["せいいく"],"comment":"(n) growth/development/breeding"},
	{"question":"生臭い","answers":["なまぐさい"],"comment":"(adj) smelling of fish or blood/fish or meat"},
	{"question":"生計","answers":["せいけい"],"comment":"(n) livelihood/living"},
	{"question":"生身","answers":["なまみ"],"comment":"(n) living flesh/flesh and blood/the quick"},
	{"question":"生長","answers":["せいちょう"],"comment":"(n) growth/increment"},
	{"question":"産む","answers":["うむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to give birth/to deliver/to produce"},
	{"question":"産休","answers":["さんきゅう"],"comment":"(n) maternity leave"},
	{"question":"産出","answers":["さんしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) yield/produce"},
	{"question":"産地","answers":["さんち"],"comment":"(n) producing area"},
	{"question":"産婦人科","answers":["さんふじんか"],"comment":"(n) maternity and gynecology department"},
	{"question":"産後","answers":["さんご"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) postpartum/after childbirth"},
	{"question":"産業","answers":["さんぎょう"],"comment":"(n) industry"},
	{"question":"産物","answers":["さんぶつ"],"comment":"(n) product/result/fruit"},
	{"question":"用","answers":["よう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) task/business/use"},
	{"question":"用いる","answers":["もちいる"],"comment":"(v1) to use/to make use of"},
	{"question":"用事","answers":["ようじ"],"comment":"(n) tasks/things to do"},
	{"question":"用件","answers":["ようけん"],"comment":"(n) business"},
	{"question":"用品","answers":["ようひん"],"comment":"(n) articles/supplies/parts"},
	{"question":"用心","answers":["ようじん"],"comment":"(n,vs) care/precaution/guarding/caution"},
	{"question":"用意","answers":["ようい"],"comment":"(n,vs) preparation"},
	{"question":"用法","answers":["ようほう"],"comment":"(n) directions/rules of use"},
	{"question":"用紙","answers":["ようし"],"comment":"(n) blank form"},
	{"question":"用語","answers":["ようご"],"comment":"(n) term/terminology"},
	{"question":"用途","answers":["ようと"],"comment":"(n) use/usefulness"},
	{"question":"田","answers":["た"],"comment":"(n) rice field"},
	{"question":"田ぼ","answers":["たんぼ"],"comment":"(n) paddy field/farm"},
	{"question":"田園","answers":["でんえん"],"comment":"(n) country/rural districts"},
	{"question":"田植え","answers":["たうえ"],"comment":"(n) rice planting"},
	{"question":"田舎","answers":["いなか"],"comment":"(gikun) (n) rural/not particularly urban/countryside/suburb"},
	{"question":"甲","answers":["こう"],"comment":"(n) 1st in rank/first sign of the Chinese calendar/shell/instep/grade A"},
	{"question":"申し上げる","answers":["もうしあげる"],"comment":"(v1) to say/to tell/to state"},
	{"question":"申し入れる","answers":["もうしいれる"],"comment":"(v1) to propose/to suggest"},
	{"question":"申し出る","answers":["もうしでる"],"comment":"(v1) to report to/to tell/to suggest/to submit/to request/to make an offer/to come forward with information"},
	{"question":"申し分","answers":["もうしぶん"],"comment":"(n,vs) objection/shortcomings"},
	{"question":"申し訳","answers":["もうしわけ"],"comment":"(n) apology/excuse"},
	{"question":"申し訳ない","answers":["もうしわけない"],"comment":"(adj-na) inexcusable"},
	{"question":"申し込む","answers":["もうしこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to apply for/to make an application/to propose (marriage)/to offer (mediation)/to make an overture (of peace)/to challenge/to lodge (objections)/to request (an interview)/to subscribe for/to book/to reserve"},
	{"question":"申す","answers":["もうす"],"comment":"(v5s) (hum) to be called/to say"},
	{"question":"申出","answers":["もうしで"],"comment":"(n) proposal/request/claim/report/notice"},
	{"question":"申告","answers":["しんこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) report/statement/filing a return/notification"},
	{"question":"申請","answers":["しんせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) application/request/petition"},
	{"question":"申込","answers":["もうしこみ"],"comment":"(n) application/entry/request/subscription/offer/proposal/overture/challenge"},
	{"question":"男","answers":["おとこ"],"comment":"(n) man"},
	{"question":"男の人","answers":["おとこのひと"],"comment":"man"},
	{"question":"男の子","answers":["おとこのこ"],"comment":"(n) boy"},
	{"question":"男子","answers":["だんし"],"comment":"(n) youth/young man"},
	{"question":"男性","answers":["だんせい"],"comment":"(n) male/man"},
	{"question":"町","answers":["まち"],"comment":"(n) (1) town/(2) street/road"},
	{"question":"画家","answers":["がか"],"comment":"(n) painter/artist"},
	{"question":"画期","answers":["かっき"],"comment":"(n) epoch-making"},
	{"question":"畑","answers":["はたけ"],"comment":"(n) field"},
	{"question":"留まる","answers":["とどまる","とまる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to be fixed/(2) to abide/to stay (in the one place)"},
	{"question":"留める","answers":["とめる"],"comment":"(v1) to fasten/to turn off/to detain"},
	{"question":"留学","answers":["りゅうがく"],"comment":"(n) studying abroad"},
	{"question":"留学生","answers":["りゅうがくせい"],"comment":"(n) overseas student"},
	{"question":"留守","answers":["るす"],"comment":"(n) absence/being away from home"},
	{"question":"留守番","answers":["るすばん"],"comment":"(n,vs) care-taking/caretaker/house-watching"},
	{"question":"畜生","answers":["ちくしょう"],"comment":"(int,n) beast/brute/damn"},
	{"question":"畜産","answers":["ちくさん"],"comment":"(n) animal husbandry"},
	{"question":"略す","answers":["りゃくす"],"comment":"(v5s) to abbreviate"},
	{"question":"略奪","answers":["りゃくだつ"],"comment":"(n) pillage/plunder/looting/robbery"},
	{"question":"略語","answers":["りゃくご"],"comment":"(n) abbreviation/acronym"},
	{"question":"番号","answers":["ばんごう"],"comment":"(n) number/series of digits"},
	{"question":"番地","answers":["ばんち"],"comment":"(n) house number/address"},
	{"question":"番組","answers":["ばんぐみ"],"comment":"(n) program (e.g. TV)"},
	{"question":"異なる","answers":["ことなる"],"comment":"(v5r) to differ/to vary/to disagree"},
	{"question":"異動","answers":["いどう"],"comment":"(n) a change"},
	{"question":"異常","answers":["いじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) strangeness/abnormality/disorder"},
	{"question":"異性","answers":["いせい"],"comment":"(n) the opposite sex"},
	{"question":"異見","answers":["いけん"],"comment":"(n) different opinion/objection"},
	{"question":"異論","answers":["いろん"],"comment":"(n) different opinion/objection"},
	{"question":"異議","answers":["いぎ"],"comment":"(n) objection/dissent/protest"},
	{"question":"畳","answers":["たたみ"],"comment":"(n) tatami mat (Japanese straw floor coverings)"},
	{"question":"畳む","answers":["たたむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to fold (clothes)"},
	{"question":"疑う","answers":["うたがう"],"comment":"(v5u) to doubt/to distrust/to be suspicious of/to suspect"},
	{"question":"疑問","answers":["ぎもん"],"comment":"(n) question/problem/doubt/guess"},
	{"question":"疑惑","answers":["ぎわく"],"comment":"(n) doubt/misgivings/distrust/suspicion"},
	{"question":"疲れ","answers":["つかれ"],"comment":"(n) tiredness/fatigue"},
	{"question":"疲れる","answers":["つかれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get tired/to tire"},
	{"question":"疲労","answers":["ひろう"],"comment":"(n,vs) fatigue/weariness"},
	{"question":"病む","answers":["やむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to fall ill/to be ill"},
	{"question":"病気","answers":["びょうき"],"comment":"(n) illness/disease/sickness"},
	{"question":"病院","answers":["びょういん"],"comment":"(n) hospital"},
	{"question":"症状","answers":["しょうじょう"],"comment":"(n) symptoms/condition"},
	{"question":"痛い","answers":["いたい"],"comment":"(adj) painful"},
	{"question":"痛み","answers":["いたみ"],"comment":"(n) pain/ache/sore/grief/distress"},
	{"question":"痛切","answers":["つうせつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) keen/acute"},
	{"question":"痛感","answers":["つうかん"],"comment":"(n,vs) feeling keenly/fully realizing"},
	{"question":"痩せる","answers":["やせる"],"comment":"(io) (v1) to become thin/to lose weight/to reduce (one's) weight/to slim"},
	{"question":"癌","answers":["がん"],"comment":"(n) cancer"},
	{"question":"癖","answers":["くせ"],"comment":"(n) a habit (often a bad habit, i.e. vice)/peculiarity"},
	{"question":"発つ","answers":["たつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to depart (on a plane, train, etc.)"},
	{"question":"発作","answers":["ほっさ"],"comment":"(n) fit/spasm"},
	{"question":"発売","answers":["はつばい"],"comment":"(n,vs) sale"},
	{"question":"発射","answers":["はっしゃ"],"comment":"(n,vs) firing/shooting/discharge/catapult"},
	{"question":"発展","answers":["はってん"],"comment":"(n,vs) development/growth"},
	{"question":"発想","answers":["はっそう"],"comment":"(n) expression (music)/conceptualization"},
	{"question":"発掘","answers":["はっくつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) excavation/exhumation/(2) discovery (e.g. new talent)"},
	{"question":"発揮","answers":["はっき"],"comment":"(n,vs) exhibition/demonstration/utilization/display"},
	{"question":"発明","answers":["はつめい"],"comment":"(n,vs) invention"},
	{"question":"発生","answers":["はっせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) outbreak/spring forth/occurrence/incidence/origin"},
	{"question":"発病","answers":["はつびょう"],"comment":"(n) attack (disease)"},
	{"question":"発育","answers":["はついく"],"comment":"(n) (physical) growth/development"},
	{"question":"発芽","answers":["はつが"],"comment":"(n,vs) burgeoning"},
	{"question":"発行","answers":["はっこう"],"comment":"(n) issue (publications)"},
	{"question":"発表","answers":["はっぴょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) announcement/publication"},
	{"question":"発見","answers":["はっけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) discovery/detection/finding"},
	{"question":"発言","answers":["はつげん"],"comment":"(n) utterance/speech/proposal"},
	{"question":"発足","answers":["ほっそく"],"comment":"(n) starting/inauguration"},
	{"question":"発車","answers":["はっしゃ"],"comment":"(n) departure of a vehicle"},
	{"question":"発達","answers":["はったつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) development/growth"},
	{"question":"発電","answers":["はつでん"],"comment":"(n,vs) generation (e.g. power)"},
	{"question":"発音","answers":["はつおん"],"comment":"(n,vs) pronunciation"},
	{"question":"登る","answers":["のぼる"],"comment":"(v5r) to climb"},
	{"question":"登場","answers":["とうじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) entry (on stage)"},
	{"question":"登山","answers":["とざん"],"comment":"(n,vs) mountain-climbing"},
	{"question":"登校","answers":["とうこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) attendance (at school)"},
	{"question":"登録","answers":["とうろく"],"comment":"(n,vs) registration/register/entry/record"},
	{"question":"白","answers":["しろ"],"comment":"(n) white"},
	{"question":"白い","answers":["しろい"],"comment":"(adj) white"},
	{"question":"白状","answers":["はくじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) confession"},
	{"question":"白髪","answers":["しらが"],"comment":"(n) white or grey hair/trendy hair bleaching"},
	{"question":"百","answers":["ひゃく"],"comment":"(num) 100/hundred"},
	{"question":"的確","answers":["てきかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) precise/accurate"},
	{"question":"皆","answers":["みな","みんな"],"comment":"(adv,n) all/everyone/everybody"},
	{"question":"皆さん","answers":["みなさん"],"comment":"(n) everyone"},
	{"question":"皇居","answers":["こうきょ"],"comment":"(n) Imperial Palace"},
	{"question":"皮","answers":["かわ"],"comment":"(n) skin/hide/leather/fur/pelt/bark/shell"},
	{"question":"皮肉","answers":["ひにく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cynicism/sarcasm"},
	{"question":"皮膚","answers":["ひふ"],"comment":"(n) skin"},
	{"question":"皿","answers":["さら"],"comment":"(n) plate/dish"},
	{"question":"盆","answers":["ぼん"],"comment":"(n) Lantern Festival/Festival of the Dead/tray"},
	{"question":"盆地","answers":["ぼんち"],"comment":"(n) basin (e.g. between mountains)"},
	{"question":"盗む","answers":["ぬすむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to steal"},
	{"question":"盗難","answers":["とうなん"],"comment":"(n) theft/robbery"},
	{"question":"盛り","answers":["さかり"],"comment":"(n) helping/serving"},
	{"question":"盛り上がる","answers":["もりあがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rouse/to swell/to rise"},
	{"question":"盛る","answers":["もる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to serve (food, etc.)/(2) to fill up/(3) to prescribe"},
	{"question":"盛ん","answers":["さかん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) popularity/prosperous"},
	{"question":"盛大","answers":["せいだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) grand/prosperous/magnificent"},
	{"question":"盛装","answers":["せいそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) be dressed up/wear rich clothes"},
	{"question":"監督","answers":["かんとく"],"comment":"(n,vs) supervision/control/superintendence"},
	{"question":"監視","answers":["かんし"],"comment":"(n,vs) observation/guarding/inspection/surveillance"},
	{"question":"目","answers":["め"],"comment":"(n) eye/eyeball"},
	{"question":"目上","answers":["めうえ"],"comment":"(n) superior(s)/senior"},
	{"question":"目下","answers":["めした","もっか"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) at present/now"},
	{"question":"目付き","answers":["めつき"],"comment":"(n) look/expression of the eyes/eyes"},
	{"question":"目印","answers":["めじるし"],"comment":"(n,vs) mark/sign/landmark"},
	{"question":"目安","answers":["めやす"],"comment":"(n) criterion/aim"},
	{"question":"目指す","answers":["めざす"],"comment":"(v5s) to aim at/to have an eye on"},
	{"question":"目方","answers":["めかた"],"comment":"(n) weight"},
	{"question":"目標","answers":["もくひょう"],"comment":"(n) mark/objective/target"},
	{"question":"目次","answers":["もくじ"],"comment":"(n) table of contents"},
	{"question":"目的","answers":["もくてき"],"comment":"(n) purpose/goal/aim/objective/intention"},
	{"question":"目盛","answers":["めもり"],"comment":"(n) scale/gradations"},
	{"question":"目立つ","answers":["めだつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to be conspicuous/to stand out"},
	{"question":"目覚し","answers":["めざまし"],"comment":"(n) (abbr) alarm-clock"},
	{"question":"目覚しい","answers":["めざましい"],"comment":"(adj) (arch) brilliant/splendid/striking/remarkable"},
	{"question":"目覚める","answers":["めざめる"],"comment":"(v1) to wake up"},
	{"question":"目論見","answers":["もくろみ"],"comment":"(n,vs) a plan/a scheme/a project/a program/intention/goal"},
	{"question":"目途","answers":["めど"],"comment":"(n) goal/outlook"},
	{"question":"目録","answers":["もくろく"],"comment":"(n) catalogue/catalog/list"},
	{"question":"盲点","answers":["もうてん"],"comment":"(n) blind spot"},
	{"question":"直","answers":["じき"],"comment":"earnestly/immediately/exactly"},
	{"question":"直す","answers":["なおす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to cure/to heal/to fix/to correct/to repair"},
	{"question":"直ちに","answers":["ただちに"],"comment":"(adv) at once/immediately/directly/in person"},
	{"question":"直に","answers":["じかに"],"comment":"(adv) immediately/readily/directly"},
	{"question":"直る","answers":["なおる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to be cured/to heal/to get mended/to get well/to be repaired/to be fixed"},
	{"question":"直前","answers":["ちょくぜん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) just before"},
	{"question":"直径","answers":["ちょっけい"],"comment":"(n) diameter"},
	{"question":"直後","answers":["ちょくご"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) immediately following"},
	{"question":"直感","answers":["ちょっかん"],"comment":"(n) intuition/instinct/insight/hunch"},
	{"question":"直接","answers":["ちょくせつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv) direct/immediate/personal/firsthand"},
	{"question":"直流","answers":["ちょくりゅう"],"comment":"(n) direct current"},
	{"question":"直線","answers":["ちょくせん"],"comment":"(n) straight line"},
	{"question":"直角","answers":["ちょっかく"],"comment":"(n) right angle"},
	{"question":"直通","answers":["ちょくつう"],"comment":"(n) direct communication"},
	{"question":"直面","answers":["ちょくめん"],"comment":"(n,vs) confrontation"},
	{"question":"相","answers":["そう"],"comment":"(n) aspect/phase/countenance"},
	{"question":"相互","answers":["そうご"],"comment":"(n) mutual/reciprocal"},
	{"question":"相場","answers":["そうば"],"comment":"(n) market price/speculation/estimation"},
	{"question":"相対","answers":["そうたい"],"comment":"(n) relative"},
	{"question":"相当","answers":["そうとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv) suitable/fair/tolerable/proper"},
	{"question":"相応","answers":["そうおう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) suitability/fitness"},
	{"question":"相手","answers":["あいて"],"comment":"(n) (1) companion/partner/company/(2) other party/addressee"},
	{"question":"相撲","answers":["すもう"],"comment":"(n) sumo wrestling"},
	{"question":"相続","answers":["そうぞく"],"comment":"(n) succession/inheritance"},
	{"question":"相談","answers":["そうだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) consultation/discussion"},
	{"question":"相違","answers":["そうい"],"comment":"(n,vs) difference/discrepancy/variation"},
	{"question":"盾","answers":["たて"],"comment":"(n) shield/buckler/escutcheon/pretext"},
	{"question":"省く","answers":["はぶく"],"comment":"(v5k) to omit/to eliminate/to curtail/to economize"},
	{"question":"省みる","answers":["かえりみる"],"comment":"(v1) to reflect"},
	{"question":"省略","answers":["しょうりゃく"],"comment":"(n,vs) omission/abbreviation/abridgment"},
	{"question":"眉","answers":["まゆ"],"comment":"(n) eyebrow"},
	{"question":"看板","answers":["かんばん"],"comment":"(n) sign/signboard/doorplate/poster/billboard/appearance/figurehead/policy/attraction/closing time"},
	{"question":"看病","answers":["かんびょう"],"comment":"(n) nursing (a patient)"},
	{"question":"看護","answers":["かんご"],"comment":"(n,vs) nursing/(army) nurse"},
	{"question":"看護婦","answers":["かんごふ"],"comment":"(n) (female) nurse"},
	{"question":"県","answers":["けん"],"comment":"(n) prefecture"},
	{"question":"県庁","answers":["けんちょう"],"comment":"(n) prefectural office"},
	{"question":"真っ二つ","answers":["まっぷたつ"],"comment":"(n) in two equal parts"},
	{"question":"真っ先","answers":["まっさき"],"comment":"(n) the head/the foremost/beginning"},
	{"question":"真っ暗","answers":["まっくら"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) total darkness/shortsightedness/pitch dark"},
	{"question":"真っ白","answers":["まっしろ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pure white"},
	{"question":"真っ直ぐ","answers":["まっすぐ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) straight (ahead)/direct/upright/erect/honest/frank"},
	{"question":"真っ赤","answers":["まっか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) deep red/flushed (of face)"},
	{"question":"真っ青","answers":["まっさお"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) deep blue/ghastly pale"},
	{"question":"真っ黒","answers":["まっくろ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pitch black"},
	{"question":"真ん丸い","answers":["まんまるい"],"comment":"(adj) perfectly circular"},
	{"question":"真ん円い","answers":["まんまるい"],"comment":"(adj) perfectly round"},
	{"question":"真ん前","answers":["まんまえ"],"comment":"(n) right in front/under the nose"},
	{"question":"真上","answers":["まうえ"],"comment":"(n) just above/right overhead"},
	{"question":"真下","answers":["ました"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) right under/directly below"},
	{"question":"真中","answers":["まんなか"],"comment":"(n) middle/centre/mid-way"},
	{"question":"真似","answers":["まね"],"comment":"(n) mimicry/imitation/behavior/pretense"},
	{"question":"真似る","answers":["まねる"],"comment":"(v1) to mimic/to imitate"},
	{"question":"真剣","answers":["しんけん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) seriousness/earnestness"},
	{"question":"真実","answers":["しんじつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) truth/reality"},
	{"question":"真心","answers":["まごころ"],"comment":"(n) sincerity/devotion"},
	{"question":"真珠","answers":["しんじゅ"],"comment":"(n) pearl"},
	{"question":"真理","answers":["しんり"],"comment":"(n) truth"},
	{"question":"真相","answers":["しんそう"],"comment":"(n) truth/real situation"},
	{"question":"真空","answers":["しんくう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) vacuum/hollow/empty"},
	{"question":"真面目","answers":["まじめ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) diligent/serious/honest"},
	{"question":"眠い","answers":["ねむい"],"comment":"(adj) (1) aestivation/estivation/(2) sleepy/drowsy"},
	{"question":"眠たい","answers":["ねむたい"],"comment":"(adj) sleepy"},
	{"question":"眠る","answers":["ねむる"],"comment":"(v5r) to sleep"},
	{"question":"眺め","answers":["ながめ"],"comment":"(n) scene/view/prospect/outlook"},
	{"question":"眺める","answers":["ながめる"],"comment":"(v1) to view/to gaze at"},
	{"question":"眼球","answers":["がんきゅう"],"comment":"(n) eyeball"},
	{"question":"眼科","answers":["がんか"],"comment":"(n) ophthalmology"},
	{"question":"眼鏡","answers":["めがね"],"comment":"(n) spectacles/glasses"},
	{"question":"着々","answers":["ちゃくちゃく"],"comment":"(adv) steadily"},
	{"question":"着く","answers":["つく"],"comment":"(v5k) to arrive at/to reach"},
	{"question":"着ける","answers":["つける"],"comment":"(v1,vt) (1) to attach/to join/to add/to append/to affix/to stick/to glue/to fasten/to sew on/to apply (ointment)/(2) to furnish (a house with)/(3) to wear/to put on/(4) to keep a diary/to make an entry/(5) to appraise/to set (a price)/(6) to bring alongside/(7) to place (under guard or doctor)/(8) to follow/to shadow/(9) to load/to give (courage to)/(10) to keep (an eye on)/(11) to establish (relations or understanding)"},
	{"question":"着せる","answers":["きせる"],"comment":"(v1) to put on clothes"},
	{"question":"着る","answers":["きる"],"comment":"(v1) to wear/to put on (from shoulders down)"},
	{"question":"着工","answers":["ちゃっこう"],"comment":"(n) start of (construction) work"},
	{"question":"着席","answers":["ちゃくせき"],"comment":"(n,vs) sit down/seat"},
	{"question":"着手","answers":["ちゃくしゅ"],"comment":"(n,vs) embarkation/launch"},
	{"question":"着替え","answers":["きがえ"],"comment":"(n) changing clothes/change of clothes"},
	{"question":"着替える","answers":["きがえる"],"comment":"(v1) to change one's clothes"},
	{"question":"着物","answers":["きもの"],"comment":"(n) kimono"},
	{"question":"着目","answers":["ちゃくもく"],"comment":"(n,vs) attention"},
	{"question":"着色","answers":["ちゃくしょく"],"comment":"(n) colouring/coloring"},
	{"question":"着陸","answers":["ちゃくりく"],"comment":"(n,vs) landing/alighting/touch down"},
	{"question":"着飾る","answers":["きかざる"],"comment":"(v5r) to dress up"},
	{"question":"睡眠","answers":["すいみん"],"comment":"(n) sleep"},
	{"question":"睨む","answers":["にらむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to glare at/to scowl at/to keep an eye on"},
	{"question":"瞬き","answers":["まばたき"],"comment":"(n) wink/twinkling (of stars)/flicker (of light)"},
	{"question":"瞬間","answers":["しゅんかん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) moment/second/instant"},
	{"question":"瞳","answers":["ひとみ"],"comment":"(n) pupil (of eye)"},
	{"question":"矛盾","answers":["むじゅん"],"comment":"(n,vs) contradiction/inconsistency"},
	{"question":"矢","answers":["や"],"comment":"(n) arrow"},
	{"question":"矢印","answers":["やじるし"],"comment":"(n) directing arrow"},
	{"question":"知らせ","answers":["しらせ"],"comment":"(n) notice"},
	{"question":"知らせる","answers":["しらせる"],"comment":"(v1) to notify/to advise"},
	{"question":"知る","answers":["しる"],"comment":"(v5r) to know/to understand/to be acquainted with/to feel"},
	{"question":"知事","answers":["ちじ"],"comment":"(n) prefectural governor"},
	{"question":"知人","answers":["ちじん"],"comment":"(n) friend/acquaintance"},
	{"question":"知合い","answers":["しりあい"],"comment":"(n) acquaintance"},
	{"question":"知性","answers":["ちせい"],"comment":"(n) intelligence"},
	{"question":"知恵","answers":["ちえ"],"comment":"(n) wisdom/wit/sagacity/sense/intelligence/advice"},
	{"question":"知的","answers":["ちてき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) intellectual"},
	{"question":"知能","answers":["ちのう"],"comment":"(n) intelligence/brains"},
	{"question":"知識","answers":["ちしき"],"comment":"(n) knowledge/information"},
	{"question":"短い","answers":["みじかい"],"comment":"(adj) short"},
	{"question":"短大","answers":["たんだい"],"comment":"(n) junior college"},
	{"question":"短所","answers":["たんしょ"],"comment":"(n) (1) defect/demerit/weak point/(2) disadvantage"},
	{"question":"短期","answers":["たんき"],"comment":"(n) short term"},
	{"question":"短歌","answers":["たんか"],"comment":"(n) tanka/31-syllable Japanese poem"},
	{"question":"短気","answers":["たんき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) quick temper"},
	{"question":"短波","answers":["たんぱ"],"comment":"(n) short wave"},
	{"question":"短編","answers":["たんぺん"],"comment":"(n) short (e.g. story, film)"},
	{"question":"短縮","answers":["たんしゅく"],"comment":"(n,vs) shortening/abbreviation/reduction"},
	{"question":"石","answers":["いし"],"comment":"(n) volume measure (approx. 180l, 5 bushels, 10 cub.ft)"},
	{"question":"石油","answers":["せきゆ"],"comment":"(n) oil/petroleum/kerosene"},
	{"question":"石炭","answers":["せきたん"],"comment":"(n) coal"},
	{"question":"石鹸","answers":["せっけん"],"comment":"(n) soap"},
	{"question":"砂","answers":["すな"],"comment":"(n) sand/grit"},
	{"question":"砂利","answers":["じゃり"],"comment":"(n) gravel/ballast/pebbles"},
	{"question":"砂漠","answers":["さばく"],"comment":"(n) desert"},
	{"question":"砂糖","answers":["さとう"],"comment":"(n) sugar"},
	{"question":"研ぐ","answers":["とぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to sharpen/to grind/to scour/to hone/to polish/to wash (rice)"},
	{"question":"研修","answers":["けんしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) training"},
	{"question":"研究","answers":["けんきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) study/research/investigation"},
	{"question":"研究室","answers":["けんきゅうしつ"],"comment":"(n) seminar room/laboratory/prof's office"},
	{"question":"砕く","answers":["くだく"],"comment":"(v5k,vt) to break/to smash"},
	{"question":"砕ける","answers":["くだける"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to break/to be broken"},
	{"question":"破る","answers":["やぶる"],"comment":"(v5r,vt) to tear/to violate/to defeat/to smash/to destroy"},
	{"question":"破れる","answers":["やぶれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get torn/to wear out"},
	{"question":"破壊","answers":["はかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) destruction"},
	{"question":"破損","answers":["はそん"],"comment":"(n) damage"},
	{"question":"破棄","answers":["はき"],"comment":"(n,vs) revocation/annulment/breaking (e.g. treaty)"},
	{"question":"破片","answers":["はへん"],"comment":"(n) fragment/splinter/broken piece"},
	{"question":"破産","answers":["はさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (personal) bankruptcy"},
	{"question":"破裂","answers":["はれつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) explosion/rupture/break off"},
	{"question":"硬い","answers":["かたい"],"comment":"(adj) solid/hard (esp. metal, stone)/unpolished writing"},
	{"question":"硬貨","answers":["こうか"],"comment":"(n) coin"},
	{"question":"碁","answers":["ご"],"comment":"(n) Go (board game of capturing territory)"},
	{"question":"碁盤","answers":["ごばん"],"comment":"(n) Go board"},
	{"question":"碑","answers":["ひ"],"comment":"(n) stone monument bearing an inscription"},
	{"question":"碗","answers":["わん"],"comment":"(n) bowl"},
	{"question":"確か","answers":["たしか"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,exp,n) certain/sure/definite/if I'm not mistaken/if I remember correctly"},
	{"question":"確かめる","answers":["たしかめる"],"comment":"(v1) to ascertain"},
	{"question":"確保","answers":["かくほ"],"comment":"(n,vs) guarantee/ensure/maintain/insure/secure"},
	{"question":"確信","answers":["かくしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) conviction/confidence"},
	{"question":"確定","answers":["かくてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) definition (math)/decision/settlement"},
	{"question":"確実","answers":["かくじつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) certainty/reliability/soundness"},
	{"question":"確率","answers":["かくりつ"],"comment":"(n) probability"},
	{"question":"確立","answers":["かくりつ"],"comment":"(n) establishment"},
	{"question":"確認","answers":["かくにん"],"comment":"(n,vs) affirmation/confirmation"},
	{"question":"磁器","answers":["じき"],"comment":"(n) porcelain/china"},
	{"question":"磁気","answers":["じき"],"comment":"(n) magnetism"},
	{"question":"磁石","answers":["じしゃく"],"comment":"(n) magnet"},
	{"question":"磨く","answers":["みがく"],"comment":"(v5k) to polish/to shine/to brush/to refine/to improve"},
	{"question":"示す","answers":["しめす"],"comment":"(v5s) to denote/to show/to point out/to indicate"},
	{"question":"礼","answers":["れい"],"comment":"(n) expression of gratitude"},
	{"question":"礼儀","answers":["れいぎ"],"comment":"(n) manners/courtesy/etiquette"},
	{"question":"社交","answers":["しゃこう"],"comment":"(n) social life/social intercourse"},
	{"question":"社会","answers":["しゃかい"],"comment":"(n) society/public"},
	{"question":"社会科学","answers":["しゃかいかがく"],"comment":"social science"},
	{"question":"社宅","answers":["しゃたく"],"comment":"(n) company owned house"},
	{"question":"社説","answers":["しゃせつ"],"comment":"(n) editorial/leading article"},
	{"question":"社長","answers":["しゃちょう"],"comment":"(n) company president/manager/director"},
	{"question":"祈り","answers":["いのり"],"comment":"(n) prayer/supplication"},
	{"question":"祈る","answers":["いのる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to pray/to wish"},
	{"question":"祖先","answers":["そせん"],"comment":"(n) ancestor"},
	{"question":"祖母","answers":["そぼ"],"comment":"(n) grandmother"},
	{"question":"祖父","answers":["そふ"],"comment":"(n) grandfather"},
	{"question":"祝い","answers":["いわい"],"comment":"(n) celebration/festival"},
	{"question":"祝う","answers":["いわう"],"comment":"(v5u) to congratulate/to celebrate"},
	{"question":"祝日","answers":["しゅくじつ"],"comment":"(n) national holiday"},
	{"question":"祝賀","answers":["しゅくが"],"comment":"(n,vs) celebration/congratulations"},
	{"question":"神","answers":["かみ"],"comment":"(n) god"},
	{"question":"神様","answers":["かみさま"],"comment":"(n) god"},
	{"question":"神殿","answers":["しんでん"],"comment":"(n) temple/sacred place"},
	{"question":"神社","answers":["じんじゃ"],"comment":"(n) Shinto shrine"},
	{"question":"神秘","answers":["しんぴ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) mystery"},
	{"question":"神経","answers":["しんけい"],"comment":"(n) nerve/sensitivity"},
	{"question":"神聖","answers":["しんせい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) holiness/sacredness/dignity"},
	{"question":"神話","answers":["しんわ"],"comment":"(n) myth/legend"},
	{"question":"票","answers":["ひょう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) label/ballot/ticket/sign"},
	{"question":"祭","answers":["まつり"],"comment":"(n) festival/feast"},
	{"question":"祭る","answers":["まつる"],"comment":"(v5r) to deify/to enshrine"},
	{"question":"祭日","answers":["さいじつ"],"comment":"(n) national holiday/festival day"},
	{"question":"禁じる","answers":["きんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to prohibit"},
	{"question":"禁止","answers":["きんし"],"comment":"(n,vs) prohibition/ban"},
	{"question":"禁煙","answers":["きんえん"],"comment":"(exp) No Smoking!"},
	{"question":"禁物","answers":["きんもつ"],"comment":"(n) taboo/forbidden thing"},
	{"question":"禅","answers":["ぜん"],"comment":"(n) Zen (Buddhism)"},
	{"question":"福","answers":["ふく"],"comment":"(n) good fortune"},
	{"question":"福祉","answers":["ふくし"],"comment":"(n) welfare/well-being"},
	{"question":"私","answers":["わたくし","わたし"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) I/myself/private affairs"},
	{"question":"私有","answers":["しゆう"],"comment":"(n) private ownership"},
	{"question":"私物","answers":["しぶつ"],"comment":"(n) private property/personal effects"},
	{"question":"私用","answers":["しよう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) personal use/private business"},
	{"question":"私立","answers":["しりつ"],"comment":"(n) private (establishment)"},
	{"question":"私鉄","answers":["してつ"],"comment":"(n) private railway"},
	{"question":"秋","answers":["あき"],"comment":"(n-adv) autumn/fall"},
	{"question":"科学","answers":["かがく"],"comment":"(n) science"},
	{"question":"科目","answers":["かもく"],"comment":"(n) (school) subject/curriculum/course"},
	{"question":"秒","answers":["びょう"],"comment":"(n) second (60th min)"},
	{"question":"秘密","answers":["ひみつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) secret/secrecy"},
	{"question":"秘書","answers":["ひしょ"],"comment":"(n) (private) secretary"},
	{"question":"秤","answers":["はかり"],"comment":"(n) scales/weighing machine"},
	{"question":"秩序","answers":["ちつじょ"],"comment":"(n) order/regularity/system/method"},
	{"question":"称する","answers":["しょうする"],"comment":"(vs-s) (1) to take the name of/to call oneself/(2) to pretend/to feign/to purport"},
	{"question":"移す","answers":["うつす"],"comment":"(v5s) to remove/to transfer/to infect"},
	{"question":"移る","answers":["うつる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to move (house)/to transfer (department)/(2) to be infected/to be contagious"},
	{"question":"移住","answers":["いじゅう"],"comment":"(n) migration/immigration"},
	{"question":"移動","answers":["いどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) removal/migration/movement"},
	{"question":"移民","answers":["いみん"],"comment":"(n) emigration/immigration/emigrant/immigrant"},
	{"question":"移行","answers":["いこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) switching over to"},
	{"question":"移転","answers":["いてん"],"comment":"(n,vs) moving/transfer/demise"},
	{"question":"稀","answers":["まれ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) rare/seldom"},
	{"question":"程","answers":["ほど"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) degree/extent/bounds/limit"},
	{"question":"程度","answers":["ていど"],"comment":"(n-adv,n,n-suf) degree/amount/grade/standard/of the order of (following a number)"},
	{"question":"税務署","answers":["ぜいむしょ"],"comment":"(n) tax office"},
	{"question":"税金","answers":["ぜいきん"],"comment":"(n) tax/duty"},
	{"question":"税関","answers":["ぜいかん"],"comment":"(n) customs house"},
	{"question":"種","answers":["しゅ","たね"],"comment":"(n) (1) seed/pip/kind/variety/quality/tone/(2) material/matter/subject/theme/(news) copy/(3) cause/source/trick/secret/inside story"},
	{"question":"種々","answers":["しゅじゅ"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,adv,n) variety"},
	{"question":"種類","answers":["しゅるい"],"comment":"(n) variety/kind/type/category/counter for different sorts of things"},
	{"question":"稲","answers":["いね"],"comment":"(n) rice-plant"},
	{"question":"稲光","answers":["いなびかり"],"comment":"(n) (flash of) lightning"},
	{"question":"稼ぐ","answers":["かせぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to earn income/to labor"},
	{"question":"稽古","answers":["けいこ"],"comment":"(n) practice/training/study"},
	{"question":"穀物","answers":["こくもつ"],"comment":"(n) grain/cereal/corn"},
	{"question":"穂","answers":["ほ"],"comment":"(n) ear (of plant)/head (of plant)"},
	{"question":"積む","answers":["つむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to pile up/to stack"},
	{"question":"積もる","answers":["つもる"],"comment":"(v5r) to pile up"},
	{"question":"積極的","answers":["せっきょくてき"],"comment":"(adj-na) positive/active/proactive"},
	{"question":"穏やか","answers":["おだやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) calm/gentle/quiet"},
	{"question":"穴","answers":["あな"],"comment":"(n) (col) ass/arse/buttocks"},
	{"question":"究極","answers":["きゅうきょく"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) ultimate/final/eventual"},
	{"question":"空","answers":["から","そら"],"comment":"(n) sky"},
	{"question":"空き","answers":["あき"],"comment":"(n) room/time to spare/emptiness/vacant"},
	{"question":"空く","answers":["あく","すく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) (1) to open/to become open/to become empty/(2) to be less crowded"},
	{"question":"空しい","answers":["むなしい"],"comment":"(adj) vacant/futile/vain/void/empty/ineffective/lifeless"},
	{"question":"空っぽ","answers":["からっぽ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) empty/vacant/hollow"},
	{"question":"空ろ","answers":["うつろ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) blank/cavity/hollow/empty (space)"},
	{"question":"空中","answers":["くうちゅう"],"comment":"(n) sky/air"},
	{"question":"空想","answers":["くうそう"],"comment":"(n) daydream/fantasy/fancy/vision"},
	{"question":"空気","answers":["くうき"],"comment":"(n) air/atmosphere"},
	{"question":"空港","answers":["くうこう"],"comment":"(n) airport"},
	{"question":"空腹","answers":["くうふく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) hunger"},
	{"question":"空間","answers":["くうかん"],"comment":"(n) space/room/airspace"},
	{"question":"突き当たり","answers":["つきあたり"],"comment":"(n) end (e.g. of street)"},
	{"question":"突き当たる","answers":["つきあたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to run into/to collide with"},
	{"question":"突く","answers":["つく","つつく"],"comment":"(v5k) (1) to thrust/to strike/to attack/(2) to poke/to nudge/to pick at"},
	{"question":"突っ張る","answers":["つっぱる"],"comment":"(v5r) to support/to become stiff/to become taut/to thrust (ones opponent)/to stick to (ones opinion)/to insist on"},
	{"question":"突っ突く","answers":["つっつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to prompt someone"},
	{"question":"突っ込む","answers":["つっこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to plunge into/to go into deeply"},
	{"question":"突如","answers":["とつじょ"],"comment":"(adv) suddenly/all of a sudden"},
	{"question":"突然","answers":["とつぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,adv) abruptly/suddenly/unexpectedly/all at once"},
	{"question":"突破","answers":["とっぱ"],"comment":"(n,vs) breaking through/breakthrough/penetration"},
	{"question":"窒息","answers":["ちっそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) suffocation"},
	{"question":"窓","answers":["まど"],"comment":"(n) window"},
	{"question":"窓口","answers":["まどぐち"],"comment":"(n) ticket window"},
	{"question":"窮乏","answers":["きゅうぼう"],"comment":"(n) poverty"},
	{"question":"窮屈","answers":["きゅうくつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) narrow/tight/stiff/rigid/uneasy/formal/constrained"},
	{"question":"立ち上がる","answers":["たちあがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stand up"},
	{"question":"立ち去る","answers":["たちさる"],"comment":"(v5r) to leave/to depart/to take one's leave"},
	{"question":"立ち寄る","answers":["たちよる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stop by/to drop in for a short visit"},
	{"question":"立ち止まる","answers":["たちどまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stop/to halt/to stand still"},
	{"question":"立つ","answers":["たつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to stand"},
	{"question":"立てる","answers":["たてる"],"comment":"(v1) to stand (something) up/to erect (something)"},
	{"question":"立て替える","answers":["たてかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to pay in advance/to pay for another/to pay someone else's debt as a loan to him"},
	{"question":"立体","answers":["りったい"],"comment":"(n) solid body"},
	{"question":"立場","answers":["たちば"],"comment":"(n) standpoint/position/situation"},
	{"question":"立方","answers":["りっぽう"],"comment":"(n) cube"},
	{"question":"立法","answers":["りっぽう"],"comment":"(n) legislation/lawmaking"},
	{"question":"立派","answers":["りっぱ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) splendid/fine/handsome/elegant/imposing/prominent/legal/legitimate"},
	{"question":"章","answers":["しょう"],"comment":"(n) (1) chapter/section/(2) medal"},
	{"question":"童話","answers":["どうわ"],"comment":"(n) fairy tale"},
	{"question":"童謡","answers":["どうよう"],"comment":"(n) children's song/nursery rhyme"},
	{"question":"端","answers":["はし"],"comment":"(n) end (e.g. of street)/edge/tip/margin/point"},
	{"question":"競争","answers":["きょうそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) competition/contest"},
	{"question":"競技","answers":["きょうぎ"],"comment":"(n) game/match/contest"},
	{"question":"競馬","answers":["けいば"],"comment":"(n) horse racing"},
	{"question":"竹","answers":["たけ"],"comment":"(n) bamboo/middle (of a three-tier ranking system)"},
	{"question":"竿","answers":["さお"],"comment":"(n) rod/pole (e.g. for drying laundry)"},
	{"question":"笑い","answers":["わらい"],"comment":"(n) laugh/laughter/smile"},
	{"question":"笑う","answers":["わらう"],"comment":"(v5u) to laugh/to smile"},
	{"question":"笑顔","answers":["えがお"],"comment":"(n) smiling face"},
	{"question":"笛","answers":["ふえ"],"comment":"(n) flute/pipe"},
	{"question":"符号","answers":["ふごう"],"comment":"(n) sign/mark/symbol"},
	{"question":"筆","answers":["ふで"],"comment":"(n) writing brush"},
	{"question":"筆者","answers":["ひっしゃ"],"comment":"(n) writer/author"},
	{"question":"筆記","answers":["ひっき"],"comment":"(n,vs) (taking) notes/copying"},
	{"question":"等","answers":["など"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,prt) (uk) et cetera/etc./and the like"},
	{"question":"等しい","answers":["ひとしい"],"comment":"(adj) equal"},
	{"question":"等分","answers":["とうぶん"],"comment":"(n,vs) division into equal parts"},
	{"question":"等級","answers":["とうきゅう"],"comment":"(n) grade/class"},
	{"question":"筋","answers":["すじ"],"comment":"(n) muscle/string/line/stripe/plot/plan/sinew"},
	{"question":"筋肉","answers":["きんにく"],"comment":"(n) muscle/sinew"},
	{"question":"筒","answers":["つつ"],"comment":"(n) pipe/tube"},
	{"question":"答","answers":["こたえ"],"comment":"(n) answer/response"},
	{"question":"答える","answers":["こたえる"],"comment":"(v1) to answer/to reply"},
	{"question":"答案","answers":["とうあん"],"comment":"(n) examination paper/examination script"},
	{"question":"策","answers":["さく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) plan/policy"},
	{"question":"箇条書","answers":["かじょうがき"],"comment":"(n) itemized form/itemization"},
	{"question":"箒","answers":["ほうき"],"comment":"(oK) (n) broom"},
	{"question":"算数","answers":["さんすう"],"comment":"(n) arithmetic"},
	{"question":"算盤","answers":["そろばん"],"comment":"(n) abacus"},
	{"question":"管","answers":["かん","くだ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) pipe/tube"},
	{"question":"管理","answers":["かんり"],"comment":"(n,vs) control/management (e.g. of a business)"},
	{"question":"箱","answers":["はこ"],"comment":"(n) box"},
	{"question":"箸","answers":["はし"],"comment":"(n) chopsticks"},
	{"question":"節","answers":["せつ","ふし"],"comment":"(n-suf) tune/tone/knot/knob/point"},
	{"question":"節約","answers":["せつやく"],"comment":"(n,vs) economising/saving"},
	{"question":"範囲","answers":["はんい"],"comment":"(n) extent/scope/sphere/range"},
	{"question":"築く","answers":["きずく"],"comment":"(v5k) to build/to pile up/to amass"},
	{"question":"簡単","answers":["かんたん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) simple"},
	{"question":"簡易","answers":["かんい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) simplicity/easiness/quasi-"},
	{"question":"簡潔","answers":["かんけつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) brevity/conciseness/simplicity"},
	{"question":"簡素","answers":["かんそ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) simplicity/plain"},
	{"question":"籠","answers":["かご"],"comment":"(n) basket/cage"},
	{"question":"籠もる","answers":["こもる"],"comment":"(v5r) to seclude oneself/to be confined in/to be implied/to be stuffy"},
	{"question":"米","answers":["こめ"],"comment":"(n) uncooked rice"},
	{"question":"粉","answers":["こな"],"comment":"(n) flour/meal/powder"},
	{"question":"粉々","answers":["こなごな"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) in very small pieces"},
	{"question":"粉末","answers":["ふんまつ"],"comment":"(n) fine powder"},
	{"question":"粋","answers":["いき","すい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) chic/style/purity/essence"},
	{"question":"粒","answers":["つぶ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) grain"},
	{"question":"粗い","answers":["あらい"],"comment":"(adj) coarse/rough"},
	{"question":"粗末","answers":["そまつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) crude/rough/plain/humble"},
	{"question":"粘り","answers":["ねばり"],"comment":"(n) stickiness/viscosity"},
	{"question":"粘る","answers":["ねばる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be sticky/to be adhesive/to persevere/to persist/to stick to"},
	{"question":"粥","answers":["かゆ"],"comment":"(n) (rice) gruel"},
	{"question":"精々","answers":["せいぜい"],"comment":"(adv) at the most/at best/to the utmost/as much (far) as possible"},
	{"question":"精密","answers":["せいみつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) precise/exact/detailed/minute/close"},
	{"question":"精巧","answers":["せいこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) elaborate/delicate/exquisite"},
	{"question":"精神","answers":["せいしん"],"comment":"(n) mind/soul/heart/spirit/intention"},
	{"question":"精算","answers":["せいさん"],"comment":"(n) exact calculation/squaring of accounts"},
	{"question":"糊","answers":["のり"],"comment":"(n) paste/starch"},
	{"question":"糸","answers":["いと"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) thread/yarn/string"},
	{"question":"系統","answers":["けいとう"],"comment":"(n) system/family line/geological formation/lineage/ancestry"},
	{"question":"約","answers":["やく"],"comment":"(adv,n) approximately/about/some"},
	{"question":"約束","answers":["やくそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) arrangement/promise"},
	{"question":"紅茶","answers":["こうちゃ"],"comment":"(n) black tea"},
	{"question":"紅葉","answers":["こうよう","もみじ"],"comment":"(n) (1) (Japanese) maple"},
	{"question":"納まる","answers":["おさまる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to be in one's place/to be installed/to settle into/(2) to be obtained/to be settled/to be paid/to be delivered"},
	{"question":"納める","answers":["おさめる"],"comment":"(v1) to obtain/to reap/to pay/to supply/to accept"},
	{"question":"納入","answers":["のうにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) payment/supply"},
	{"question":"納得","answers":["なっとく"],"comment":"(n,vs) consent/assent/understanding/agreement/comprehension/grasp"},
	{"question":"紐","answers":["ひも"],"comment":"(n) (1) string/cord/(2) pimp"},
	{"question":"純情","answers":["じゅんじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pure heart/naivete/self-sacrificing devotion"},
	{"question":"純粋","answers":["じゅんすい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pure/true/genuine/unmixed"},
	{"question":"紙","answers":["かみ"],"comment":"(n) paper"},
	{"question":"紙屑","answers":["かみくず"],"comment":"(n) wastepaper"},
	{"question":"紙幣","answers":["しへい"],"comment":"(n) paper money/notes/bills"},
	{"question":"級","answers":["きゅう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) class, grade, rank/school class, grade"},
	{"question":"紛らわしい","answers":["まぎらわしい"],"comment":"(adj) confusing/misleading/equivocal/ambiguous"},
	{"question":"紛れる","answers":["まぎれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be diverted/to slip into"},
	{"question":"紛争","answers":["ふんそう"],"comment":"(n) dispute/trouble/strife"},
	{"question":"紛失","answers":["ふんしつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) losing something"},
	{"question":"素","answers":["もと"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) prime"},
	{"question":"素人","answers":["しろうと"],"comment":"(n) amateur/novice"},
	{"question":"素早い","answers":["すばやい"],"comment":"(adj) fast/quick/prompt/agile"},
	{"question":"素晴らしい","answers":["すばらしい"],"comment":"(adj) wonderful/splendid/magnificent"},
	{"question":"素朴","answers":["そぼく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) simplicity/artlessness/naivete"},
	{"question":"素材","answers":["そざい"],"comment":"(n) raw materials/subject matter"},
	{"question":"素直","answers":["すなお"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) obedient/meek/docile/unaffected"},
	{"question":"素質","answers":["そしつ"],"comment":"(n) character/qualities/genius"},
	{"question":"紡績","answers":["ぼうせき"],"comment":"(n) spinning"},
	{"question":"索引","answers":["さくいん"],"comment":"(n) index/indices"},
	{"question":"紫","answers":["むらさき"],"comment":"(n) purple colour/violet"},
	{"question":"細い","answers":["ほそい"],"comment":"(adj) thin/slender/fine"},
	{"question":"細かい","answers":["こまかい"],"comment":"(adj) (1) small/(2) fine/minute"},
	{"question":"細やか","answers":["こまやか"],"comment":"(adj-na) meagre/modest"},
	{"question":"細工","answers":["さいく"],"comment":"(n) work/craftsmanship/tactics/trick"},
	{"question":"細胞","answers":["さいぼう"],"comment":"(n) cell (biology)"},
	{"question":"細菌","answers":["さいきん"],"comment":"(n) bacillus/bacterium/germ"},
	{"question":"紳士","answers":["しんし"],"comment":"(n) gentleman"},
	{"question":"紹介","answers":["しょうかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) introduction"},
	{"question":"紺","answers":["こん"],"comment":"(n) navy blue/deep blue"},
	{"question":"終","answers":["おわり"],"comment":"(n) the end"},
	{"question":"終える","answers":["おえる"],"comment":"(v1) to finish"},
	{"question":"終る","answers":["おわる"],"comment":"(io) (v5r) to finish/to close"},
	{"question":"終わり","answers":["おわり"],"comment":"(n) the end"},
	{"question":"終了","answers":["しゅうりょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) end/close/termination"},
	{"question":"終始","answers":["しゅうし"],"comment":"(adv,n,vs) (1) beginning and end/from beginning to end/doing a thing from beginning to end/(2) consistent(ly)"},
	{"question":"終日","answers":["しゅうじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) all day"},
	{"question":"終点","answers":["しゅうてん"],"comment":"(n) terminus/last stop (e.g train)"},
	{"question":"組","answers":["くみ"],"comment":"(n) class/group/team/set"},
	{"question":"組み合わせる","answers":["くみあわせる"],"comment":"(v1) to join together/to combine/to join up"},
	{"question":"組み立てる","answers":["くみたてる"],"comment":"(v1) to assemble/to set up/to construct"},
	{"question":"組み込む","answers":["くみこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to insert/to include/to cut in (printing)"},
	{"question":"組む","answers":["くむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to put together"},
	{"question":"組合","answers":["くみあい"],"comment":"(n) association/union"},
	{"question":"組合せ","answers":["くみあわせ"],"comment":"(n) combination"},
	{"question":"組織","answers":["そしき"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) organization/(2) structure/construction/(3) tissue/(4) system"},
	{"question":"経つ","answers":["たつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to pass/to lapse"},
	{"question":"経る","answers":["へる"],"comment":"(v1) to pass/to elapse/to experience"},
	{"question":"経営","answers":["けいえい"],"comment":"(n,vs) management/administration"},
	{"question":"経度","answers":["けいど"],"comment":"(n) longitude"},
	{"question":"経歴","answers":["けいれき"],"comment":"(n) personal history/career"},
	{"question":"経済","answers":["けいざい"],"comment":"(n) economics/business/finance/economy"},
	{"question":"経由","answers":["けいゆ"],"comment":"(n) go by the way/via"},
	{"question":"経緯","answers":["けいい"],"comment":"(n) (1) details/whole story/sequence of events/particulars/how it started/how things got this way/(2) complications/position"},
	{"question":"経費","answers":["けいひ"],"comment":"(n) expenses/cost/outlay"},
	{"question":"経路","answers":["けいろ"],"comment":"(n) course/route/channel"},
	{"question":"経過","answers":["けいか"],"comment":"(n) passage/expiration/progress"},
	{"question":"経験","answers":["けいけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) experience"},
	{"question":"結び","answers":["むすび"],"comment":"(n) ending/conclusion/union"},
	{"question":"結び付き","answers":["むすびつき"],"comment":"(n) connection/relation"},
	{"question":"結び付く","answers":["むすびつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be connected or related/to join together"},
	{"question":"結び付ける","answers":["むすびつける"],"comment":"(v1) to combine/to join/to tie on/to attach with a knot"},
	{"question":"結ぶ","answers":["むすぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to tie/to bind/to link"},
	{"question":"結合","answers":["けつごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) combination/union"},
	{"question":"結婚","answers":["けっこん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) marriage"},
	{"question":"結局","answers":["けっきょく"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) after all/eventually"},
	{"question":"結成","answers":["けっせい"],"comment":"(n) formation"},
	{"question":"結晶","answers":["けっしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) crystal/crystallization"},
	{"question":"結束","answers":["けっそく"],"comment":"(n) union/unity"},
	{"question":"結果","answers":["けっか"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) result/consequence"},
	{"question":"結核","answers":["けっかく"],"comment":"(n) tuberculosis/tubercule"},
	{"question":"結構","answers":["けっこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n) (1) (uk) splendid/nice/wonderful/delicious/sweet/(2) (arch) construction/architecture/(3) well enough/tolerably"},
	{"question":"結論","answers":["けつろん"],"comment":"(n) conclusion"},
	{"question":"絞る","answers":["しぼる"],"comment":"(v5r) to press/to wring/to squeeze"},
	{"question":"絡む","answers":["からむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to entangle/to entwine"},
	{"question":"給う","answers":["たまう"],"comment":"(v5u) to receive/to grant"},
	{"question":"給与","answers":["きゅうよ"],"comment":"(n,vs) allowance/grant/supply"},
	{"question":"給仕","answers":["きゅうじ"],"comment":"(n) office boy (girl)/page/waiter"},
	{"question":"給料","answers":["きゅうりょう"],"comment":"(n) salary/wages"},
	{"question":"給食","answers":["きゅうしょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) school lunch/providing a meal"},
	{"question":"統一","answers":["とういつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) unity/consolidation/uniformity/unification/compatible"},
	{"question":"統制","answers":["とうせい"],"comment":"(n) regulation/control"},
	{"question":"統合","answers":["とうごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) integration/unification/synthesis"},
	{"question":"統治","answers":["とうち"],"comment":"(n,vs) rule/reign/government/governing"},
	{"question":"統率","answers":["とうそつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) command/lead/generalship/leadership"},
	{"question":"統計","answers":["とうけい"],"comment":"scattering/a scatter/dispersion"},
	{"question":"絵","answers":["え"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) picture/drawing/painting/sketch"},
	{"question":"絵の具","answers":["えのぐ"],"comment":"(n) colors/paints"},
	{"question":"絵画","answers":["かいが"],"comment":"(n) picture"},
	{"question":"絶えず","answers":["たえず"],"comment":"(adv) constantly"},
	{"question":"絶える","answers":["たえる"],"comment":"(v1) to die out/to peter out/to become extinct"},
	{"question":"絶対","answers":["ぜったい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv,n) absolute/unconditional/absoluteness"},
	{"question":"絶滅","answers":["ぜつめつ"],"comment":"(n) destruction/extinction"},
	{"question":"絶版","answers":["ぜっぱん"],"comment":"(n) out of print"},
	{"question":"絹","answers":["きぬ"],"comment":"(n) silk"},
	{"question":"継ぐ","answers":["つぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to succeed (someone in a business or inheritence)"},
	{"question":"継目","answers":["つぎめ"],"comment":"(n) joint/seam"},
	{"question":"継続","answers":["けいぞく"],"comment":"(n,vs) continuation"},
	{"question":"続々","answers":["ぞくぞく"],"comment":"(n-adv) successively/one after another"},
	{"question":"続き","answers":["つづき"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) sequel/continuation/(also suffix) continuation (in time and space)/second series/succession/spell"},
	{"question":"続く","answers":["つづく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) to be continued"},
	{"question":"続ける","answers":["つづける"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to continue/to keep up/to keep on"},
	{"question":"維持","answers":["いじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) maintenance/preservation"},
	{"question":"綱","answers":["つな"],"comment":"(n) rope"},
	{"question":"網","answers":["あみ"],"comment":"(n) net/network"},
	{"question":"綴じる","answers":["とじる"],"comment":"(v1) to bind/to file"},
	{"question":"綻びる","answers":["ほころびる"],"comment":"(v1) to come apart at the seams/to begin to open/to smile broadly"},
	{"question":"綿","answers":["めん","わた"],"comment":"(n) cotton/padding"},
	{"question":"緊張","answers":["きんちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) tension/mental strain/nervousness"},
	{"question":"緊急","answers":["きんきゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) urgent/pressing/emergency"},
	{"question":"総会","answers":["そうかい"],"comment":"(n) general meeting"},
	{"question":"総合","answers":["そうごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) synthesis/coordination/putting together/integration/composite"},
	{"question":"総理大臣","answers":["そうりだいじん"],"comment":"Prime Minister"},
	{"question":"緑","answers":["みどり"],"comment":"(n) greenery"},
	{"question":"線","answers":["せん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) line (also telephone, railway)/wire/beam"},
	{"question":"線路","answers":["せんろ"],"comment":"(n) line/track/roadbed"},
	{"question":"締める","answers":["しめる"],"comment":"(v1) to tie/to fasten"},
	{"question":"締め切る","answers":["しめきる"],"comment":"(v5r) to shut up"},
	{"question":"締切","answers":["しめきり"],"comment":"(n) closing/cut-off/end/deadline/Closed/No Entrance"},
	{"question":"編む","answers":["あむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to knit"},
	{"question":"編物","answers":["あみもの"],"comment":"(n) knitting/web"},
	{"question":"編集","answers":["へんしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) editing/compilation/editorial (e.g. committee)"},
	{"question":"緩い","answers":["ゆるい"],"comment":"(adj) loose/lenient/slow"},
	{"question":"緩む","answers":["ゆるむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to become loose/to slacken"},
	{"question":"緩める","answers":["ゆるめる"],"comment":"(v1) to loosen/to slow down"},
	{"question":"緩やか","answers":["ゆるやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) lenient"},
	{"question":"緩和","answers":["かんわ"],"comment":"(n) relief/mitigation"},
	{"question":"緯度","answers":["いど"],"comment":"(n) latitude (nav.)"},
	{"question":"練る","answers":["ねる"],"comment":"(v5r) to knead/to work over/to polish up"},
	{"question":"練習","answers":["れんしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) practice"},
	{"question":"縁","answers":["えん","ふち","へり"],"comment":"(n) a means, e.g. of living"},
	{"question":"縁側","answers":["えんがわ"],"comment":"(n) veranda/porch/balcony/open corridor"},
	{"question":"縁談","answers":["えんだん"],"comment":"(n) marriage proposal/engagement"},
	{"question":"縄","answers":["なわ"],"comment":"(n) rope/hemp"},
	{"question":"縛る","answers":["しばる"],"comment":"(v5r) to tie/to bind"},
	{"question":"縞","answers":["しま"],"comment":"(n) stripe"},
	{"question":"縦","answers":["たて"],"comment":"(n) length/height"},
	{"question":"縫う","answers":["ぬう"],"comment":"(v5u) to sew"},
	{"question":"縮まる","answers":["ちぢまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be shortened/to be contracted/to shrink"},
	{"question":"縮む","answers":["ちぢむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to shrink/to be contracted"},
	{"question":"縮める","answers":["ちぢめる"],"comment":"(v1) to shorten/to reduce/to boil down/to shrink"},
	{"question":"縮れる","answers":["ちぢれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be wavy/to be curled"},
	{"question":"縮小","answers":["しゅくしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) reduction/curtailment"},
	{"question":"繁栄","answers":["はんえい"],"comment":"(n,vs) prospering/prosperity/thriving/flourishing"},
	{"question":"繁殖","answers":["はんしょく"],"comment":"(n) breed/multiply/increase/propagation"},
	{"question":"繁盛","answers":["はんじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) prosperity/flourishing/thriving"},
	{"question":"繊維","answers":["せんい"],"comment":"(n) fibre/fiber/textile"},
	{"question":"繋がり","answers":["つながり"],"comment":"(n) connection/link/relationship"},
	{"question":"繋がる","answers":["つながる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be tied together/to be connected to/to be related to"},
	{"question":"繋ぐ","answers":["つなぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) (uk) to tie/to fasten/to connect/to transfer (phone call)"},
	{"question":"繋げる","answers":["つなげる"],"comment":"(v1) to connect"},
	{"question":"織る","answers":["おる"],"comment":"(v5r) to weave"},
	{"question":"織物","answers":["おりもの"],"comment":"(n) textile/fabric"},
	{"question":"繕う","answers":["つくろう"],"comment":"(v5u) to mend/to repair/to fix/to patch up/to darn/to tidy up/to adjust/to trim"},
	{"question":"繰り返す","answers":["くりかえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to repeat/to do something over again"},
	{"question":"纏まり","answers":["まとまり"],"comment":"(n) conclusion/settlement/consistency"},
	{"question":"纏まる","answers":["まとまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be collected/to be settled/to be in order"},
	{"question":"纏め","answers":["まとめ"],"comment":"(n) settlement/conclusion"},
	{"question":"纏める","answers":["まとめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to put in order/to collect/to bring to a conclusion"},
	{"question":"缶","answers":["かん"],"comment":"(n) can/tin"},
	{"question":"缶詰","answers":["かんづめ"],"comment":"(n) packing (in cans)/canning/canned goods/tin can"},
	{"question":"罪","answers":["つみ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) crime/fault/indiscretion"},
	{"question":"置く","answers":["おく"],"comment":"(v5k) to put/to place"},
	{"question":"罰","answers":["ばつ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) punishment/penalty"},
	{"question":"罰する","answers":["ばっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to punish/to penalize"},
	{"question":"署名","answers":["しょめい"],"comment":"(n,vs) signature"},
	{"question":"罵る","answers":["ののしる"],"comment":"(v5r) to speak ill of/to abuse"},
	{"question":"罹る","answers":["かかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to suffer from"},
	{"question":"羊毛","answers":["ようもう"],"comment":"(n) wool"},
	{"question":"美","answers":["び"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) beauty"},
	{"question":"美しい","answers":["うつくしい"],"comment":"(adj) beautiful/lovely"},
	{"question":"美人","answers":["びじん"],"comment":"(n) beautiful person (woman)"},
	{"question":"美容","answers":["びよう"],"comment":"(n) beauty of figure or form"},
	{"question":"美術","answers":["びじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) art/fine arts"},
	{"question":"美術館","answers":["びじゅつかん"],"comment":"(n) art gallery/art museum"},
	{"question":"群","answers":["ぐん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) group (math)"},
	{"question":"群がる","answers":["むらがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to swarm/to gather"},
	{"question":"群れ","answers":["むれ"],"comment":"(n) group/crowd/flock/herd/bevy/school/swarm/cluster (of stars)/clump"},
	{"question":"群衆","answers":["ぐんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) (social) group/crowd/throng/mob/multitude"},
	{"question":"群集","answers":["ぐんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) (social) group/crowd/throng/mob/multitude"},
	{"question":"羨ましい","answers":["うらやましい"],"comment":"(adj) envious/enviable"},
	{"question":"羨む","answers":["うらやむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to envy"},
	{"question":"義務","answers":["ぎむ"],"comment":"(n) duty/obligation/responsibility"},
	{"question":"義理","answers":["ぎり"],"comment":"(n) duty/sense of duty/honor/decency/courtesy/debt of gratitude/social obligation"},
	{"question":"羽","answers":["はね"],"comment":"(n-suf) counter for birds/counter for rabbits"},
	{"question":"羽根","answers":["はね"],"comment":"(n) shuttlecock"},
	{"question":"習う","answers":["ならう"],"comment":"(v5u) to learn"},
	{"question":"習字","answers":["しゅうじ"],"comment":"(n) penmanship"},
	{"question":"習慣","answers":["しゅうかん"],"comment":"(n) custom/habit/manners"},
	{"question":"翻訳","answers":["ほんやく"],"comment":"(n,vs) translation/de-encryption/deciphering"},
	{"question":"翼","answers":["つばさ"],"comment":"(n) wings"},
	{"question":"老いる","answers":["おいる"],"comment":"(v1) to age/to grow old"},
	{"question":"老ける","answers":["ふける"],"comment":"(v1) to age"},
	{"question":"老人","answers":["ろうじん"],"comment":"(n) the aged/old person"},
	{"question":"老衰","answers":["ろうすい"],"comment":"(n) senility/senile decay"},
	{"question":"考え","answers":["かんがえ"],"comment":"(n) thinking/thought/ideas/intention"},
	{"question":"考える","answers":["かんがえる"],"comment":"(v1) to consider"},
	{"question":"考古学","answers":["こうこがく"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) archaeology"},
	{"question":"考慮","answers":["こうりょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) consideration/taking into account"},
	{"question":"者","answers":["もの"],"comment":"(n) person"},
	{"question":"耐える","answers":["たえる"],"comment":"(v1) to bear/to stand/to endure/to put up with/to support/to withstand/to resist/to brave/to be fit for/to be equal to"},
	{"question":"耕す","answers":["たがやす"],"comment":"(v5s) to till/to plow/to cultivate"},
	{"question":"耕作","answers":["こうさく"],"comment":"(n,vs) cultivation/farming"},
	{"question":"耕地","answers":["こうち"],"comment":"(n) arable land"},
	{"question":"耳","answers":["みみ"],"comment":"(n) ear"},
	{"question":"耳鼻科","answers":["じびか"],"comment":"(n) otolaryngology"},
	{"question":"耽る","answers":["ふける"],"comment":"(v5r) to indulge in/to give oneself up to/to be obsessed by/to be engrossed in/to be lost in/to be absorbed in"},
	{"question":"聖書","answers":["せいしょ"],"comment":"(n) Bible/scriptures"},
	{"question":"聞き取り","answers":["ききとり"],"comment":"(n) listening comprehension"},
	{"question":"聞く","answers":["きく"],"comment":"(v5k) to hear/to listen/to ask"},
	{"question":"聞こえる","answers":["きこえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be heard/to be audible"},
	{"question":"聳える","answers":["そびえる"],"comment":"(v1) to rise/to tower/to soar"},
	{"question":"聴覚","answers":["ちょうかく"],"comment":"(n) the sense of hearing"},
	{"question":"聴診器","answers":["ちょうしんき"],"comment":"(n) stethoscope"},
	{"question":"聴講","answers":["ちょうこう"],"comment":"(n) lecture attendance/auditing"},
	{"question":"職","answers":["しょく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) employment"},
	{"question":"職人","answers":["しょくにん"],"comment":"(n) worker/mechanic/artisan/craftsman"},
	{"question":"職務","answers":["しょくむ"],"comment":"(n) professional duties"},
	{"question":"職員","answers":["しょくいん"],"comment":"(n) staff member/personnel"},
	{"question":"職場","answers":["しょくば"],"comment":"(n) one's post/place of work/workplace"},
	{"question":"職業","answers":["しょくぎょう"],"comment":"(n) occupation/business"},
	{"question":"肉","answers":["にく"],"comment":"(n) meat"},
	{"question":"肉体","answers":["にくたい"],"comment":"(n) the body/the flesh"},
	{"question":"肉親","answers":["にくしん"],"comment":"(n) blood relationship/blood relative"},
	{"question":"肌","answers":["はだ"],"comment":"(n) skin/body/grain/texture/disposition"},
	{"question":"肌着","answers":["はだぎ"],"comment":"(n) underwear/lingerie/singlet/chemise"},
	{"question":"肘","answers":["ひじ"],"comment":"(n) (uk) elbow"},
	{"question":"肝心","answers":["かんじん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) essential/fundamental/crucial/vital/main"},
	{"question":"肝腎","answers":["かんじん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) essential/fundamental/crucial/vital/main"},
	{"question":"股","answers":["また","もも"],"comment":"(n) thigh/femur"},
	{"question":"肩","answers":["かた"],"comment":"(n) shoulder"},
	{"question":"肯定","answers":["こうてい"],"comment":"(n) positive/affirmation"},
	{"question":"育ち","answers":["そだち"],"comment":"(n) breeding/growth"},
	{"question":"育つ","answers":["そだつ"],"comment":"(v5t,vi) to raise (child)/to be brought up/to grow (up)"},
	{"question":"育てる","answers":["そだてる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to raise/to rear/to bring up"},
	{"question":"育児","answers":["いくじ"],"comment":"(n) childcare/nursing/upbringing"},
	{"question":"育成","answers":["いくせい"],"comment":"(n) rearing/training/nurture/cultivation/promotion"},
	{"question":"肺","answers":["はい"],"comment":"(n) lung"},
	{"question":"胃","answers":["い"],"comment":"(n) stomach"},
	{"question":"背","answers":["せ","せい"],"comment":"(n) height/stature"},
	{"question":"背く","answers":["そむく"],"comment":"(v5k) to run counter to/to go against/to disobey/to infringe"},
	{"question":"背中","answers":["せなか"],"comment":"(n) back (of body)"},
	{"question":"背広","answers":["せびろ"],"comment":"(n) business suit"},
	{"question":"背後","answers":["はいご"],"comment":"(n) back/rear"},
	{"question":"背景","answers":["はいけい"],"comment":"(n) background/scenery/setting/circumstance"},
	{"question":"背負う","answers":["せおう"],"comment":"(v5u) to be burdened with/to carry on back or shoulder"},
	{"question":"胡椒","answers":["こしょう"],"comment":"(n) pepper"},
	{"question":"胴","answers":["どう"],"comment":"(n) trunk/body/frame"},
	{"question":"胸","answers":["むね"],"comment":"(n) breast/chest"},
	{"question":"能","answers":["のう"],"comment":"(adv,n,vs) being skilled in/nicely/properly/well/skillfully/thoroughly"},
	{"question":"能力","answers":["のうりょく"],"comment":"(n) ability/faculty"},
	{"question":"能率","answers":["のうりつ"],"comment":"(n) efficiency"},
	{"question":"脂","answers":["あぶら"],"comment":"(n) nicotine/resin/sleep in one's eyes (eye mucus)"},
	{"question":"脂肪","answers":["しぼう"],"comment":"(n) fat/grease/blubber"},
	{"question":"脅かす","answers":["おびやかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to threaten/to coerce"},
	{"question":"脅迫","answers":["きょうはく"],"comment":"(n) threat/menace/coercion/terrorism"},
	{"question":"脆い","answers":["もろい"],"comment":"(adj) brittle/fragile/tender-hearted"},
	{"question":"脇","answers":["わき"],"comment":"(n) side"},
	{"question":"脈","answers":["みゃく"],"comment":"(n) pulse"},
	{"question":"脚本","answers":["きゃくほん"],"comment":"(n) scenario"},
	{"question":"脚色","answers":["きゃくしょく"],"comment":"(n) dramatization (e.g. film)"},
	{"question":"脱ぐ","answers":["ぬぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to take off clothes"},
	{"question":"脱する","answers":["だっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to escape from/to get out"},
	{"question":"脱出","answers":["だっしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) escape"},
	{"question":"脱線","answers":["だっせん"],"comment":"(n,vs) derailment/digression"},
	{"question":"脱退","answers":["だったい"],"comment":"(n,vs) secession/retirement/withdrawal (e.g. from a lawsuit)"},
	{"question":"脳","answers":["のう"],"comment":"(n) brain/memory"},
	{"question":"腐る","answers":["くさる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rot/to go bad"},
	{"question":"腐敗","answers":["ふはい"],"comment":"(n) decay/depravity"},
	{"question":"腕","answers":["うで"],"comment":"(n) (1) arm/(2) skill"},
	{"question":"腕前","answers":["うでまえ"],"comment":"(n) ability/skill/facility"},
	{"question":"腫れる","answers":["はれる"],"comment":"(v1) to swell (from inflammation)/to become swollen"},
	{"question":"腰","answers":["こし"],"comment":"(n) hip"},
	{"question":"腰掛け","answers":["こしかけ"],"comment":"(n) seat/bench"},
	{"question":"腰掛ける","answers":["こしかける"],"comment":"(v1) to sit (down)"},
	{"question":"腸","answers":["ちょう"],"comment":"(n) guts/bowels/intestines"},
	{"question":"腹","answers":["はら"],"comment":"(n) abdomen/belly/stomach"},
	{"question":"腹立ち","answers":["はらだち"],"comment":"(n) anger"},
	{"question":"腿","answers":["もも"],"comment":"(n) thigh/femur"},
	{"question":"膜","answers":["まく"],"comment":"(n) membrane/film"},
	{"question":"膝","answers":["ひざ"],"comment":"(n) knee/lap"},
	{"question":"膨らます","answers":["ふくらます"],"comment":"(v5s) to swell/to expand/to inflate/to bulge"},
	{"question":"膨らむ","answers":["ふくらむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to expand/to swell (out)/to get big/to become inflated"},
	{"question":"膨れる","answers":["ふくれる"],"comment":"(v1) to get cross/to get sulky/to swell (out)/to expand/to be inflated/to distend/to bulge"},
	{"question":"膨大","answers":["ぼうだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) huge/bulky/enormous/extensive/swelling/expansion"},
	{"question":"膨張","answers":["ぼうちょう"],"comment":"(n) expansion/swelling/increase/growth"},
	{"question":"膳","answers":["ぜん"],"comment":"(n) (small) table/tray/meal"},
	{"question":"臆病","answers":["おくびょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) cowardice/timidity"},
	{"question":"臨む","answers":["のぞむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to look out on/to face/to deal with/to attend (function)"},
	{"question":"臨時","answers":["りんじ"],"comment":"(n) temporary/special/extraordinary"},
	{"question":"自ずから","answers":["おのずから"],"comment":"(adv) naturally/as a matter of course"},
	{"question":"自ら","answers":["みずから"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) for one's self/personally"},
	{"question":"自主","answers":["じしゅ"],"comment":"(n) independence/autonomy"},
	{"question":"自分","answers":["じぶん"],"comment":"(n) myself/oneself"},
	{"question":"自動","answers":["じどう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) automatic/self-motion"},
	{"question":"自動車","answers":["じどうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) automobile"},
	{"question":"自在","answers":["じざい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) freely/at will"},
	{"question":"自宅","answers":["じたく"],"comment":"(n) one's home"},
	{"question":"自尊心","answers":["じそんしん"],"comment":"(n) self-respect/conceit"},
	{"question":"自己","answers":["じこ"],"comment":"(n) self/oneself"},
	{"question":"自慢","answers":["じまん"],"comment":"(n,vs) pride/boast"},
	{"question":"自我","answers":["じが"],"comment":"(n) self/the ego"},
	{"question":"自殺","answers":["じさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) suicide"},
	{"question":"自治","answers":["じち"],"comment":"(n) self-government/autonomy"},
	{"question":"自然","answers":["しぜん"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) nature/spontaneous"},
	{"question":"自然科学","answers":["しぜんかがく"],"comment":"natural science"},
	{"question":"自由","answers":["じゆう"],"comment":"(adj-na,exp,n) freedom/liberty/as it pleases you"},
	{"question":"自立","answers":["じりつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) independence/self-reliance"},
	{"question":"自習","answers":["じしゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) self-study"},
	{"question":"自衛","answers":["じえい"],"comment":"(n) self-defense"},
	{"question":"自覚","answers":["じかく"],"comment":"(n) self-conscious"},
	{"question":"自身","answers":["じしん"],"comment":"(n) by oneself/personally"},
	{"question":"自転","answers":["じてん"],"comment":"(n) rotation/spin"},
	{"question":"自転車","answers":["じてんしゃ"],"comment":"(n) bicycle"},
	{"question":"自首","answers":["じしゅ"],"comment":"(n,vs) surrender/give oneself up"},
	{"question":"臭い","answers":["くさい"],"comment":"(n) odour/scent/smell/stench/fragrance/aroma/perfume"},
	{"question":"至る","answers":["いたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to come/to arrive"},
	{"question":"至急","answers":["しきゅう"],"comment":"(adv,n) urgent/pressing"},
	{"question":"致す","answers":["いたす"],"comment":"(v5s) (hum) to do"},
	{"question":"興じる","answers":["きょうじる"],"comment":"(v1) to amuse oneself/to make merry"},
	{"question":"興味","answers":["きょうみ"],"comment":"(n) interest (in something)"},
	{"question":"興奮","answers":["こうふん"],"comment":"(n,vs) excitement/stimulation/agitation/arousal"},
	{"question":"興業","answers":["こうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) industrial enterprise"},
	{"question":"舌","answers":["した"],"comment":"(n) tongue"},
	{"question":"舗装","answers":["ほそう"],"comment":"(n) pavement/road surface"},
	{"question":"舞う","answers":["まう"],"comment":"(v5u,vi) to dance/to flutter about/to revolve"},
	{"question":"舞台","answers":["ぶたい"],"comment":"(n) stage (theatre)"},
	{"question":"舟","answers":["ふね"],"comment":"(n) ship/boat/watercraft/shipping/vessel/steamship"},
	{"question":"航海","answers":["こうかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) sail/voyage"},
	{"question":"航空","answers":["こうくう"],"comment":"(n) aviation/flying"},
	{"question":"船","answers":["ふね"],"comment":"(n) ship/boat/watercraft/shipping/vessel/steamship"},
	{"question":"船便","answers":["ふなびん"],"comment":"(n) surface mail (ship)"},
	{"question":"船舶","answers":["せんぱく"],"comment":"(n) ship"},
	{"question":"良い","answers":["よい"],"comment":"(adj) good/nice/pleasant/ok"},
	{"question":"良し","answers":["よし"],"comment":"OK!/all right!"},
	{"question":"良好","answers":["りょうこう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) favorable/satisfactory"},
	{"question":"良心","answers":["りょうしん"],"comment":"(n) conscience"},
	{"question":"良識","answers":["りょうしき"],"comment":"(n) good sense"},
	{"question":"良質","answers":["りょうしつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) good quality/superior quality"},
	{"question":"色","answers":["いろ"],"comment":"(n) (1) colour/(2) sensuality/lust"},
	{"question":"色彩","answers":["しきさい"],"comment":"(n) colour/hue/tints"},
	{"question":"艶","answers":["つや"],"comment":"(n) gloss/glaze"},
	{"question":"芝","answers":["しば"],"comment":"(n) lawn/sod/turf"},
	{"question":"芝居","answers":["しばい"],"comment":"(n) play/drama"},
	{"question":"芝生","answers":["しばふ"],"comment":"(n) lawn"},
	{"question":"芯","answers":["しん"],"comment":"(n) core/heart/wick/marrow"},
	{"question":"花","answers":["はな"],"comment":"(n) flower"},
	{"question":"花びら","answers":["はなびら"],"comment":"(n) (flower) petal"},
	{"question":"花壇","answers":["かだん"],"comment":"(n) flower bed"},
	{"question":"花嫁","answers":["はなよめ"],"comment":"(n) bride"},
	{"question":"花火","answers":["はなび"],"comment":"(n) fireworks"},
	{"question":"花瓶","answers":["かびん"],"comment":"(n) (flower) vase"},
	{"question":"花粉","answers":["かふん"],"comment":"(n) pollen"},
	{"question":"花見","answers":["はなみ"],"comment":"(n,vs) cherry-blossom viewing/flower viewing"},
	{"question":"芸","answers":["げい"],"comment":"(n) art/accomplishment/performance"},
	{"question":"芸能","answers":["げいのう"],"comment":"(n) public entertainment/accomplishments/attainments"},
	{"question":"芸術","answers":["げいじゅつ"],"comment":"(n) (fine) art/the arts"},
	{"question":"芽","answers":["め"],"comment":"(n) sprout"},
	{"question":"苗","answers":["なえ"],"comment":"(n) rice seedling"},
	{"question":"若々しい","answers":["わかわかしい"],"comment":"(adj) youthful/young"},
	{"question":"若い","answers":["わかい"],"comment":"(adj) young"},
	{"question":"若干","answers":["じゃっかん"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) some/few/number of"},
	{"question":"苦い","answers":["にがい"],"comment":"(adj) bitter"},
	{"question":"苦しい","answers":["くるしい"],"comment":"(adj) painful/difficult"},
	{"question":"苦しむ","answers":["くるしむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to suffer/to groan/to be worried"},
	{"question":"苦労","answers":["くろう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) troubles/hardships"},
	{"question":"苦心","answers":["くしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) pain/trouble/anxiety/diligence/hard work"},
	{"question":"苦情","answers":["くじょう"],"comment":"(n) complaint/troubles/objection"},
	{"question":"苦手","answers":["にがて"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) poor (at)/weak (in)/dislike (of)"},
	{"question":"苦痛","answers":["くつう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pain/agony"},
	{"question":"英和","answers":["えいわ"],"comment":"(n) English-Japanese (e.g. dictionary)"},
	{"question":"英字","answers":["えいじ"],"comment":"(n) English letter (character)"},
	{"question":"英文","answers":["えいぶん"],"comment":"(n) sentence in English"},
	{"question":"英語","answers":["えいご"],"comment":"(n) the English language"},
	{"question":"英雄","answers":["えいゆう"],"comment":"(n) hero/great man"},
	{"question":"茂る","answers":["しげる"],"comment":"(v5r) to grow thick/to luxuriate/to be luxurious"},
	{"question":"茎","answers":["くき"],"comment":"(n) stalk"},
	{"question":"茶","answers":["ちゃ"],"comment":"(n) tea"},
	{"question":"茶の湯","answers":["ちゃのゆ"],"comment":"(n) tea ceremony"},
	{"question":"茶の間","answers":["ちゃのま"],"comment":"(n) living room (Japanese style)"},
	{"question":"茶碗","answers":["ちゃわん"],"comment":"(n) rice bowl/tea cup/teacup"},
	{"question":"茶色","answers":["ちゃいろ"],"comment":"(n) light brown/tawny"},
	{"question":"草","answers":["くさ"],"comment":"(n) grass"},
	{"question":"草履","answers":["ぞうり"],"comment":"(n) zoori (Japanese footwear)/sandals"},
	{"question":"荒い","answers":["あらい"],"comment":"(adj) rough/rude/wild"},
	{"question":"荒っぽい","answers":["あらっぽい"],"comment":"(adj) rough/rude"},
	{"question":"荒らす","answers":["あらす"],"comment":"(v5s) (1) to lay waste/to devastate/to damage/(2) to invade/to break into"},
	{"question":"荒れる","answers":["あれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be stormy/to be rough/to lose one's temper"},
	{"question":"荒廃","answers":["こうはい"],"comment":"(n,vs) ruin"},
	{"question":"荷","answers":["に"],"comment":"(n) load/baggage/cargo"},
	{"question":"荷物","answers":["にもつ"],"comment":"(n) luggage"},
	{"question":"荷造り","answers":["にづくり"],"comment":"(n,vs) packing/baling/crating"},
	{"question":"莫大","answers":["ばくだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) enormous/vast"},
	{"question":"菌","answers":["きん"],"comment":"(n) germ/bacterium/bacillus"},
	{"question":"菓子","answers":["かし"],"comment":"(n) pastry"},
	{"question":"華々しい","answers":["はなばなしい"],"comment":"(adj) brilliant/magnificent/spectacular"},
	{"question":"華やか","answers":["はなやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) gay/showy/brilliant/gorgeous/florid"},
	{"question":"華奢","answers":["きゃしゃ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) luxury/pomp/delicate/slender/gorgeous"},
	{"question":"萎びる","answers":["しなびる"],"comment":"(v1) to wilt/to fade"},
	{"question":"落し物","answers":["おとしもの"],"comment":"(n) lost property"},
	{"question":"落す","answers":["おとす"],"comment":"(io) (v5s) to drop/to lose/to let fall"},
	{"question":"落ち着き","answers":["おちつき"],"comment":"(n) calm/composure"},
	{"question":"落ち込む","answers":["おちこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to fall into/to feel down (sad)"},
	{"question":"落下","answers":["らっか"],"comment":"(n,vs) fall/drop/come down"},
	{"question":"落着く","answers":["おちつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to calm down/to settle down/to be steady/to settle in/to take up one's residence/to harmonize with/to match/to restore presence of mind"},
	{"question":"落第","answers":["らくだい"],"comment":"(n,vs) failure/dropping out of a class"},
	{"question":"落葉","answers":["おちば"],"comment":"(n,vs) fallen leaves/leaf litter/defoliation/shedding leaves"},
	{"question":"葉","answers":["は"],"comment":"(n) leaf"},
	{"question":"葉書","answers":["はがき"],"comment":"(n) postcard"},
	{"question":"著しい","answers":["いちじるしい"],"comment":"(adj) remarkable/considerable"},
	{"question":"著す","answers":["あらわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to write/to publish"},
	{"question":"著名","answers":["ちょめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) well-known/noted/celebrated"},
	{"question":"著書","answers":["ちょしょ"],"comment":"(n) literary work/book"},
	{"question":"著者","answers":["ちょしゃ"],"comment":"(n) author/writer"},
	{"question":"葬る","answers":["ほうむる"],"comment":"(v5r) to bury/to inter/to entomb/to consign to oblivion/to shelve"},
	{"question":"葬式","answers":["そうしき"],"comment":"(n) funeral"},
	{"question":"蒔く","answers":["まく"],"comment":"(v5k) to sow (seeds)"},
	{"question":"蒸し暑い","answers":["むしあつい"],"comment":"(adj) humid/sultry"},
	{"question":"蒸す","answers":["むす"],"comment":"(v5s) to steam/to poultice/to be sultry"},
	{"question":"蒸気","answers":["じょうき"],"comment":"(n) steam/vapour"},
	{"question":"蒸溜","answers":["じょうりゅう"],"comment":"(n) distillation"},
	{"question":"蒸発","answers":["じょうはつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) evaporation/unexplained disappearance"},
	{"question":"蓄える","answers":["たくわえる"],"comment":"(v1) to store/to lay in stock"},
	{"question":"蓄積","answers":["ちくせき"],"comment":"(n,vs) accumulation/accumulate/store"},
	{"question":"蓋","answers":["ふた"],"comment":"(n) cover/lid/cap"},
	{"question":"蔵","answers":["くら"],"comment":"(n) warehouse/cellar/magazine/granary/godown/depository/treasury/elevator"},
	{"question":"蔵相","answers":["ぞうしょう"],"comment":"(n) Minister of Finance"},
	{"question":"蕎麦","answers":["そば"],"comment":"(n) soba (buckwheat noodles)"},
	{"question":"蕾","answers":["つぼみ"],"comment":"(n) bud/flower bud"},
	{"question":"薄い","answers":["うすい"],"comment":"(adj) thin/weak/watery/diluted"},
	{"question":"薄める","answers":["うすめる"],"comment":"(v1) to dilute/to water down"},
	{"question":"薄弱","answers":["はくじゃく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) feebleness/weakness/weak"},
	{"question":"薄暗い","answers":["うすぐらい"],"comment":"(adj) dim/gloomy"},
	{"question":"薬","answers":["くすり"],"comment":"(n) medicine"},
	{"question":"薬品","answers":["やくひん"],"comment":"(n) medicine(s)/chemical(s)"},
	{"question":"薬局","answers":["やっきょく"],"comment":"(n) pharmacy/drugstore"},
	{"question":"薬指","answers":["くすりゆび"],"comment":"(n) ring finger"},
	{"question":"薬缶","answers":["やかん"],"comment":"(n) kettle"},
	{"question":"藁","answers":["わら"],"comment":"(n) straw"},
	{"question":"蘇る","answers":["よみがえる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be resurrected/to be revived/to be resuscitated/to be rehabilitated"},
	{"question":"虎","answers":["とら"],"comment":"(n) tiger"},
	{"question":"虫","answers":["むし"],"comment":"(n) insect"},
	{"question":"虫歯","answers":["むしば"],"comment":"(n) cavity/tooth decay/decayed tooth/caries"},
	{"question":"虹","answers":["にじ"],"comment":"(n) rainbow"},
	{"question":"蚊","answers":["か"],"comment":"(n) mosquito"},
	{"question":"蛇口","answers":["じゃぐち"],"comment":"(n) faucet/tap"},
	{"question":"蛋白質","answers":["たんぱくしつ"],"comment":"(n) protein"},
	{"question":"蛍光灯","answers":["けいこうとう"],"comment":"(n) fluorescent lamp/person who is slow to react"},
	{"question":"蜂蜜","answers":["はちみつ"],"comment":"(n) honey"},
	{"question":"蝋燭","answers":["ろうそく"],"comment":"(n) (uk) candle"},
	{"question":"蝶","answers":["ちょう"],"comment":"(n) butterfly"},
	{"question":"融資","answers":["ゆうし"],"comment":"(n) financing/loan"},
	{"question":"融通","answers":["ゆうずう"],"comment":"(n,vs) lending (money)/accommodation/adaptability/versatility/finance"},
	{"question":"血","answers":["ち"],"comment":"(n) blood/consanguinity"},
	{"question":"血圧","answers":["けつあつ"],"comment":"(n) blood pressure"},
	{"question":"血液","answers":["けつえき"],"comment":"(n) blood"},
	{"question":"血管","answers":["けっかん"],"comment":"(n) blood vessel"},
	{"question":"衆","answers":["しゅう"],"comment":"(n) masses/great number/the people"},
	{"question":"衆議院","answers":["しゅうぎいん"],"comment":"(n) Lower House/House of Representatives"},
	{"question":"行い","answers":["おこない"],"comment":"(io) (n) deed/conduct/behavior/action/asceticism"},
	{"question":"行う","answers":["おこなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to perform/to do/to conduct oneself/to carry out"},
	{"question":"行き","answers":["いき","ゆき"],"comment":"(n) going"},
	{"question":"行き違い","answers":["いきちがい"],"comment":"(n) misunderstanding/estrangement/disagreement/crossing without meeting/going astray"},
	{"question":"行く","answers":["いく","ゆく"],"comment":"(v5k-s) to go"},
	{"question":"行事","answers":["ぎょうじ"],"comment":"(n) event/function"},
	{"question":"行儀","answers":["ぎょうぎ"],"comment":"(n) manners"},
	{"question":"行列","answers":["ぎょうれつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) line/procession/(2) matrix (math)"},
	{"question":"行動","answers":["こうどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) action/conduct/behaviour/mobilization"},
	{"question":"行政","answers":["ぎょうせい"],"comment":"(n) administration"},
	{"question":"行方","answers":["ゆくえ"],"comment":"(n) one's whereabouts"},
	{"question":"行為","answers":["こうい"],"comment":"(n) act/deed/conduct"},
	{"question":"行進","answers":["こうしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) march/parade"},
	{"question":"街","answers":["まち"],"comment":"(n) (1) town/(2) street/road"},
	{"question":"街角","answers":["まちかど"],"comment":"(n) street corner"},
	{"question":"街道","answers":["かいどう"],"comment":"(n) highway"},
	{"question":"街頭","answers":["がいとう"],"comment":"(n) in the street"},
	{"question":"衛星","answers":["えいせい"],"comment":"(n) satellite"},
	{"question":"衝撃","answers":["しょうげき"],"comment":"(n) shock/crash/impact/ballistic"},
	{"question":"衝突","answers":["しょうとつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) collision/conflict"},
	{"question":"衣料","answers":["いりょう"],"comment":"(n) clothing"},
	{"question":"衣服","answers":["いふく"],"comment":"(n) clothes"},
	{"question":"衣装","answers":["いしょう"],"comment":"(n) clothing/costume/outfit/garment/dress"},
	{"question":"衣類","answers":["いるい"],"comment":"(n) clothes/clothing/garments"},
	{"question":"衣食住","answers":["いしょくじゅう"],"comment":"(n) necessities of life (food, clothing, etc.)"},
	{"question":"表","answers":["おもて","ひょう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) table (e.g. Tab 1)/chart/list"},
	{"question":"表す","answers":["あらわす"],"comment":"(v5s) to express/to show/to reveal"},
	{"question":"表情","answers":["ひょうじょう"],"comment":"(n) facial expression"},
	{"question":"表現","answers":["ひょうげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) expression/presentation/representation (math)"},
	{"question":"表紙","answers":["ひょうし"],"comment":"(n) front cover/binding"},
	{"question":"表面","answers":["ひょうめん"],"comment":"(n) surface/outside/face/appearance"},
	{"question":"衰える","answers":["おとろえる"],"comment":"(v1) to become weak/to decline/to wear/to abate/to decay/to wither/to waste away"},
	{"question":"袋","answers":["ふくろ"],"comment":"(n) bag/sack"},
	{"question":"袖","answers":["そで"],"comment":"(n) sleeve"},
	{"question":"被せる","answers":["かぶせる"],"comment":"(v1) to cover (with something)/to plate something (with a metal)/to pour or dash a liquid (on something)/to charge (a person with a guilt)"},
	{"question":"被る","answers":["かぶる"],"comment":"(v5r) to suffer"},
	{"question":"被害","answers":["ひがい"],"comment":"(n) damage"},
	{"question":"裁く","answers":["さばく"],"comment":"(v5k) to judge"},
	{"question":"裁判","answers":["さいばん"],"comment":"(n,vs) trial/judgement"},
	{"question":"裁縫","answers":["さいほう"],"comment":"(n) sewing"},
	{"question":"裂く","answers":["さく"],"comment":"(v5k) to tear/to split"},
	{"question":"裂ける","answers":["さける"],"comment":"(v1) to split/to tear/to burst"},
	{"question":"装備","answers":["そうび"],"comment":"(n) equipment"},
	{"question":"装置","answers":["そうち"],"comment":"(n,vs) equipment/installation/apparatus"},
	{"question":"装飾","answers":["そうしょく"],"comment":"(n) ornament"},
	{"question":"裏","answers":["うら"],"comment":"(n) reverse side/wrong side/back/undersurface/inside/palm/sole/opposite/rear/lining/last half (of an inning)"},
	{"question":"裏切る","answers":["うらぎる"],"comment":"(v5r) to betray/to turn traitor to/to double-cross"},
	{"question":"裏口","answers":["うらぐち"],"comment":"(n) backdoor/rear entrance"},
	{"question":"裏返し","answers":["うらがえし"],"comment":"(n) inside out/upside down"},
	{"question":"裏返す","answers":["うらがえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to turn inside out/to turn the other way/to turn (something) over"},
	{"question":"補う","answers":["おぎなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to compensate for"},
	{"question":"補償","answers":["ほしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) compensation/reparation"},
	{"question":"補充","answers":["ほじゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) supplementation/supplement/replenishment/replenishing"},
	{"question":"補助","answers":["ほじょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) assistance/support/aid/auxiliary"},
	{"question":"補強","answers":["ほきょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) compensation/reinforcement"},
	{"question":"補給","answers":["ほきゅう"],"comment":"(n) supply/supplying/replenishment"},
	{"question":"補足","answers":["ほそく"],"comment":"(n) supplement/complement"},
	{"question":"裸","answers":["はだか"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) naked/nude/bare"},
	{"question":"裸足","answers":["はだし"],"comment":"(n) barefoot"},
	{"question":"製作","answers":["せいさく"],"comment":"(n,vs) manufacture/production"},
	{"question":"製品","answers":["せいひん"],"comment":"(n) manufactured goods/finished goods"},
	{"question":"製法","answers":["せいほう"],"comment":"(n) manufacturing method/recipe/formula"},
	{"question":"製造","answers":["せいぞう"],"comment":"(n,vs) manufacture/production"},
	{"question":"製鉄","answers":["せいてつ"],"comment":"(n) iron manufacture"},
	{"question":"裾","answers":["すそ"],"comment":"(n) (trouser) cuff/(skirt) hem/cut edge of a hairdo/foot of mountain"},
	{"question":"複写","answers":["ふくしゃ"],"comment":"(n) copy/duplicate"},
	{"question":"複合","answers":["ふくごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) composite/complex"},
	{"question":"複数","answers":["ふくすう"],"comment":"(n) plural/multiple"},
	{"question":"複雑","answers":["ふくざつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) complexity/complication"},
	{"question":"褒める","answers":["ほめる"],"comment":"(v1) to praise/to admire/to speak well"},
	{"question":"褒美","answers":["ほうび"],"comment":"(n) reward/prize"},
	{"question":"襖","answers":["ふすま"],"comment":"(n) sliding screen"},
	{"question":"襟","answers":["えり"],"comment":"(n) neck/collar/lapel/neckband"},
	{"question":"襲う","answers":["おそう"],"comment":"(v5u) to attack"},
	{"question":"襲撃","answers":["しゅうげき"],"comment":"(n) attack/charge/raid"},
	{"question":"西","answers":["にし"],"comment":"(n) west"},
	{"question":"西日","answers":["にしび"],"comment":"(n) westering sun"},
	{"question":"西暦","answers":["せいれき"],"comment":"(n) Christian Era/anno domini (A.D.)"},
	{"question":"西洋","answers":["せいよう"],"comment":"(n) the west/Western countries"},
	{"question":"要する","answers":["ようする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to demand/to require/to take"},
	{"question":"要するに","answers":["ようするに"],"comment":"(adv,exp) in a word/after all/the point is ../in short .."},
	{"question":"要る","answers":["いる"],"comment":"(v5r) to need"},
	{"question":"要因","answers":["よういん"],"comment":"(n) primary factor/main cause"},
	{"question":"要旨","answers":["ようし"],"comment":"(n) gist/essentials/summary/fundamentals"},
	{"question":"要望","answers":["ようぼう"],"comment":"(n) demand for/request"},
	{"question":"要求","answers":["ようきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) request/demand/requisition"},
	{"question":"要点","answers":["ようてん"],"comment":"(n) gist/main point"},
	{"question":"要素","answers":["ようそ"],"comment":"(n) element"},
	{"question":"要請","answers":["ようせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) claim/demand/request/application"},
	{"question":"要領","answers":["ようりょう"],"comment":"(n) point/gist/essentials/outline"},
	{"question":"覆う","answers":["おおう"],"comment":"(v5u) to cover/to hide/to conceal/to wrap/to disguise"},
	{"question":"覆す","answers":["くつがえす"],"comment":"(v5s) to overturn/to upset/to overthrow/to undermine"},
	{"question":"覆面","answers":["ふくめん"],"comment":"(n) mask/veil/disguise"},
	{"question":"見える","answers":["みえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be seen/to be in sight/to look/to seem/to appear"},
	{"question":"見せびらかす","answers":["みせびらかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to show off/to flaunt"},
	{"question":"見せる","answers":["みせる"],"comment":"(v1) to show/to display"},
	{"question":"見せ物","answers":["みせもの"],"comment":"(n) show/exhibition"},
	{"question":"見つかる","answers":["みつかる"],"comment":"(v5r) (uk) to be found/to be discovered"},
	{"question":"見つける","answers":["みつける"],"comment":"(v1) to be familiar/to discover/to find fault/to detect/to find out/to locate"},
	{"question":"見る","answers":["みる"],"comment":"(v1) to see/to watch"},
	{"question":"見上げる","answers":["みあげる"],"comment":"(v1) to look up at/to raise one's eyes/to admire"},
	{"question":"見下ろす","answers":["みおろす"],"comment":"(v5s) to overlook/to command a view of/to look down on something"},
	{"question":"見事","answers":["みごと"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) splendid/magnificent/beautiful/admirable"},
	{"question":"見付かる","answers":["みつかる"],"comment":"(v5r) (uk) to be found/to be discovered"},
	{"question":"見付ける","answers":["みつける"],"comment":"(v1) to be familiar/to discover/to find fault/to detect/to find out/to locate"},
	{"question":"見出し","answers":["みだし"],"comment":"(n) heading/caption/subtitle/index"},
	{"question":"見合い","answers":["みあい"],"comment":"(n) formal marriage interview"},
	{"question":"見合わせる","answers":["みあわせる"],"comment":"(v1) to exchange glances/to postpone/to suspend operations/to refrain from performing an action"},
	{"question":"見地","answers":["けんち"],"comment":"(n) point of view"},
	{"question":"見学","answers":["けんがく"],"comment":"(n,vs) inspection/study by observation/field trip"},
	{"question":"見当","answers":["けんとう"],"comment":"(n) be found/aim/mark/estimate/guess/approx/direction"},
	{"question":"見慣れる","answers":["みなれる"],"comment":"(v1) to become used to seeing/to be familiar with"},
	{"question":"見掛け","answers":["みかけ"],"comment":"(n) outward appearance"},
	{"question":"見掛ける","answers":["みかける"],"comment":"(v1) to (happen to) see/to notice/to catch sight of"},
	{"question":"見晴らし","answers":["みはらし"],"comment":"(n) view"},
	{"question":"見本","answers":["みほん"],"comment":"(n) sample"},
	{"question":"見渡す","answers":["みわたす"],"comment":"(v5s) to look out over/to survey (scene)/to take an extensive view of"},
	{"question":"見物","answers":["けんぶつ"],"comment":"(n) a sight/an attraction/something worth seeing"},
	{"question":"見直す","answers":["みなおす"],"comment":"(v5s) to look again/to get a better opinion of"},
	{"question":"見積もり","answers":["みつもり"],"comment":"(n) estimation/quotation"},
	{"question":"見習う","answers":["みならう"],"comment":"(v5u) to follow another's example"},
	{"question":"見舞い","answers":["みまい"],"comment":"(n) enquiry/expression of sympathy/expression of concern"},
	{"question":"見舞う","answers":["みまう"],"comment":"(v5u) to ask after (health)/to visit"},
	{"question":"見苦しい","answers":["みぐるしい"],"comment":"(adj) unsightly/ugly"},
	{"question":"見落とす","answers":["みおとす"],"comment":"(v5s) to overlook/to fail to notice"},
	{"question":"見解","answers":["けんかい"],"comment":"(n) opinion/point of view"},
	{"question":"見計らう","answers":["みはからう"],"comment":"(v5u) to choose at one's own discretion"},
	{"question":"見詰める","answers":["みつめる"],"comment":"(v1) (uk) to stare at/to gaze at/to look hard at/to watch intently/to fix one's eyes on"},
	{"question":"見込み","answers":["みこみ"],"comment":"(n) forecast/prospects/expectation/hope"},
	{"question":"見送り","answers":["みおくり"],"comment":"(n) seeing one off/farewell/escort"},
	{"question":"見送る","answers":["みおくる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to see off/to farewell/(2) to escort/(3) to let pass/to wait and see/(4) to let a pitch go by (baseball)/to watch a batted ball go into the stands"},
	{"question":"見逃す","answers":["みのがす"],"comment":"(v5s) to miss/to overlook/to leave at large"},
	{"question":"見通し","answers":["みとおし"],"comment":"(n) perspective/unobstructed view/outlook/forecast/prospect/insight"},
	{"question":"規制","answers":["きせい"],"comment":"(n) regulation"},
	{"question":"規則","answers":["きそく"],"comment":"(n) rule/regulations"},
	{"question":"規定","answers":["きてい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n,vs) regulation/provisions"},
	{"question":"規律","answers":["きりつ"],"comment":"(n) order/rules/law"},
	{"question":"規格","answers":["きかく"],"comment":"(n) standard/norm"},
	{"question":"規模","answers":["きぼ"],"comment":"(n) scale/scope/plan/structure"},
	{"question":"規準","answers":["きじゅん"],"comment":"(n) standard/basis/criteria/norm"},
	{"question":"規範","answers":["きはん"],"comment":"(n) model/standard/pattern/norm/criterion/example"},
	{"question":"規約","answers":["きやく"],"comment":"(n) agreement/rules/code"},
	{"question":"視察","answers":["しさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) inspection/observation"},
	{"question":"視点","answers":["してん"],"comment":"(n) opinion/point of view/visual point"},
	{"question":"視覚","answers":["しかく"],"comment":"(n) sense of sight/vision"},
	{"question":"視野","answers":["しや"],"comment":"(n) field of vision/outlook"},
	{"question":"覗く","answers":["のぞく"],"comment":"(v5k) to peep in/to look in/to peek in/to stick out"},
	{"question":"覚え","answers":["おぼえ"],"comment":"(n) memory/sense/experience"},
	{"question":"覚える","answers":["おぼえる"],"comment":"(v1) to remember/to memorize"},
	{"question":"覚ます","answers":["さます"],"comment":"(v5s) to awaken"},
	{"question":"覚める","answers":["さめる"],"comment":"(v1) to wake/to wake up"},
	{"question":"覚悟","answers":["かくご"],"comment":"(n,vs) resolution/resignation/readiness/preparedness"},
	{"question":"親","answers":["おや"],"comment":"(n) parents"},
	{"question":"親しい","answers":["したしい"],"comment":"(adj) intimate/close (e.g. friend)"},
	{"question":"親しむ","answers":["したしむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be intimate with/to befriend"},
	{"question":"親切","answers":["しんせつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) kindness/gentleness"},
	{"question":"親友","answers":["しんゆう"],"comment":"(n) close friend/bosom (old, intimate) friend/buddy/crony/chum"},
	{"question":"親善","answers":["しんぜん"],"comment":"(n) friendship"},
	{"question":"親戚","answers":["しんせき"],"comment":"(n) relative"},
	{"question":"親指","answers":["おやゆび"],"comment":"(n) thumb"},
	{"question":"親父","answers":["おやじ"],"comment":"(gikun) (n) one's father/old man/one's boss"},
	{"question":"親類","answers":["しんるい"],"comment":"(n) relation/kin"},
	{"question":"観光","answers":["かんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) sightseeing"},
	{"question":"観客","answers":["かんきゃく"],"comment":"(n) audience/spectator(s)"},
	{"question":"観察","answers":["かんさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) observation/survey"},
	{"question":"観念","answers":["かんねん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (1) idea/notion/conception/(2) sense (e.g. of duty)/(3) resignation/preparedness/acceptance"},
	{"question":"観測","answers":["かんそく"],"comment":"(n,vs) observation"},
	{"question":"観点","answers":["かんてん"],"comment":"(n) point of view"},
	{"question":"観衆","answers":["かんしゅう"],"comment":"(n) spectators/onlookers/members of the audience"},
	{"question":"観覧","answers":["かんらん"],"comment":"(n) viewing"},
	{"question":"角","answers":["かく","かど","すみ","つの"],"comment":"(n) horn"},
	{"question":"角度","answers":["かくど"],"comment":"(n) angle"},
	{"question":"解く","answers":["とく"],"comment":"(v5k) to unfasten"},
	{"question":"解ける","answers":["とける","ほどける"],"comment":"(v1) to come untied/to come apart"},
	{"question":"解剖","answers":["かいぼう"],"comment":"(n) dissection/autopsy"},
	{"question":"解放","answers":["かいほう"],"comment":"(n,vs) release/liberation/emancipation"},
	{"question":"解散","answers":["かいさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) breakup/dissolution"},
	{"question":"解決","answers":["かいけつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) settlement/solution/resolution"},
	{"question":"解答","answers":["かいとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) answer/solution"},
	{"question":"解説","answers":["かいせつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) explanation/commentary"},
	{"question":"解釈","answers":["かいしゃく"],"comment":"(n,vs) explanation/interpretation"},
	{"question":"解除","answers":["かいじょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) cancellation/rescinding/release/calling off"},
	{"question":"触る","answers":["さわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to touch/to feel"},
	{"question":"触れる","answers":["ふれる"],"comment":"(v1) to touch/to be touched/to touch on a subject/to feel/to violate (law, copyright, etc.)/to perceive/to be emotionally moved"},
	{"question":"言い付ける","answers":["いいつける"],"comment":"(v1) to tell/to tell on (someone)/to order/to charge/to direct"},
	{"question":"言い出す","answers":["いいだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to start talking/to speak/to tell/to propose/to suggest/to break the ice"},
	{"question":"言い訳","answers":["いいわけ"],"comment":"(n,vs) excuse/explanation"},
	{"question":"言う","answers":["いう","ゆう"],"comment":"(v5u) to say"},
	{"question":"言わば","answers":["いわば"],"comment":"(adv) so to speak"},
	{"question":"言付け","answers":["ことづけ"],"comment":"(n) (verbal) message"},
	{"question":"言付ける","answers":["ことづける"],"comment":"(v1) to send word/to send a message"},
	{"question":"言葉","answers":["ことば"],"comment":"(n) word(s)/language/speech"},
	{"question":"言葉遣い","answers":["ことばづかい"],"comment":"(n) speech/expression/wording"},
	{"question":"言語","answers":["げんご"],"comment":"(n) language"},
	{"question":"言論","answers":["げんろん"],"comment":"(n) discussion"},
	{"question":"訂正","answers":["ていせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) correction/revision"},
	{"question":"計","answers":["けい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) plan"},
	{"question":"計る","answers":["はかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to measure/to weigh/to survey/to time (sound, gauge, estimate)"},
	{"question":"計器","answers":["けいき"],"comment":"(n) meter/gauge"},
	{"question":"計画","answers":["けいかく"],"comment":"(n,vs) plan/project/schedule/scheme/program"},
	{"question":"計算","answers":["けいさん"],"comment":"(n,vs) calculation/reckoning"},
	{"question":"討つ","answers":["うつ"],"comment":"(v5t) to attack/to avenge"},
	{"question":"討論","answers":["とうろん"],"comment":"(n,vs) debate/discussion"},
	{"question":"討議","answers":["とうぎ"],"comment":"(n,vs) debate/discussion"},
	{"question":"訓","answers":["くん"],"comment":"(n) native Japanese reading (rendering) of a Chinese character"},
	{"question":"訓練","answers":["くんれん"],"comment":"(n,vs) practice/training"},
	{"question":"記す","answers":["しるす"],"comment":"(v5s) to note/to write down"},
	{"question":"記事","answers":["きじ"],"comment":"(n) article/news story/report/account"},
	{"question":"記入","answers":["きにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) entry/filling in of forms"},
	{"question":"記号","answers":["きごう"],"comment":"(n) symbol/code"},
	{"question":"記名","answers":["きめい"],"comment":"(n) signature/register"},
	{"question":"記念","answers":["きねん"],"comment":"(n) commemoration/memory"},
	{"question":"記憶","answers":["きおく"],"comment":"(n,vs) memory/recollection/remembrance"},
	{"question":"記者","answers":["きしゃ"],"comment":"(n) reporter"},
	{"question":"記載","answers":["きさい"],"comment":"(n) mention/entry"},
	{"question":"記述","answers":["きじゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) describing/descriptor"},
	{"question":"記録","answers":["きろく"],"comment":"(n,vs) record/minutes/document"},
	{"question":"訪ねる","answers":["たずねる"],"comment":"(v1) to visit"},
	{"question":"訪れる","answers":["おとずれる"],"comment":"(v1) to visit"},
	{"question":"訪問","answers":["ほうもん"],"comment":"(n,vs) call/visit"},
	{"question":"設ける","answers":["もうける"],"comment":"(v1) to create/to establish"},
	{"question":"設備","answers":["せつび"],"comment":"(n,vs) equipment/device/facilities/installation"},
	{"question":"設定","answers":["せってい"],"comment":"(n,vs) establishment/creation"},
	{"question":"設立","answers":["せつりつ"],"comment":"(n) establishment/foundation/institution"},
	{"question":"設置","answers":["せっち"],"comment":"(n) establishment/institution"},
	{"question":"設計","answers":["せっけい"],"comment":"(n,vs) plan/design"},
	{"question":"許す","answers":["ゆるす"],"comment":"(v5s) to permit/to allow/to approve/to exempt (from fine)/to excuse (from)/to confide in/to forgive/to pardon/to excuse/to release/to let off"},
	{"question":"許可","answers":["きょか"],"comment":"(n,vs) permission/approval"},
	{"question":"許容","answers":["きょよう"],"comment":"(n) permission/pardon"},
	{"question":"訳","answers":["やく","わけ"],"comment":"(n) (uk) meaning/reason/circumstances/can be deduced/situation"},
	{"question":"訳す","answers":["やくす"],"comment":"(v5s) to translate"},
	{"question":"訴え","answers":["うったえ"],"comment":"(n) lawsuit/complaint"},
	{"question":"訴える","answers":["うったえる"],"comment":"(v1) to sue (a person)/to resort to/to appeal to"},
	{"question":"訴訟","answers":["そしょう"],"comment":"(n) litigation/lawsuit"},
	{"question":"診る","answers":["みる"],"comment":"(v1) to examine (medical)"},
	{"question":"診察","answers":["しんさつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) medical examination"},
	{"question":"診断","answers":["しんだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) diagnosis"},
	{"question":"診療","answers":["しんりょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) medical examination and treatment/diagnosis"},
	{"question":"証拠","answers":["しょうこ"],"comment":"(n) evidence/proof"},
	{"question":"証明","answers":["しょうめい"],"comment":"(n,vs) proof/verification"},
	{"question":"証言","answers":["しょうげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) evidence/testimony"},
	{"question":"詐欺","answers":["さぎ"],"comment":"(n) fraud/swindle"},
	{"question":"評価","answers":["ひょうか"],"comment":"(n,vs) valuation/estimation/assessment/evaluation"},
	{"question":"評判","answers":["ひょうばん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) fame/reputation/popularity/arrant"},
	{"question":"評論","answers":["ひょうろん"],"comment":"(n) criticism/critique"},
	{"question":"試し","answers":["ためし"],"comment":"(n) trial/test"},
	{"question":"試す","answers":["ためす"],"comment":"(v5s) to attempt/to test"},
	{"question":"試み","answers":["こころみ"],"comment":"(n) trial/experiment"},
	{"question":"試みる","answers":["こころみる"],"comment":"(v1) to try/to test"},
	{"question":"試合","answers":["しあい"],"comment":"(n) match/game/bout/contest"},
	{"question":"試験","answers":["しけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) examination/test/study"},
	{"question":"詩","answers":["し"],"comment":"(n) poem/verse of poetry"},
	{"question":"詩人","answers":["しじん"],"comment":"(n) poet"},
	{"question":"詫び","answers":["わび"],"comment":"(n) apology"},
	{"question":"詫びる","answers":["わびる"],"comment":"(v1) to apologize"},
	{"question":"詰まる","answers":["つまる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to be blocked/to be packed/(2) to hit the ball near the handle of the bat (baseball)"},
	{"question":"詰める","answers":["つめる"],"comment":"(v1) to pack/to shorten/to work out (details)"},
	{"question":"詰る","answers":["なじる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rebuke/to scold/to tell off"},
	{"question":"話","answers":["はなし"],"comment":"(io) (n) talk/speech/chat/story/conversation"},
	{"question":"話し合う","answers":["はなしあう"],"comment":"(v5u) to discuss/to talk together"},
	{"question":"話し掛ける","answers":["はなしかける"],"comment":"(v1) to accost a person/to talk (to someone)"},
	{"question":"話す","answers":["はなす"],"comment":"(v5s) to speak"},
	{"question":"話中","answers":["はなしちゅう"],"comment":"(n) while talking/the line is busy"},
	{"question":"話合い","answers":["はなしあい"],"comment":"(n) discussion/conference"},
	{"question":"話題","answers":["わだい"],"comment":"(n) topic/subject"},
	{"question":"該当","answers":["がいとう"],"comment":"(n,vs) corresponding/answering to/coming under"},
	{"question":"詳しい","answers":["くわしい"],"comment":"(adj) knowing very well/detailed/full/accurate"},
	{"question":"詳細","answers":["しょうさい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) detail/particulars"},
	{"question":"誇り","answers":["ほこり"],"comment":"(n) pride"},
	{"question":"誇る","answers":["ほこる"],"comment":"(v5r) to boast of/to be proud of"},
	{"question":"誇張","answers":["こちょう"],"comment":"(n) exaggeration"},
	{"question":"認める","answers":["みとめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to recognize/to appreciate/to approve/to admit/to notice"},
	{"question":"認識","answers":["にんしき"],"comment":"(n,vs) recognition/cognizance"},
	{"question":"誓う","answers":["ちかう"],"comment":"(v5u) to swear/to vow/to take an oath/to pledge"},
	{"question":"誕生","answers":["たんじょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) birth"},
	{"question":"誕生日","answers":["たんじょうび"],"comment":"(n) birthday"},
	{"question":"誘う","answers":["さそう"],"comment":"(v5u) (1) to invite/to ask/to call (for)/(2) to tempt/to lure/to induce"},
	{"question":"誘導","answers":["ゆうどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) guidance/leading/induction/introduction/incitement/inducement"},
	{"question":"誘惑","answers":["ゆうわく"],"comment":"(n,vs) temptation/allurement/lure"},
	{"question":"語","answers":["ご"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) language/word"},
	{"question":"語る","answers":["かたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to talk/to tell/to recite"},
	{"question":"語句","answers":["ごく"],"comment":"(n) words/phrases"},
	{"question":"語学","answers":["ごがく"],"comment":"(n) language study"},
	{"question":"語彙","answers":["ごい"],"comment":"(n) vocabulary/glossary"},
	{"question":"語源","answers":["ごげん"],"comment":"(n) word root/word derivation/etymology"},
	{"question":"誠","answers":["まこと"],"comment":"(adv,n) truth/faith/fidelity/sincerity/trust/confidence/reliance/devotion"},
	{"question":"誠実","answers":["せいじつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) sincere/honest/faithful"},
	{"question":"誤り","answers":["あやまり"],"comment":"(n) error"},
	{"question":"誤る","answers":["あやまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to make a mistake"},
	{"question":"誤差","answers":["ごさ"],"comment":"(n) error"},
	{"question":"誤解","answers":["ごかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) misunderstanding"},
	{"question":"説","answers":["せつ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) theory"},
	{"question":"説く","answers":["とく"],"comment":"(v5k) to explain/to advocate/to preach/to persuade"},
	{"question":"説得","answers":["せっとく"],"comment":"(n) persuasion"},
	{"question":"説明","answers":["せつめい"],"comment":"(n,vs) explanation/exposition"},
	{"question":"読み","answers":["よみ"],"comment":"(n) reading"},
	{"question":"読み上げる","answers":["よみあげる"],"comment":"(v1) to read out loud (and clearly)/to call a roll"},
	{"question":"読む","answers":["よむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to read"},
	{"question":"読書","answers":["どくしょ"],"comment":"(n) reading"},
	{"question":"誰","answers":["だれ"],"comment":"(n) who"},
	{"question":"誰か","answers":["だれか"],"comment":"(n) (uk) someone/somebody"},
	{"question":"課","answers":["か"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) counter for chapters (of a book)"},
	{"question":"課外","answers":["かがい"],"comment":"(n) extracurricular"},
	{"question":"課程","answers":["かてい"],"comment":"(n) course/curriculum"},
	{"question":"課税","answers":["かぜい"],"comment":"(n,vs) taxation"},
	{"question":"課題","answers":["かだい"],"comment":"(n) subject/theme/task"},
	{"question":"調べ","answers":["しらべ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) preparation/investigation/inspection"},
	{"question":"調べる","answers":["しらべる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to investigate/to check up"},
	{"question":"調停","answers":["ちょうてい"],"comment":"(n) arbitration/conciliation/mediation"},
	{"question":"調印","answers":["ちょういん"],"comment":"(n) signature/sign/sealing"},
	{"question":"調味料","answers":["ちょうみりょう"],"comment":"(n) condiment/seasoning"},
	{"question":"調和","answers":["ちょうわ"],"comment":"(n) harmony"},
	{"question":"調子","answers":["ちょうし"],"comment":"(n) tune/tone/key/pitch/time/rhythm/vein/mood/way/manner/style/knack/condition/state of health/strain/impetus/spur of the moment/trend"},
	{"question":"調整","answers":["ちょうせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) regulation/adjustment/tuning"},
	{"question":"調査","answers":["ちょうさ"],"comment":"(n,vs) investigation/examination/inquiry/survey"},
	{"question":"調理","answers":["ちょうり"],"comment":"(n,vs) cooking"},
	{"question":"調節","answers":["ちょうせつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) regulation/adjustment/control"},
	{"question":"請求","answers":["せいきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) claim/demand/application/request"},
	{"question":"論じる","answers":["ろんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to argue/to discuss/to debate"},
	{"question":"論ずる","answers":["ろんずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to argue/to discuss/to debate"},
	{"question":"論争","answers":["ろんそう"],"comment":"(n) controversy/dispute"},
	{"question":"論文","answers":["ろんぶん"],"comment":"(n) thesis/essay/treatise/paper"},
	{"question":"論理","answers":["ろんり"],"comment":"(n) logic"},
	{"question":"論議","answers":["ろんぎ"],"comment":"(n) discussion"},
	{"question":"諦め","answers":["あきらめ"],"comment":"(n) resignation/acceptance/consolation"},
	{"question":"諦める","answers":["あきらめる"],"comment":"(v1) to give up/to abandon"},
	{"question":"諮る","answers":["はかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to consult with/to confer"},
	{"question":"諸君","answers":["しょくん"],"comment":"(n) Gentlemen!/Ladies!"},
	{"question":"諺","answers":["ことわざ"],"comment":"(n) proverb/maxim"},
	{"question":"謎","answers":["なぞ"],"comment":"(n) riddle/puzzle/enigma"},
	{"question":"謎謎","answers":["なぞなぞ"],"comment":"(n) riddle/puzzle/enigma"},
	{"question":"謙虚","answers":["けんきょ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) modesty/humility"},
	{"question":"謙遜","answers":["けんそん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) humble/humility/modesty"},
	{"question":"講堂","answers":["こうどう"],"comment":"(n) auditorium"},
	{"question":"講師","answers":["こうし"],"comment":"(n) lecturer"},
	{"question":"講演","answers":["こうえん"],"comment":"(n,vs) lecture/address"},
	{"question":"講義","answers":["こうぎ"],"comment":"(n,vs) lecture"},
	{"question":"講習","answers":["こうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) short course/training"},
	{"question":"講読","answers":["こうどく"],"comment":"(n,vs) reading/translation"},
	{"question":"謝る","answers":["あやまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to apologize"},
	{"question":"謝絶","answers":["しゃぜつ"],"comment":"(n) refusal"},
	{"question":"謹む","answers":["つつしむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be careful/to be chaste or discreet/to abstain or refrain"},
	{"question":"警備","answers":["けいび"],"comment":"(n,vs) defense/guard/policing/security"},
	{"question":"警告","answers":["けいこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) warning/advice"},
	{"question":"警官","answers":["けいかん"],"comment":"(n) policeman"},
	{"question":"警察","answers":["けいさつ"],"comment":"(n) police"},
	{"question":"警戒","answers":["けいかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) warning/admonition/vigilance"},
	{"question":"警部","answers":["けいぶ"],"comment":"(n) police inspector"},
	{"question":"議事堂","answers":["ぎじどう"],"comment":"(n) Diet building"},
	{"question":"議会","answers":["ぎかい"],"comment":"(n) Diet/congress/parliament"},
	{"question":"議員","answers":["ぎいん"],"comment":"(n) member of the Diet, congress or parliament"},
	{"question":"議案","answers":["ぎあん"],"comment":"(n) legislative bill"},
	{"question":"議決","answers":["ぎけつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) resolution/decision/vote"},
	{"question":"議論","answers":["ぎろん"],"comment":"(n,vs) argument/discussion/dispute"},
	{"question":"議長","answers":["ぎちょう"],"comment":"(n) chairman"},
	{"question":"議題","answers":["ぎだい"],"comment":"(n) topic of discussion/agenda"},
	{"question":"譲る","answers":["ゆずる"],"comment":"(v5r) to turn over/to assign/to hand over/to transmit/to convey/to sell/to dispose of/to yield/to surrender"},
	{"question":"譲歩","answers":["じょうほ"],"comment":"(n) concession/conciliation/compromise"},
	{"question":"護衛","answers":["ごえい"],"comment":"(n) guard/convoy/escort"},
	{"question":"谷","answers":["たに"],"comment":"(n) valley"},
	{"question":"豆","answers":["まめ"],"comment":"(n) beans/peas"},
	{"question":"豊か","answers":["ゆたか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) abundant/wealthy/plentiful/rich"},
	{"question":"豊作","answers":["ほうさく"],"comment":"(n) abundant harvest/bumper crop"},
	{"question":"豊富","answers":["ほうふ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) abundance/wealth/plenty/bounty"},
	{"question":"豚肉","answers":["ぶたにく"],"comment":"(n) pork"},
	{"question":"象","answers":["ぞう"],"comment":"(n) elephant"},
	{"question":"象徴","answers":["しょうちょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) symbol"},
	{"question":"豪華","answers":["ごうか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) wonderful/gorgeous/splendor/pomp/extravagance"},
	{"question":"貝","answers":["かい"],"comment":"(n) shell/shellfish"},
	{"question":"貝殻","answers":["かいがら"],"comment":"(n) shell"},
	{"question":"負う","answers":["おう"],"comment":"(v5u) to bear/to owe"},
	{"question":"負かす","answers":["まかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to defeat"},
	{"question":"負け","answers":["まけ"],"comment":"(n) defeat/loss/losing (a game)"},
	{"question":"負ける","answers":["まける"],"comment":"(v1) to lose/to be defeated"},
	{"question":"負債","answers":["ふさい"],"comment":"(n) debt/liabilities"},
	{"question":"負傷","answers":["ふしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) injury/wound"},
	{"question":"負担","answers":["ふたん"],"comment":"(n) burden/charge/responsibility"},
	{"question":"財","answers":["ざい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) fortune/riches"},
	{"question":"財布","answers":["さいふ"],"comment":"(n) purse/wallet"},
	{"question":"財政","answers":["ざいせい"],"comment":"(n) economy/financial affairs"},
	{"question":"財源","answers":["ざいげん"],"comment":"(n) source of funds/resources/finances"},
	{"question":"財産","answers":["ざいさん"],"comment":"(n) property/fortune/assets"},
	{"question":"貢献","answers":["こうけん"],"comment":"(n,vs) contribution/services"},
	{"question":"貧しい","answers":["まずしい"],"comment":"(adj) poor/needy"},
	{"question":"貧乏","answers":["びんぼう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) poverty/destitute/poor"},
	{"question":"貧困","answers":["ひんこん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) poverty/lack"},
	{"question":"貧弱","answers":["ひんじゃく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) poor/meagre/insubstantial"},
	{"question":"貨幣","answers":["かへい"],"comment":"(n) money/currency/coinage"},
	{"question":"貨物","answers":["かもつ"],"comment":"(n) cargo/freight"},
	{"question":"販売","answers":["はんばい"],"comment":"(n,vs) sale/selling/marketing"},
	{"question":"貫く","answers":["つらぬく"],"comment":"(v5k) to go through"},
	{"question":"貫禄","answers":["かんろく"],"comment":"(n) presence/dignity"},
	{"question":"責める","answers":["せめる"],"comment":"(v1) to condemn/to blame/to criticize"},
	{"question":"責任","answers":["せきにん"],"comment":"(n) duty/responsibility"},
	{"question":"責務","answers":["せきむ"],"comment":"(n) duty/obligation"},
	{"question":"貯蓄","answers":["ちょちく"],"comment":"(n) savings"},
	{"question":"貯蔵","answers":["ちょぞう"],"comment":"(n) storage/preservation"},
	{"question":"貯金","answers":["ちょきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (bank) savings"},
	{"question":"貰う","answers":["もらう"],"comment":"(v5u) (uk) to receive"},
	{"question":"貴い","answers":["とうとい"],"comment":"(adj) precious/valuable/priceless/noble/exalted/sacred"},
	{"question":"貴族","answers":["きぞく"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) noble/aristocrat"},
	{"question":"貴重","answers":["きちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) precious/valuable"},
	{"question":"買い物","answers":["かいもの"],"comment":"(n) shopping"},
	{"question":"買う","answers":["かう"],"comment":"(v5u) to buy"},
	{"question":"貸し","answers":["かし"],"comment":"(n) loan/lending"},
	{"question":"貸し出し","answers":["かしだし"],"comment":"(n,vs) lending/loaning"},
	{"question":"貸す","answers":["かす"],"comment":"(v5s) to lend"},
	{"question":"貸家","answers":["かしや"],"comment":"(n) house for rent"},
	{"question":"貸間","answers":["かしま"],"comment":"(n) room to let"},
	{"question":"費やす","answers":["ついやす"],"comment":"(v5s) to spend/to devote/to waste"},
	{"question":"費用","answers":["ひよう"],"comment":"(n) cost/expense"},
	{"question":"貼る","answers":["はる"],"comment":"(v5r) to stick/to paste"},
	{"question":"貿易","answers":["ぼうえき"],"comment":"(n) trade (foreign)"},
	{"question":"賃金","answers":["ちんぎん"],"comment":"(n) wages"},
	{"question":"賄う","answers":["まかなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to give board to/to provide meals/to pay"},
	{"question":"資料","answers":["しりょう"],"comment":"(n) materials/data"},
	{"question":"資本","answers":["しほん"],"comment":"(n) funds/capital"},
	{"question":"資格","answers":["しかく"],"comment":"(n) qualifications/requirements/capabilities"},
	{"question":"資源","answers":["しげん"],"comment":"(n) resources"},
	{"question":"資産","answers":["しさん"],"comment":"(n) property/fortune/means/assets"},
	{"question":"資金","answers":["しきん"],"comment":"(n) funds/capital"},
	{"question":"賑やか","answers":["にぎやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) bustling/busy"},
	{"question":"賑わう","answers":["にぎわう"],"comment":"(v5u) to prosper/to flourish/to do thriving business/to be crowded with people"},
	{"question":"賛成","answers":["さんせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) approval/agreement/support/favour"},
	{"question":"賛美","answers":["さんび"],"comment":"(n,vs) praise/adoration/glorification"},
	{"question":"賜る","answers":["たまわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to grant/to bestow"},
	{"question":"賞","answers":["しょう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) prize/award"},
	{"question":"賞品","answers":["しょうひん"],"comment":"(n) prize/trophy"},
	{"question":"賞金","answers":["しょうきん"],"comment":"(n) prize/monetary award"},
	{"question":"賠償","answers":["ばいしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) reparations/indemnity/compensation"},
	{"question":"賢い","answers":["かしこい"],"comment":"(adj) wise/clever/smart"},
	{"question":"賢明","answers":["けんめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) wisdom/intelligence/prudence"},
	{"question":"質","answers":["しつ"],"comment":"(n) quality/nature (of person)"},
	{"question":"質問","answers":["しつもん"],"comment":"(n,vs) question/inquiry"},
	{"question":"質疑","answers":["しつぎ"],"comment":"(n) question"},
	{"question":"質素","answers":["しっそ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) simplicity/modesty/frugality"},
	{"question":"賭","answers":["かけ"],"comment":"(n) betting/gambling/a gamble"},
	{"question":"賭ける","answers":["かける"],"comment":"(v1) to wager/to bet/to risk/to stake/to gamble"},
	{"question":"購入","answers":["こうにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) purchase/buy"},
	{"question":"購読","answers":["こうどく"],"comment":"(n,vs) subscription (e.g. magazine)"},
	{"question":"購買","answers":["こうばい"],"comment":"(n,vs) purchase/buy"},
	{"question":"贅沢","answers":["ぜいたく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) luxury/extravagance"},
	{"question":"贈り物","answers":["おくりもの"],"comment":"(n) present/gift"},
	{"question":"贈る","answers":["おくる"],"comment":"(v5r) to send/to give to/to award to/to confer on"},
	{"question":"贋物","answers":["にせもの"],"comment":"(n) imitation/counterfeit/forgery/sham"},
	{"question":"赤い","answers":["あかい"],"comment":"(adj) red"},
	{"question":"赤らむ","answers":["あからむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to become red/to redden/to blush"},
	{"question":"赤ん坊","answers":["あかんぼう"],"comment":"(n) baby"},
	{"question":"赤字","answers":["あかじ"],"comment":"(n) deficit/go in the red"},
	{"question":"赤道","answers":["せきどう"],"comment":"(n) equator"},
	{"question":"走る","answers":["はしる"],"comment":"(v5r) to run"},
	{"question":"走行","answers":["そうこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) running a wheeled vehicle (e.g. car)/traveling"},
	{"question":"赴く","answers":["おもむく"],"comment":"(v5k) to go/to proceed/to repair to/to become"},
	{"question":"赴任","answers":["ふにん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (proceeding to) new appointment"},
	{"question":"起きる","answers":["おきる"],"comment":"(v1) to get up/to rise"},
	{"question":"起こる","answers":["おこる"],"comment":"(v5r) to occur/to happen"},
	{"question":"起す","answers":["おこす"],"comment":"(io) (v5s) to raise/to cause/to wake someone"},
	{"question":"起伏","answers":["きふく"],"comment":"(n) undulation"},
	{"question":"起床","answers":["きしょう"],"comment":"(n) rising/getting out of bed"},
	{"question":"起源","answers":["きげん"],"comment":"(n) origin/beginning/rise"},
	{"question":"起点","answers":["きてん"],"comment":"(n) starting point"},
	{"question":"超","answers":["ちょう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf,pref) super-/ultra-/hyper-"},
	{"question":"超える","answers":["こえる"],"comment":"(v1) to exceed/to cross over/to cross/to pass through/to pass over (out of)"},
	{"question":"超す","answers":["こす"],"comment":"(v5s) to cross/to pass/to tide over"},
	{"question":"超過","answers":["ちょうか"],"comment":"(n,vs) excess/being more than"},
	{"question":"越える","answers":["こえる"],"comment":"(v1) to exceed/to cross over/to cross/to pass through/to pass over (out of)"},
	{"question":"越す","answers":["こす"],"comment":"(v5s) to go over (e.g. with audience)"},
	{"question":"趣","answers":["おもむき"],"comment":"(n) (1) meaning/tenor/gist/(2) effect/influence/(3) appearance/aspect/(4) taste/(5) grace/charm/refinement"},
	{"question":"趣味","answers":["しゅみ"],"comment":"(n) hobby/tastes/preference"},
	{"question":"趣旨","answers":["しゅし"],"comment":"(n) object/meaning"},
	{"question":"足","answers":["あし"],"comment":"(n) foot/pace/gait/leg"},
	{"question":"足し算","answers":["たしざん"],"comment":"(n) addition"},
	{"question":"足す","answers":["たす"],"comment":"(v5s) to add (numbers)/to do (e.g. one's business)"},
	{"question":"足りる","answers":["たりる"],"comment":"(v1) to be sufficient/to be enough"},
	{"question":"足る","answers":["たる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be sufficient/to be enough"},
	{"question":"足元","answers":["あしもと"],"comment":"(n) (1) at one's feet/underfoot/(2) gait/pace/step"},
	{"question":"足袋","answers":["たび"],"comment":"(n) tabi/Japanese socks (with split toe)"},
	{"question":"足跡","answers":["あしあと"],"comment":"(n) footprints"},
	{"question":"跡","answers":["あと"],"comment":"(n) (1) trace/tracks/mark/sign/(2) remains/ruins/(3) scar"},
	{"question":"跡継ぎ","answers":["あとつぎ"],"comment":"(n) heir/successor"},
	{"question":"跳ねる","answers":["はねる"],"comment":"(v1) to jump/to leap/to prance/to spring up/to bound/to hop"},
	{"question":"跳ぶ","answers":["とぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to jump/to fly/to leap/to spring/to bound/to hop"},
	{"question":"踊り","answers":["おどり"],"comment":"(n) dance"},
	{"question":"踊る","answers":["おどる"],"comment":"(v5r) to dance"},
	{"question":"踏まえる","answers":["ふまえる"],"comment":"(v1) to be based on/to have origin in"},
	{"question":"踏み込む","answers":["ふみこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to step into (someone else's territory)/to break into/to raid"},
	{"question":"踏む","answers":["ふむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to step on/to tread on"},
	{"question":"踏切","answers":["ふみきり"],"comment":"(n) railway crossing/level crossing/starting line/scratch/crossover"},
	{"question":"蹴る","answers":["ける"],"comment":"(v5r) to kick"},
	{"question":"蹴飛ばす","answers":["けとばす"],"comment":"(v5s) to kick away/to kick off/to kick (someone)/to refuse/to reject"},
	{"question":"身","answers":["み"],"comment":"(n) body/main part/oneself/sword"},
	{"question":"身なり","answers":["みなり"],"comment":"(n) personal appearance"},
	{"question":"身の上","answers":["みのうえ"],"comment":"(n) one's future/one's welfare/one's personal history"},
	{"question":"身の回り","answers":["みのまわり"],"comment":"(n) one's personal appearance/personal belongings"},
	{"question":"身体","answers":["しんたい"],"comment":"(n) the body"},
	{"question":"身分","answers":["みぶん"],"comment":"(n) social position/social status"},
	{"question":"身振り","answers":["みぶり"],"comment":"(n) gesture"},
	{"question":"身近","answers":["みぢか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) near oneself/close to one/familiar"},
	{"question":"身長","answers":["しんちょう"],"comment":"(n) height (of body)/stature"},
	{"question":"躾","answers":["しつけ"],"comment":"(n) home discipline/training/upbringing/breeding"},
	{"question":"躾ける","answers":["しつける"],"comment":"(v1) to train/to discipline/to teach manners"},
	{"question":"車","answers":["くるま"],"comment":"(n) car/vehicle/wheel"},
	{"question":"車庫","answers":["しゃこ"],"comment":"(n) garage/car shed"},
	{"question":"車掌","answers":["しゃしょう"],"comment":"(n) (train) conductor"},
	{"question":"車輪","answers":["しゃりん"],"comment":"(n) (car) wheel"},
	{"question":"軌道","answers":["きどう"],"comment":"(n) (1) orbit/(2) railroad track"},
	{"question":"軍","answers":["ぐん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) army/force/troops"},
	{"question":"軍事","answers":["ぐんじ"],"comment":"(n) military affairs"},
	{"question":"軍備","answers":["ぐんび"],"comment":"(n) armaments/military preparations"},
	{"question":"軍服","answers":["ぐんぷく"],"comment":"(n) military or naval uniform"},
	{"question":"軍艦","answers":["ぐんかん"],"comment":"(n) warship/battleship"},
	{"question":"軍隊","answers":["ぐんたい"],"comment":"(n) army/troops"},
	{"question":"軒","answers":["けん","のき"],"comment":"(n) eaves"},
	{"question":"軒並","answers":["のきなみ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) row of houses"},
	{"question":"軟らかい","answers":["やわらかい"],"comment":"(adj) soft/tender/limp"},
	{"question":"転がす","answers":["ころがす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to roll"},
	{"question":"転がる","answers":["ころがる"],"comment":"(v5r) to roll/to tumble"},
	{"question":"転じる","answers":["てんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to turn/to shift/to alter/to distract"},
	{"question":"転ずる","answers":["てんずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to turn/to shift/to alter/to distract"},
	{"question":"転ぶ","answers":["ころぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to fall down/to fall over"},
	{"question":"転任","answers":["てんにん"],"comment":"(n) change of post"},
	{"question":"転勤","answers":["てんきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) transfer/transmission"},
	{"question":"転回","answers":["てんかい"],"comment":"(n) revolution/rotation"},
	{"question":"転寝","answers":["うたたね"],"comment":"(n) dozing/napping on the floor (in one's clothes)"},
	{"question":"転居","answers":["てんきょ"],"comment":"(n) moving/changing residence"},
	{"question":"転換","answers":["てんかん"],"comment":"(n) convert/divert"},
	{"question":"転校","answers":["てんこう"],"comment":"(n) change schools"},
	{"question":"転落","answers":["てんらく"],"comment":"(n,vs) fall/degradation/slump/spill"},
	{"question":"軸","answers":["じく"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) axis/stem/shaft/axle"},
	{"question":"軽い","answers":["かるい"],"comment":"(adj) light/non-serious/minor"},
	{"question":"軽快","answers":["けいかい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) rhythmical (e.g. melody)/casual (e.g. dress)/light/nimble"},
	{"question":"軽減","answers":["けいげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) abatement"},
	{"question":"軽率","answers":["けいそつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) rash/thoughtless/careless/hasty"},
	{"question":"軽蔑","answers":["けいべつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) scorn/disdain"},
	{"question":"載せる","answers":["のせる"],"comment":"(v1) to place on (something)/to take on board/to give a ride/to let (one) take part/to impose on/to record/to mention/to load (luggage)/to publish/to run (an ad)"},
	{"question":"載る","answers":["のる"],"comment":"(v5r) to appear (in print)/to be recorded"},
	{"question":"輝く","answers":["かがやく"],"comment":"(v5k) to shine/to glitter/to sparkle"},
	{"question":"輪","answers":["わ"],"comment":"(n) ring/hoop/circle"},
	{"question":"輸入","answers":["ゆにゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) importation/import/introduction"},
	{"question":"輸出","answers":["ゆしゅつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) export"},
	{"question":"輸血","answers":["ゆけつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) blood transfusion"},
	{"question":"輸送","answers":["ゆそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) transport/transportation"},
	{"question":"轢く","answers":["ひく"],"comment":"(v5k) to run somebody over (with vehicle)/to knock someone down"},
	{"question":"辛い","answers":["からい","つらい"],"comment":"(adj) painful/heart-breaking"},
	{"question":"辛抱","answers":["しんぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) patience/endurance"},
	{"question":"辞める","answers":["やめる"],"comment":"(v1) to retire"},
	{"question":"辞典","answers":["じてん"],"comment":"(n) dictionary"},
	{"question":"辞書","answers":["じしょ"],"comment":"(n) dictionary/lexicon"},
	{"question":"辞職","answers":["じしょく"],"comment":"(n) resignation"},
	{"question":"辞退","answers":["じたい"],"comment":"(n) refusal"},
	{"question":"辟易","answers":["へきえき"],"comment":"(n,vs) wince/shrink back/succumbing to/being frightened/disconcerted"},
	{"question":"農地","answers":["のうち"],"comment":"(n) agricultural land"},
	{"question":"農場","answers":["のうじょう"],"comment":"(n) farm (agriculture)"},
	{"question":"農家","answers":["のうか"],"comment":"(n) farmer/farm family"},
	{"question":"農村","answers":["のうそん"],"comment":"(n) agricultural community/farm village/rural"},
	{"question":"農業","answers":["のうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) agriculture"},
	{"question":"農民","answers":["のうみん"],"comment":"(n) farmers/peasants"},
	{"question":"農産物","answers":["のうさんぶつ"],"comment":"(n) agricultural produce"},
	{"question":"農耕","answers":["のうこう"],"comment":"(n) farming/agriculture"},
	{"question":"農薬","answers":["のうやく"],"comment":"(n) agricultural chemicals"},
	{"question":"辺","answers":["へん"],"comment":"(n) area/vicinity"},
	{"question":"辺り","answers":["あたり"],"comment":"(n) (in the) neighbourhood/vicinity/nearby"},
	{"question":"込む","answers":["こむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to be crowded"},
	{"question":"込める","answers":["こめる"],"comment":"(v1) to include/to put into"},
	{"question":"辿り着く","answers":["たどりつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to grope along to/to struggle on to/to arrive somewhere after a struggle"},
	{"question":"辿る","answers":["たどる"],"comment":"(v5r) to follow (road)/to pursue (course)/to follow up"},
	{"question":"迅速","answers":["じんそく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) quick/fast/rapid/swift/prompt"},
	{"question":"迎え","answers":["むかえ"],"comment":"(n) meeting/person sent to pick up an arrival"},
	{"question":"迎える","answers":["むかえる"],"comment":"(v1) to go out to meet/to accept as a member of a group or family"},
	{"question":"近々","answers":["ちかぢか"],"comment":"(adv) nearness/before long"},
	{"question":"近い","answers":["ちかい"],"comment":"(adj,suf) near/close by/short"},
	{"question":"近く","answers":["ちかく"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) near/neighbourhood/vicinity"},
	{"question":"近付ける","answers":["ちかづける"],"comment":"(v1) to bring near/to put close/to let come near/to associate with"},
	{"question":"近代","answers":["きんだい"],"comment":"(n) present day"},
	{"question":"近寄る","answers":["ちかよる"],"comment":"(v5r) to approach/to draw near"},
	{"question":"近所","answers":["きんじょ"],"comment":"(n) neighbourhood"},
	{"question":"近眼","answers":["きんがん"],"comment":"(n) nearsightedness/shortsightedness/myopia"},
	{"question":"近視","answers":["きんし"],"comment":"(n) shortsightedness"},
	{"question":"近郊","answers":["きんこう"],"comment":"(n) suburbs/outskirts"},
	{"question":"近頃","answers":["ちかごろ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) lately/recently/nowadays"},
	{"question":"返す","answers":["かえす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to return something"},
	{"question":"返事","answers":["へんじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) reply/answer"},
	{"question":"返済","answers":["へんさい"],"comment":"(n,vs) repayment"},
	{"question":"返答","answers":["へんとう"],"comment":"(n) reply"},
	{"question":"返還","answers":["へんかん"],"comment":"(n,vs) return/restoration"},
	{"question":"迫る","answers":["せまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to draw near/to press"},
	{"question":"迫害","answers":["はくがい"],"comment":"(n,vs) persecution"},
	{"question":"述べる","answers":["のべる"],"comment":"(v1) to state/to express/to mention"},
	{"question":"述語","answers":["じゅつご"],"comment":"(n) predicate"},
	{"question":"迷う","answers":["まよう"],"comment":"(v5u) to be puzzled/to be perplexed/to lose one's way"},
	{"question":"迷信","answers":["めいしん"],"comment":"(n) superstition"},
	{"question":"迷子","answers":["まいご"],"comment":"(n) lost (stray) child"},
	{"question":"迷惑","answers":["めいわく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) trouble/bother/annoyance"},
	{"question":"追い付く","answers":["おいつく"],"comment":"(v5k) to overtake/to catch up (with)"},
	{"question":"追い出す","answers":["おいだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to expel/to drive out"},
	{"question":"追い掛ける","answers":["おいかける"],"comment":"(v1) to chase or run after someone/to run down/to pursue"},
	{"question":"追い越す","answers":["おいこす"],"comment":"(v5s) to pass (e.g. car)/to outdistance/to outstrip"},
	{"question":"追い込む","answers":["おいこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to herd/to corner/to drive"},
	{"question":"追う","answers":["おう"],"comment":"(v5u) to chase/to run after"},
	{"question":"追加","answers":["ついか"],"comment":"(n,vs) addition/supplement/appendix"},
	{"question":"追及","answers":["ついきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) gaining on/carrying out/solving (crime)"},
	{"question":"追放","answers":["ついほう"],"comment":"(n) exile/banishment"},
	{"question":"追跡","answers":["ついせき"],"comment":"(n) pursuit"},
	{"question":"退く","answers":["どく"],"comment":"(v5k,vi) (1) to retreat/to recede/to withdraw"},
	{"question":"退ける","answers":["どける"],"comment":"(v1) to remove/to take away/to dislodge/to put something out of the way"},
	{"question":"退化","answers":["たいか"],"comment":"(n) degeneration/retrogression"},
	{"question":"退学","answers":["たいがく"],"comment":"(n) dropping out of school"},
	{"question":"退屈","answers":["たいくつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) tedium/boredom"},
	{"question":"退治","answers":["たいじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) extermination"},
	{"question":"退職","answers":["たいしょく"],"comment":"(n,vs) retirement (from office)"},
	{"question":"退院","answers":["たいいん"],"comment":"(n,vs) leaving hospital"},
	{"question":"送り仮名","answers":["おくりがな"],"comment":"part of word written in kana"},
	{"question":"送る","answers":["おくる"],"comment":"(v5r) to send (a thing)/to dispatch/to take or escort (a person somewhere)/to see off (a person)/to spend a period of time/to live a life"},
	{"question":"送別","answers":["そうべつ"],"comment":"(n) farewell/send-off"},
	{"question":"送料","answers":["そうりょう"],"comment":"(n) postage/carriage"},
	{"question":"送金","answers":["そうきん"],"comment":"(n) remittance/sending money"},
	{"question":"逃がす","answers":["にがす"],"comment":"(v5s) to let loose/to set free/to let escape"},
	{"question":"逃げる","answers":["にげる"],"comment":"(v1) to escape/to run away"},
	{"question":"逃げ出す","answers":["にげだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to run away/to escape from"},
	{"question":"逃す","answers":["のがす"],"comment":"(v5s) to let loose/to set free/to let escape"},
	{"question":"逃れる","answers":["のがれる"],"comment":"(v1) to escape"},
	{"question":"逃亡","answers":["とうぼう"],"comment":"(n,vs) escape"},
	{"question":"逃走","answers":["とうそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) flight/desertion/escape"},
	{"question":"逆","answers":["ぎゃく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) reverse/opposite"},
	{"question":"逆さ","answers":["さかさ"],"comment":"(n) reverse/inversion/upside down"},
	{"question":"逆らう","answers":["さからう"],"comment":"(v5u) to go against/to oppose/to disobey/to defy"},
	{"question":"逆様","answers":["さかさま"],"comment":"(adj-na,adj-no,n) inversion/upside down"},
	{"question":"逆立ち","answers":["さかだち"],"comment":"(n) handstand/headstand"},
	{"question":"逆転","answers":["ぎゃくてん"],"comment":"(n) (sudden) change/reversal/turn-around/coming from behind (baseball)"},
	{"question":"透き通る","answers":["すきとおる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be(come) transparent"},
	{"question":"透明","answers":["とうめい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) transparency/cleanness"},
	{"question":"途上","answers":["とじょう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) en route/half way"},
	{"question":"途中","answers":["とちゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) on the way/en route/midway"},
	{"question":"途端","answers":["とたん"],"comment":"(n) just (now, at the moment, etc.)"},
	{"question":"途絶える","answers":["とだえる"],"comment":"(v1) to stop/to cease/to come to an end"},
	{"question":"這う","answers":["はう"],"comment":"(v5u) to creep/to crawl"},
	{"question":"通う","answers":["かよう"],"comment":"(v5u) (1) to go back and forth/to ply between/(2) to commute/to attend (school, church, etc.)"},
	{"question":"通じる","answers":["つうじる"],"comment":"(v1) to run to/to lead to/to communicate/to understand/to be well informed"},
	{"question":"通す","answers":["とおす"],"comment":"(v5s) to let pass/to overlook/to continue/to keep/to make way for/to persist in"},
	{"question":"通り","answers":["とおり","とおり","とおり"],"comment":"(n-suf) in accordance with ~/following ~/~ Street/~ Avenue"},
	{"question":"通り掛かる","answers":["とおりかかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to happen to pass by"},
	{"question":"通り過ぎる","answers":["とおりすぎる"],"comment":"(v1) to pass/to pass through"},
	{"question":"通る","answers":["とおる"],"comment":"(v5r) to pass (by)/to go through/to walk along/to pass exams"},
	{"question":"通信","answers":["つうしん"],"comment":"(n,vs) correspondence/communication/news/signal"},
	{"question":"通勤","answers":["つうきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) commuting to work"},
	{"question":"通学","answers":["つうがく"],"comment":"(n) commuting to school"},
	{"question":"通帳","answers":["つうちょう"],"comment":"(n) passbook"},
	{"question":"通常","answers":["つうじょう"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n-t) common/general/normal/usual"},
	{"question":"通用","answers":["つうよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) popular use/circulation"},
	{"question":"通知","answers":["つうち"],"comment":"(n,vs) notice/notification"},
	{"question":"通行","answers":["つうこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) passage/passing"},
	{"question":"通訳","answers":["つうやく"],"comment":"(n,vs) interpretation"},
	{"question":"通貨","answers":["つうか"],"comment":"(n) currency"},
	{"question":"通路","answers":["つうろ"],"comment":"(n) passage/pathway"},
	{"question":"通過","answers":["つうか"],"comment":"(n,vs) passage through/passing"},
	{"question":"速い","answers":["はやい"],"comment":"(adj) quick/fast/swift"},
	{"question":"速力","answers":["そくりょく"],"comment":"(n) speed"},
	{"question":"速度","answers":["そくど"],"comment":"(n) speed/velocity/rate"},
	{"question":"速達","answers":["そくたつ"],"comment":"(n) express/special delivery"},
	{"question":"造り","answers":["つくり"],"comment":"(n) make up/structure/physique"},
	{"question":"造る","answers":["つくる"],"comment":"(v5r) to make/to create/to manufacture/to draw up/to write/to compose/to build/to coin/to cultivate/to organize/to establish/to make up (a face)/to trim (a tree)/to fabricate/to prepare (food)/to commit (sin)/to construct"},
	{"question":"造船","answers":["ぞうせん"],"comment":"(n) shipbuilding"},
	{"question":"連なる","answers":["つらなる"],"comment":"(v5r) to extend/to stretch out/to stand in a row"},
	{"question":"連ねる","answers":["つらねる"],"comment":"(v1) to link/to join/to put together"},
	{"question":"連れ","answers":["つれ"],"comment":"(n,vs) companion/company"},
	{"question":"連れる","answers":["つれる"],"comment":"(v1) to lead/to take (a person)"},
	{"question":"連中","answers":["れんちゅう"],"comment":"(n) colleagues/company/a lot"},
	{"question":"連休","answers":["れんきゅう"],"comment":"(n) consecutive holidays"},
	{"question":"連合","answers":["れんごう"],"comment":"(n) union/alliance"},
	{"question":"連帯","answers":["れんたい"],"comment":"(n) solidarity"},
	{"question":"連想","answers":["れんそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) association (of ideas)/suggestion"},
	{"question":"連日","answers":["れんじつ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every day/prolonged"},
	{"question":"連盟","answers":["れんめい"],"comment":"(n) league/union/alliance"},
	{"question":"連絡","answers":["れんらく"],"comment":"(n,vs) junction/communication/contact/connection/coordination"},
	{"question":"連続","answers":["れんぞく"],"comment":"(n,vs) serial/consecutive/continuity/occurring in succession/continuing"},
	{"question":"連邦","answers":["れんぽう"],"comment":"(n) commonwealth/federation of states"},
	{"question":"逮捕","answers":["たいほ"],"comment":"(n,vs) arrest/apprehension/capture"},
	{"question":"週","answers":["しゅう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) week"},
	{"question":"週間","answers":["しゅうかん"],"comment":"(n) week/weekly"},
	{"question":"進み","answers":["すすみ"],"comment":"(n) progress"},
	{"question":"進む","answers":["すすむ"],"comment":"(v5m,vi) to make progress/to advance/to improve"},
	{"question":"進める","answers":["すすめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to advance/to promote/to hasten"},
	{"question":"進出","answers":["しんしゅつ"],"comment":"(n) advance/step forward"},
	{"question":"進化","answers":["しんか"],"comment":"(n) evolution/progress"},
	{"question":"進呈","answers":["しんてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) presentation"},
	{"question":"進学","answers":["しんがく"],"comment":"(n,vs) going on to university"},
	{"question":"進展","answers":["しんてん"],"comment":"(n,vs) progress/development"},
	{"question":"進度","answers":["しんど"],"comment":"(n) progress"},
	{"question":"進歩","answers":["しんぽ"],"comment":"(n,vs) progress/development"},
	{"question":"進行","answers":["しんこう"],"comment":"(n) advance"},
	{"question":"逸れる","answers":["それる"],"comment":"(v1) to stray (turn) from subject/to get lost/to go astray"},
	{"question":"遂げる","answers":["とげる"],"comment":"(v1) to accomplish/to achieve/to carry out"},
	{"question":"遂に","answers":["ついに"],"comment":"(adv) finally/at last"},
	{"question":"遅い","answers":["おそい"],"comment":"(adj) late/slow"},
	{"question":"遅くとも","answers":["おそくとも"],"comment":"(adv) at the latest"},
	{"question":"遅らす","answers":["おくらす"],"comment":"(v5s) to retard/to delay"},
	{"question":"遅れ","answers":["おくれ"],"comment":"(n) delay/lag"},
	{"question":"遅れる","answers":["おくれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be late/to be delayed/to fall behind schedule"},
	{"question":"遅刻","answers":["ちこく"],"comment":"(n,vs) lateness/late coming"},
	{"question":"遊び","answers":["あそび"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) playing"},
	{"question":"遊ぶ","answers":["あそぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) (1) to play/to make a visit (esp. for pleasure)/(2) to be idle/to do nothing"},
	{"question":"遊園地","answers":["ゆうえんち"],"comment":"(n) amusement park"},
	{"question":"遊牧","answers":["ゆうぼく"],"comment":"(n) nomadism"},
	{"question":"運","answers":["うん"],"comment":"(n) fortune/luck"},
	{"question":"運ぶ","answers":["はこぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to transport"},
	{"question":"運動","answers":["うんどう"],"comment":"(n,vs) motion/exercise"},
	{"question":"運命","answers":["うんめい"],"comment":"(n) fate"},
	{"question":"運営","answers":["うんえい"],"comment":"(n,vs) management/administration/operation"},
	{"question":"運搬","answers":["うんぱん"],"comment":"(n,vs) transport/carriage"},
	{"question":"運河","answers":["うんが"],"comment":"(n) canal/waterway"},
	{"question":"運用","answers":["うんよう"],"comment":"(n,vs) making use of/application/investment/practical use"},
	{"question":"運賃","answers":["うんちん"],"comment":"(n) freight rates/shipping expenses/fare"},
	{"question":"運転","answers":["うんてん"],"comment":"(n,vs) operation/motion/driving"},
	{"question":"運転手","answers":["うんてんしゅ"],"comment":"(n) driver/chauffeur"},
	{"question":"運輸","answers":["うんゆ"],"comment":"(n) transportation"},
	{"question":"運送","answers":["うんそう"],"comment":"(n) shipping/marine transportation"},
	{"question":"過ぎる","answers":["すぎる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to pass/to go beyond/to elapse/to exceed"},
	{"question":"過ごす","answers":["すごす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to pass/to spend/to go through/to tide over"},
	{"question":"過ち","answers":["あやまち"],"comment":"(n) fault/error/indiscretion"},
	{"question":"過剰","answers":["かじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) excess/over-"},
	{"question":"過労","answers":["かろう"],"comment":"(n) overwork/strain"},
	{"question":"過半数","answers":["かはんすう"],"comment":"(n) majority"},
	{"question":"過去","answers":["かこ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) the past/bygone days/the previous"},
	{"question":"過失","answers":["かしつ"],"comment":"(n) error/blunder/accident"},
	{"question":"過密","answers":["かみつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) crowded"},
	{"question":"過疎","answers":["かそ"],"comment":"(n) depopulation"},
	{"question":"過程","answers":["かてい"],"comment":"(n) process"},
	{"question":"道","answers":["みち"],"comment":"(n) road/street/way/method"},
	{"question":"道具","answers":["どうぐ"],"comment":"(n) implement/tool/means"},
	{"question":"道場","answers":["どうじょう"],"comment":"(n) (arch) dojo/hall used for martial arts training/mandala"},
	{"question":"道徳","answers":["どうとく"],"comment":"(n) morals"},
	{"question":"道路","answers":["どうろ"],"comment":"(n) road/highway"},
	{"question":"道順","answers":["みちじゅん"],"comment":"(n) itinerary/route"},
	{"question":"達する","answers":["たっする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to reach/to get to"},
	{"question":"達成","answers":["たっせい"],"comment":"(n,vs) achievement"},
	{"question":"達者","answers":["たっしゃ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) skillful/in good health"},
	{"question":"違い","answers":["ちがい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) difference/discrepancy"},
	{"question":"違いない","answers":["ちがいない"],"comment":"(adj,exp) (phrase) sure/no mistaking it/for certain"},
	{"question":"違う","answers":["ちがう"],"comment":"(v5u) to differ (from)"},
	{"question":"違える","answers":["ちがえる"],"comment":"(v1) to change"},
	{"question":"違反","answers":["いはん"],"comment":"(n) violation (of law)/transgression/infringement/breach"},
	{"question":"遠い","answers":["とおい"],"comment":"(adj) far/distant"},
	{"question":"遠く","answers":["とおく"],"comment":"(adj-no,n-adv,n) far away/distant/at a distance/distant place/by far"},
	{"question":"遠ざかる","answers":["とおざかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to go far off"},
	{"question":"遠回り","answers":["とおまわり"],"comment":"(n) detour/roundabout way"},
	{"question":"遠慮","answers":["えんりょ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) diffidence/restraint/reserve"},
	{"question":"遠方","answers":["えんぽう"],"comment":"(n) long way/distant place"},
	{"question":"遠足","answers":["えんそく"],"comment":"(n) trip/hike/picnic"},
	{"question":"遡る","answers":["さかのぼる"],"comment":"(v5r) to go back/to go upstream/to make retroactive"},
	{"question":"遥か","answers":["はるか"],"comment":"(adj-na,adv,n) far/far-away/distant/remote/far off"},
	{"question":"適する","answers":["てきする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to fit/to suit"},
	{"question":"適切","answers":["てきせつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) pertinent/appropriate/adequate/relevance"},
	{"question":"適宜","answers":["てきぎ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv) suitability"},
	{"question":"適度","answers":["てきど"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) moderate"},
	{"question":"適当","answers":["てきとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) fitness/suitability/adequacy/relevance"},
	{"question":"適応","answers":["てきおう"],"comment":"(n) adaptation/accommodation/conformity"},
	{"question":"適性","answers":["てきせい"],"comment":"(n) aptitude"},
	{"question":"適用","answers":["てきよう"],"comment":"(n) applying"},
	{"question":"適確","answers":["てきかく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) precise/accurate"},
	{"question":"遭う","answers":["あう"],"comment":"(v5u) to meet/to encounter (undesirable nuance)"},
	{"question":"遭難","answers":["そうなん"],"comment":"(n) disaster/shipwreck/accident"},
	{"question":"遮る","answers":["さえぎる"],"comment":"(v5r) to interrupt/to intercept/to obstruct"},
	{"question":"選ぶ","answers":["えらぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to choose/to select"},
	{"question":"選手","answers":["せんしゅ"],"comment":"(n) (1) player (in game)/(2) team"},
	{"question":"選択","answers":["せんたく"],"comment":"(n,vs) selection/choice"},
	{"question":"選挙","answers":["せんきょ"],"comment":"(n,vs) election"},
	{"question":"選考","answers":["せんこう"],"comment":"(n,vs) selection/screening"},
	{"question":"遺跡","answers":["いせき"],"comment":"(n) historic ruins (remains, relics)"},
	{"question":"避ける","answers":["さける","よける"],"comment":"(v1) (1) to avoid (physical contact with)/(2) to ward off/to avert"},
	{"question":"避難","answers":["ひなん"],"comment":"(n,vs) taking refuge/finding shelter"},
	{"question":"還元","answers":["かんげん"],"comment":"(n,vs) resolution/reduction/return to origins"},
	{"question":"還暦","answers":["かんれき"],"comment":"(n) 60th birthday"},
	{"question":"邪魔","answers":["じゃま"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) hindrance/intrusion"},
	{"question":"邸宅","answers":["ていたく"],"comment":"(n) mansion/residence"},
	{"question":"郊外","answers":["こうがい"],"comment":"(n) suburb/outskirts"},
	{"question":"郡","answers":["ぐん"],"comment":"(n) country/district"},
	{"question":"部下","answers":["ぶか"],"comment":"(n) subordinate person"},
	{"question":"部分","answers":["ぶぶん"],"comment":"(n) portion/section/part"},
	{"question":"部品","answers":["ぶひん"],"comment":"(n) parts/accessories"},
	{"question":"部屋","answers":["へや"],"comment":"(n) room"},
	{"question":"部門","answers":["ぶもん"],"comment":"(n) class/group/category/department/field/branch"},
	{"question":"部首","answers":["ぶしゅ"],"comment":"(n) radical (of a kanji character)"},
	{"question":"郵便","answers":["ゆうびん"],"comment":"(n) mail/postal service"},
	{"question":"郵便局","answers":["ゆうびんきょく"],"comment":"(n) post office"},
	{"question":"郵送","answers":["ゆうそう"],"comment":"(n,vs) mailing"},
	{"question":"郷土","answers":["きょうど"],"comment":"(n) native place/birth place/one's old home"},
	{"question":"郷愁","answers":["きょうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) nostalgia/homesickness"},
	{"question":"郷里","answers":["きょうり"],"comment":"(n) birth-place/home town"},
	{"question":"都","answers":["と","みやこ"],"comment":"(n) capital"},
	{"question":"都会","answers":["とかい"],"comment":"(n) city"},
	{"question":"都合","answers":["つごう"],"comment":"(adv,n) circumstances/condition/convenience"},
	{"question":"都市","answers":["とし"],"comment":"(n) town/city/municipal/urban"},
	{"question":"都心","answers":["としん"],"comment":"(n) heart (of city)"},
	{"question":"酌む","answers":["くむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to serve sake"},
	{"question":"配る","answers":["くばる"],"comment":"(v5r) to distribute/to deliver"},
	{"question":"配偶者","answers":["はいぐうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) spouse/wife/husband"},
	{"question":"配分","answers":["はいぶん"],"comment":"(n,vs) distribution/allotment"},
	{"question":"配列","answers":["はいれつ"],"comment":"(n) arrangement/array (programming)"},
	{"question":"配布","answers":["はいふ"],"comment":"(n,vs) distribution"},
	{"question":"配慮","answers":["はいりょ"],"comment":"(n) consideration/concern/forethought"},
	{"question":"配給","answers":["はいきゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) distribution (eg. films, rice)"},
	{"question":"配置","answers":["はいち"],"comment":"(n) arrangement (of resources)/disposition"},
	{"question":"配達","answers":["はいたつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) delivery/distribution"},
	{"question":"酒","answers":["さけ"],"comment":"(n) alcohol/sake"},
	{"question":"酒場","answers":["さかば"],"comment":"(n) bar/bar-room"},
	{"question":"酔う","answers":["よう"],"comment":"(v5u) to get drunk/to become intoxicated"},
	{"question":"酔っ払い","answers":["よっぱらい"],"comment":"(n) drunkard"},
	{"question":"酢","answers":["す"],"comment":"(n) vinegar"},
	{"question":"酪農","answers":["らくのう"],"comment":"(n) dairy (farm)"},
	{"question":"酸","answers":["さん"],"comment":"(n) acid"},
	{"question":"酸化","answers":["さんか"],"comment":"(n) oxidation"},
	{"question":"酸性","answers":["さんせい"],"comment":"(n) acidity"},
	{"question":"酸素","answers":["さんそ"],"comment":"(n) oxygen"},
	{"question":"醜い","answers":["みにくい"],"comment":"(adj) ugly"},
	{"question":"醤油","answers":["しょうゆ"],"comment":"(n) soy sauce"},
	{"question":"重い","answers":["おもい"],"comment":"(adj) (1) heavy/massive/(2) serious/important/severe/oppressed"},
	{"question":"重たい","answers":["おもたい"],"comment":"(adj) heavy/massive/serious/important/severe/oppressed"},
	{"question":"重なる","answers":["かさなる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be piled up/lie on top of one another/overlap each other"},
	{"question":"重ねる","answers":["かさねる"],"comment":"(v1) to pile up/to put something on another/to heap up/to add/to repeat"},
	{"question":"重んじる","answers":["おもんじる"],"comment":"(v1) to respect/to honor/to esteem/to prize"},
	{"question":"重んずる","answers":["おもんずる"],"comment":"(v5z) to honor/to respect/to esteem/to prize"},
	{"question":"重体","answers":["じゅうたい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) seriously ill/serious condition/critical state"},
	{"question":"重力","answers":["じゅうりょく"],"comment":"(n) gravity"},
	{"question":"重大","answers":["じゅうだい"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) serious/important/grave/weighty"},
	{"question":"重宝","answers":["ちょうほう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,vs) priceless treasure/convenience/usefulness"},
	{"question":"重役","answers":["じゅうやく"],"comment":"(n) director/high executive"},
	{"question":"重点","answers":["じゅうてん"],"comment":"(n) important point/lay stress on/colon/emphasis"},
	{"question":"重複","answers":["じゅうふく","ちょうふく"],"comment":"(n,vs) duplication/repetition/overlapping/redundancy/restoration"},
	{"question":"重要","answers":["じゅうよう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) important/momentous/essential/principal/major"},
	{"question":"重視","answers":["じゅうし"],"comment":"(n,vs) importance/stress/serious consideration"},
	{"question":"重量","answers":["じゅうりょう"],"comment":"(n) (1) weight/(2) heavyweight boxer"},
	{"question":"野","answers":["の"],"comment":"(n) field"},
	{"question":"野党","answers":["やとう"],"comment":"(n) opposition party"},
	{"question":"野外","answers":["やがい"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) fields/outskirts/open air/suburbs"},
	{"question":"野心","answers":["やしん"],"comment":"(n) ambition/aspiration/designs/treachery"},
	{"question":"野生","answers":["やせい"],"comment":"(n) wild"},
	{"question":"野菜","answers":["やさい"],"comment":"(n) vegetable"},
	{"question":"量","answers":["りょう"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) quantity/amount/volume/portion (of food)"},
	{"question":"量る","answers":["はかる"],"comment":"(v5r) to measure/to weigh/to survey/to time (sound, gauge, estimate)"},
	{"question":"金","answers":["かね","きん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) (1) gold/(2) gold general (shogi) (abbr)"},
	{"question":"金属","answers":["きんぞく"],"comment":"(n) metal"},
	{"question":"金庫","answers":["きんこ"],"comment":"(n) safe/vault/treasury/provider of funds"},
	{"question":"金持ち","answers":["かねもち"],"comment":"(n) rich man"},
	{"question":"金曜","answers":["きんよう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) (abbr) Friday"},
	{"question":"金曜日","answers":["きんようび"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) Friday"},
	{"question":"金槌","answers":["かなづち"],"comment":"(n) (iron) hammer"},
	{"question":"金融","answers":["きんゆう"],"comment":"(n) monetary circulation/credit situation"},
	{"question":"金銭","answers":["きんせん"],"comment":"(n) money/cash"},
	{"question":"金額","answers":["きんがく"],"comment":"(n) amount of money"},
	{"question":"金魚","answers":["きんぎょ"],"comment":"(n) goldfish"},
	{"question":"釘","answers":["くぎ"],"comment":"(n) nail"},
	{"question":"釜","answers":["かま"],"comment":"(n) iron pot/kettle"},
	{"question":"針","answers":["はり"],"comment":"(n) needle/fish hook/pointer/hand (e.g. clock)"},
	{"question":"針路","answers":["しんろ"],"comment":"(n) course/direction/compass bearing"},
	{"question":"針金","answers":["はりがね"],"comment":"(n) wire"},
	{"question":"釣り合う","answers":["つりあう"],"comment":"(v5u) to balance/to be in harmony/to suit"},
	{"question":"釣り鐘","answers":["つりがね"],"comment":"(n) temple bell (for striking)"},
	{"question":"釣る","answers":["つる","つる"],"comment":"(v5r) to fish"},
	{"question":"鈍い","answers":["にぶい","のろい"],"comment":"(adj) dull (e.g. a knife)/thickheaded/slow (opposite of fast)/stupid"},
	{"question":"鈍る","answers":["にぶる"],"comment":"(v5r) to become less capable/to grow dull/to become blunt/to weaken"},
	{"question":"鈍感","answers":["どんかん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) thickheadedness/stolidity"},
	{"question":"鈴","answers":["すず"],"comment":"(n) bell"},
	{"question":"鉄","answers":["てつ"],"comment":"(n) iron"},
	{"question":"鉄棒","answers":["てつぼう"],"comment":"(n) iron rod/crowbar/horizontal bar (gymnastics)"},
	{"question":"鉄橋","answers":["てっきょう"],"comment":"(n) railway bridge/iron bridge"},
	{"question":"鉄砲","answers":["てっぽう"],"comment":"(n) gun"},
	{"question":"鉄道","answers":["てつどう"],"comment":"(n) railroad"},
	{"question":"鉄鋼","answers":["てっこう"],"comment":"(n) iron and steel"},
	{"question":"鉛","answers":["なまり"],"comment":"(n) lead (the metal)"},
	{"question":"鉛筆","answers":["えんぴつ"],"comment":"(n) pencil"},
	{"question":"鉢","answers":["はち"],"comment":"(n) a bowl/a pot/a basin/a flowerpot/a crown/a brainpan"},
	{"question":"鉱山","answers":["こうざん"],"comment":"(n) mine (ore)"},
	{"question":"鉱業","answers":["こうぎょう"],"comment":"(n) mining industry"},
	{"question":"鉱物","answers":["こうぶつ"],"comment":"(n) mineral"},
	{"question":"銀","answers":["ぎん"],"comment":"(n) (1) silver/silver coin/silver paint"},
	{"question":"銀行","answers":["ぎんこう"],"comment":"(n) bank"},
	{"question":"銃","answers":["じゅう"],"comment":"gun"},
	{"question":"銅","answers":["どう"],"comment":"(n) copper"},
	{"question":"銘々","answers":["めいめい"],"comment":"(n) each/individual"},
	{"question":"鋭い","answers":["するどい"],"comment":"(adj) pointed/sharp"},
	{"question":"錆","answers":["さび"],"comment":"(n) rust (colour)"},
	{"question":"錆びる","answers":["さびる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to rust/to become rusty"},
	{"question":"錯誤","answers":["さくご"],"comment":"(n) mistake"},
	{"question":"録音","answers":["ろくおん"],"comment":"(n,vs) (audio) recording"},
	{"question":"鍋","answers":["なべ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) saucepan/pot"},
	{"question":"鍛える","answers":["きたえる"],"comment":"(v1) to forge/to drill/to temper/to train/to discipline"},
	{"question":"鍵","answers":["かぎ"],"comment":"(n) key"},
	{"question":"鎖","answers":["くさり"],"comment":"(n) chain"},
	{"question":"鏡","answers":["かがみ"],"comment":"(n) mirror"},
	{"question":"鐘","answers":["かね"],"comment":"(n) bell/chime"},
	{"question":"鑑賞","answers":["かんしょう"],"comment":"(n,vs) appreciation"},
	{"question":"長々","answers":["ながなが"],"comment":"(adv) long/drawn-out/very long"},
	{"question":"長い","answers":["ながい"],"comment":"(adj) long"},
	{"question":"長女","answers":["ちょうじょ"],"comment":"(n) eldest daughter"},
	{"question":"長官","answers":["ちょうかん"],"comment":"(n) chief/(government) secretary"},
	{"question":"長引く","answers":["ながびく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be prolonged/to drag on"},
	{"question":"長所","answers":["ちょうしょ"],"comment":"(n) (1) strong point/merit/(2) advantage"},
	{"question":"長方形","answers":["ちょうほうけい"],"comment":"(n) rectangle/oblong"},
	{"question":"長期","answers":["ちょうき"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) long time period"},
	{"question":"長男","answers":["ちょうなん"],"comment":"(n) eldest son"},
	{"question":"長短","answers":["ちょうたん"],"comment":"(n) length/long and short/+-"},
	{"question":"長編","answers":["ちょうへん"],"comment":"(n) long (e.g. novel, film)"},
	{"question":"門","answers":["もん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) gate"},
	{"question":"閉じる","answers":["とじる"],"comment":"(v1) to close (e.g. book, eyes, meeting, etc.)/to shut"},
	{"question":"閉まる","answers":["しまる"],"comment":"(v5r,vi) to close/to be closed"},
	{"question":"閉める","answers":["しめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to close/to shut"},
	{"question":"閉会","answers":["へいかい"],"comment":"(n,vs) closure"},
	{"question":"閉口","answers":["へいこう"],"comment":"(n) shut mouth"},
	{"question":"閉鎖","answers":["へいさ"],"comment":"(n,vs) closing/closure/shutdown/lockout/unsociable"},
	{"question":"開く","answers":["あく","ひらく"],"comment":"(v5k) to open (e.g. a festival)"},
	{"question":"開ける","answers":["あける"],"comment":"(v1) to become civilized/to become opened up/be up-to-date"},
	{"question":"開会","answers":["かいかい"],"comment":"(n) opening of a meeting"},
	{"question":"開催","answers":["かいさい"],"comment":"(n,vs) holding a meeting/open an exhibition"},
	{"question":"開始","answers":["かいし"],"comment":"(n,vs) start/commencement/beginning"},
	{"question":"開拓","answers":["かいたく"],"comment":"(n,vs) reclamation (of wasteland)/cultivation/pioneer"},
	{"question":"開放","answers":["かいほう"],"comment":"(n,vs) open/throw open/liberalization"},
	{"question":"開発","answers":["かいはつ"],"comment":"(n) development/exploitation"},
	{"question":"開通","answers":["かいつう"],"comment":"(n,vs) opening/open"},
	{"question":"間","answers":["あいだ","ま"],"comment":"(n) space/room/time/pause"},
	{"question":"間に合う","answers":["まにあう"],"comment":"(v5u) (1) to be in time for/(2) to serve (suit, meet) the purpose/to be good enough/to be enough"},
	{"question":"間も無く","answers":["まもなく"],"comment":"(adv) soon/before long/in a short time"},
	{"question":"間接","answers":["かんせつ"],"comment":"(n) indirection/indirectness"},
	{"question":"間柄","answers":["あいだがら"],"comment":"(n) relation(ship)"},
	{"question":"間違い","answers":["まちがい"],"comment":"(n) mistake"},
	{"question":"間違える","answers":["まちがえる"],"comment":"(v1) to err/to make a mistake"},
	{"question":"間隔","answers":["かんかく"],"comment":"(n) space/interval/SPC"},
	{"question":"関する","answers":["かんする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to concern/to be related"},
	{"question":"関与","answers":["かんよ"],"comment":"(n,vs) participation/taking part in/participating in/being concerned in"},
	{"question":"関係","answers":["かんけい"],"comment":"(n,vs) relation/connection"},
	{"question":"関心","answers":["かんしん"],"comment":"(n) concern/interest"},
	{"question":"関東","answers":["かんとう"],"comment":"Kantou (eastern half of Japan, including Tokyo)"},
	{"question":"関税","answers":["かんぜい"],"comment":"(n) customs/duty/tariff"},
	{"question":"関西","answers":["かんさい"],"comment":"Kansai (south-western half of Japan, including Osaka)"},
	{"question":"関連","answers":["かんれん"],"comment":"(n) relation/connection/relevance"},
	{"question":"閲覧","answers":["えつらん"],"comment":"(n,vs) inspection/reading"},
	{"question":"闇","answers":["やみ"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) darkness/the dark/black-marketeering/dark/shady/illegal"},
	{"question":"防ぐ","answers":["ふせぐ"],"comment":"(v5g,vt) to defend (against)/to protect/to prevent"},
	{"question":"防止","answers":["ぼうし"],"comment":"(n) prevention/check"},
	{"question":"防火","answers":["ぼうか"],"comment":"(n) fire prevention/fire fighting/fire proof"},
	{"question":"防犯","answers":["ぼうはん"],"comment":"(n) prevention of crime"},
	{"question":"防衛","answers":["ぼうえい"],"comment":"(n) defense/protection/self-defense"},
	{"question":"阻む","answers":["はばむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to keep someone from doing/to stop/to prevent/to check/to hinder/to obstruct/to oppose/to thwart"},
	{"question":"阻止","answers":["そし"],"comment":"(n,vs) obstruction/check/hindrance/prevention/interdiction"},
	{"question":"附属","answers":["ふぞく"],"comment":"(n,vs) attached/belonging/affiliated/annexed/associated/subordinate/incidental/dependent/auxiliary"},
	{"question":"降りる","answers":["おりる"],"comment":"(v1) to alight (e.g. from bus)/to get off/to descend (e.g. a mountain)"},
	{"question":"降る","answers":["ふる"],"comment":"(v5r) to precipitate/to fall (e.g. rain)"},
	{"question":"降ろす","answers":["おろす"],"comment":"(v5s) to take down/to launch/to drop/to lower/to let (a person) off/to unload/to discharge"},
	{"question":"降伏","answers":["こうふく"],"comment":"(n) capitulation/surrender/submission"},
	{"question":"降水","answers":["こうすい"],"comment":"(n) rainfall/precipitation"},
	{"question":"限り","answers":["かぎり"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) limit(s)/as far as possible/as much as possible/to the best of one's ability"},
	{"question":"限る","answers":["かぎる"],"comment":"(v5r) to restrict/to limit/to confine"},
	{"question":"限定","answers":["げんてい"],"comment":"(n,vs) limit/restriction"},
	{"question":"限度","answers":["げんど"],"comment":"(n) limit/bounds"},
	{"question":"限界","answers":["げんかい"],"comment":"(n) limit/bound"},
	{"question":"陣","answers":["じん"],"comment":"(n) battle formation/camp/encampment"},
	{"question":"除く","answers":["のぞく"],"comment":"(v5k) to remove/to exclude/to except"},
	{"question":"除外","answers":["じょがい"],"comment":"(n,vs) exception/exclusion"},
	{"question":"陰","answers":["かげ"],"comment":"(n) shade/shadow/other side"},
	{"question":"陰気","answers":["いんき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) gloom/melancholy"},
	{"question":"陳列","answers":["ちんれつ"],"comment":"(n,vs) exhibition/display/show"},
	{"question":"陶器","answers":["とうき"],"comment":"(n) pottery/ceramics"},
	{"question":"陸","answers":["りく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) six (used in legal documents)"},
	{"question":"険しい","answers":["けわしい"],"comment":"(adj) inaccessible place/impregnable position/steep place/sharp eyes"},
	{"question":"陽射","answers":["ひざし"],"comment":"(n) sunlight/rays of the sun"},
	{"question":"陽気","answers":["ようき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) season/weather/cheerfulness"},
	{"question":"隅","answers":["すみ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) corner/nook"},
	{"question":"隊","answers":["たい"],"comment":"(n) party/company/body (of troops)/corps"},
	{"question":"階層","answers":["かいそう"],"comment":"(n) class/level/stratum/hierarchy"},
	{"question":"階段","answers":["かいだん"],"comment":"(n) stairs"},
	{"question":"階級","answers":["かいきゅう"],"comment":"(n) class/rank/grade"},
	{"question":"随分","answers":["ずいぶん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n-adv) extremely"},
	{"question":"随筆","answers":["ずいひつ"],"comment":"(n) essays/miscellaneous writings"},
	{"question":"隔たる","answers":["へだたる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be distant"},
	{"question":"隔てる","answers":["へだてる"],"comment":"(v1) to be shut out"},
	{"question":"隔週","answers":["かくしゅう"],"comment":"(n-adv,n-t) every other week"},
	{"question":"隙","answers":["すき"],"comment":"(n) (1) chance or opportunity/chink (in one's armor)/(2) interval/gap"},
	{"question":"隙間","answers":["すきま"],"comment":"(n) crevice/crack/gap/opening"},
	{"question":"際","answers":["さい"],"comment":"(n-adv,n) on the occasion of/circumstances"},
	{"question":"障る","answers":["さわる"],"comment":"(v5r) to hinder/to interfere with/to affect/to do one harm/to be harmful to"},
	{"question":"障子","answers":["しょうじ"],"comment":"(n) paper sliding door"},
	{"question":"障害","answers":["しょうがい"],"comment":"(n) obstacle/impediment (fault)/damage"},
	{"question":"隠す","answers":["かくす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to hide/to conceal"},
	{"question":"隠れる","answers":["かくれる"],"comment":"(v1,vi) to hide/to be hidden/to conceal oneself/to disappear"},
	{"question":"隠居","answers":["いんきょ"],"comment":"(n) (1) retirement/(2) retired person"},
	{"question":"隣","answers":["となり"],"comment":"(n) next to/next door to"},
	{"question":"雄","answers":["おす"],"comment":"(n) male (animal)"},
	{"question":"集まり","answers":["あつまり"],"comment":"(n) gathering/meeting/assembly/collection"},
	{"question":"集める","answers":["あつめる"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to collect/to assemble"},
	{"question":"集る","answers":["あつまる"],"comment":"(v5r) (1) to gather/to crowd round/to swarm/to flock/(2) to extort from/to sponge off"},
	{"question":"集中","answers":["しゅうちゅう"],"comment":"(n,vs) concentration/focusing the mind"},
	{"question":"集会","answers":["しゅうかい"],"comment":"(n) meeting/assembly"},
	{"question":"集合","answers":["しゅうごう"],"comment":"(n,vs) gathering/assembly/meeting/set (math)"},
	{"question":"集団","answers":["しゅうだん"],"comment":"(n) group/mass"},
	{"question":"集計","answers":["しゅうけい"],"comment":"(n,vs) totalization/aggregate"},
	{"question":"集金","answers":["しゅうきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) money collection"},
	{"question":"雇う","answers":["やとう"],"comment":"(v5u) to employ/to hire"},
	{"question":"雌","answers":["めす"],"comment":"(n) female (animal)"},
	{"question":"雑","answers":["ざつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) rough/crude"},
	{"question":"雑巾","answers":["ぞうきん"],"comment":"(n) house-cloth/dust cloth"},
	{"question":"雑木","answers":["ぞうき"],"comment":"(n) various kinds of small trees/assorted trees"},
	{"question":"雑誌","answers":["ざっし"],"comment":"(n) journal/magazine"},
	{"question":"雑談","answers":["ざつだん"],"comment":"(n,vs) chatting/idle talk"},
	{"question":"雑貨","answers":["ざっか"],"comment":"(n) miscellaneous goods/general goods/sundries"},
	{"question":"雑音","answers":["ざつおん"],"comment":"(n) noise (jarring, grating)"},
	{"question":"雛","answers":["ひな"],"comment":"(n) young bird/chick/doll"},
	{"question":"雛祭","answers":["ひなまつり"],"comment":"(n) Girls' (dolls') Festival"},
	{"question":"離す","answers":["はなす"],"comment":"(v5s) to part/divide/separate"},
	{"question":"離れる","answers":["はなれる"],"comment":"(v1) to be separated from/to leave/to go away/to be a long way off"},
	{"question":"離婚","answers":["りこん"],"comment":"(n,vs) divorce"},
	{"question":"難","answers":["なん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) difficulty/hardships/defect"},
	{"question":"難しい","answers":["むずかしい"],"comment":"(adj) difficult"},
	{"question":"雨","answers":["あめ"],"comment":"(n) rain"},
	{"question":"雨具","answers":["あまぐ"],"comment":"(n) rain gear"},
	{"question":"雨天","answers":["うてん"],"comment":"(n) rainy weather"},
	{"question":"雨戸","answers":["あまど"],"comment":"(n) sliding storm door"},
	{"question":"雪","answers":["ゆき"],"comment":"(n) snow"},
	{"question":"雪崩","answers":["なだれ"],"comment":"(n) avalanche"},
	{"question":"雫","answers":["しずく"],"comment":"(n) drop (of water)"},
	{"question":"雰囲気","answers":["ふんいき"],"comment":"(n) atmosphere (e.g. musical)/mood/ambience"},
	{"question":"雲","answers":["くも"],"comment":"(n) cloud"},
	{"question":"零","answers":["れい"],"comment":"(n) zero/nought"},
	{"question":"零点","answers":["れいてん"],"comment":"(n) zero/no marks"},
	{"question":"雷","answers":["かみなり"],"comment":"(n) thunder"},
	{"question":"電力","answers":["でんりょく"],"comment":"(n) electric power"},
	{"question":"電報","answers":["でんぽう"],"comment":"(n) telegram"},
	{"question":"電子","answers":["でんし"],"comment":"(n) electron"},
	{"question":"電柱","answers":["でんちゅう"],"comment":"(n) telephone pole/telegraph pole/lightpole"},
	{"question":"電気","answers":["でんき"],"comment":"(n) electricity/(electric) light"},
	{"question":"電池","answers":["でんち"],"comment":"(n) battery"},
	{"question":"電波","answers":["でんぱ"],"comment":"(n) electro-magnetic wave"},
	{"question":"電流","answers":["でんりゅう"],"comment":"(n) electric current"},
	{"question":"電源","answers":["でんげん"],"comment":"(n) source of electricity/power (button on TV, etc.)"},
	{"question":"電灯","answers":["でんとう"],"comment":"(n) electric light"},
	{"question":"電球","answers":["でんきゅう"],"comment":"(n) light bulb"},
	{"question":"電話","answers":["でんわ"],"comment":"(n,vs) telephone"},
	{"question":"電車","answers":["でんしゃ"],"comment":"(n) electric train"},
	{"question":"需要","answers":["じゅよう"],"comment":"(n) demand/request"},
	{"question":"震える","answers":["ふるえる"],"comment":"(v1) to shiver/to shake/to quake"},
	{"question":"震わせる","answers":["ふるわせる"],"comment":"(v1) to be shaking/to be trembling"},
	{"question":"霜","answers":["しも"],"comment":"(n) frost"},
	{"question":"霞む","answers":["かすむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to grow hazy/to be misty"},
	{"question":"霧","answers":["きり"],"comment":"(n) fog/mist"},
	{"question":"霰","answers":["あられ"],"comment":"(n) hail (i.e. falling iceballs)"},
	{"question":"露","answers":["つゆ"],"comment":"(adv,n) dew"},
	{"question":"露骨","answers":["ろこつ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) (1) frank/blunt/plain/outspoken/(2) conspicuous/open/(3) broad/suggestive"},
	{"question":"青","answers":["あお"],"comment":"(n) blue/green/green light"},
	{"question":"青い","answers":["あおい"],"comment":"(adj) blue/pale/green/unripe/inexperienced"},
	{"question":"青少年","answers":["せいしょうねん"],"comment":"(n) youth/young person"},
	{"question":"青年","answers":["せいねん"],"comment":"(n) youth/young man"},
	{"question":"青春","answers":["せいしゅん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) youth/springtime of life/adolescent"},
	{"question":"青白い","answers":["あおじろい"],"comment":"(adj) pale/pallid"},
	{"question":"静か","answers":["しずか"],"comment":"(adj-na) quiet/peaceful"},
	{"question":"静まる","answers":["しずまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to quieten down/to calm down/to subside/to die down/to abate/to be suppressed"},
	{"question":"静止","answers":["せいし"],"comment":"(n) stillness/repose/standing still"},
	{"question":"静的","answers":["せいてき"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) static"},
	{"question":"非常","answers":["ひじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) emergency/extraordinary/unusual"},
	{"question":"非常に","answers":["ひじょうに"],"comment":"(adv) very/extremely/exceedingly"},
	{"question":"非行","answers":["ひこう"],"comment":"(n) delinquency/misconduct"},
	{"question":"非難","answers":["ひなん"],"comment":"(n,vs) blame/attack/criticism"},
	{"question":"面","answers":["めん"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) face/mug/surface/facial features/mask/face guard/side or facet/corner/page"},
	{"question":"面する","answers":["めんする"],"comment":"(vs-s) to face on/to look out on to"},
	{"question":"面会","answers":["めんかい"],"comment":"(n) interview"},
	{"question":"面倒","answers":["めんどう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) trouble/difficulty/care/attention"},
	{"question":"面倒臭い","answers":["めんどうくさい"],"comment":"(adj) bother to do/tiresome"},
	{"question":"面接","answers":["めんせつ"],"comment":"(n) interview"},
	{"question":"面目","answers":["めんぼく","めんもく"],"comment":"(n) face/honour/reputation/prestige/dignity/credit"},
	{"question":"面積","answers":["めんせき"],"comment":"(n) area"},
	{"question":"革","answers":["かわ"],"comment":"(n) leather"},
	{"question":"革命","answers":["かくめい"],"comment":"(n) revolution"},
	{"question":"革新","answers":["かくしん"],"comment":"(n) reform/innovation"},
	{"question":"靴","answers":["くつ"],"comment":"(n) shoes/footwear"},
	{"question":"靴下","answers":["くつした"],"comment":"(n) socks"},
	{"question":"鞠","answers":["まり"],"comment":"(n) ball"},
	{"question":"音","answers":["おと","おん","ね"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) sound/note"},
	{"question":"音楽","answers":["おんがく"],"comment":"(n) music/musical movement"},
	{"question":"音色","answers":["ねいろ"],"comment":"(n) tone color/tone quality/timbre/synthesizer patch"},
	{"question":"響き","answers":["ひびき"],"comment":"(n) echo/sound/reverberation/noise"},
	{"question":"響く","answers":["ひびく"],"comment":"(v5k) to resound"},
	{"question":"頂く","answers":["いただく"],"comment":"(v5k) to receive/to take food or drink (hum)/to be crowned with/to wear/to live under (a ruler)/to install (a president)/to accept/to buy/to take"},
	{"question":"頂上","answers":["ちょうじょう"],"comment":"(n) top/summit/peak"},
	{"question":"頂点","answers":["ちょうてん"],"comment":"(n) top/summit"},
	{"question":"頃","answers":["ころ"],"comment":"(n-adv,n,n-suf) (uk) time/about/toward/approximately (time)"},
	{"question":"項目","answers":["こうもく"],"comment":"(n) item"},
	{"question":"順","answers":["じゅん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,n-suf) order/turn"},
	{"question":"順々","answers":["じゅんじゅん"],"comment":"(adv,n) in order/in turn"},
	{"question":"順序","answers":["じゅんじょ"],"comment":"(n) order/sequence/procedure"},
	{"question":"順番","answers":["じゅんばん"],"comment":"(n) turn (in line)/order of things"},
	{"question":"順調","answers":["じゅんちょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) favourable/doing well/O.K./all right"},
	{"question":"預かる","answers":["あずかる"],"comment":"(v5r,vt) to keep in custody/to receive on deposit/to take charge of"},
	{"question":"預ける","answers":["あずける"],"comment":"(v1,vt) to give into custody/to leave (a child) in the care of/to entrust/to deposit"},
	{"question":"預金","answers":["よきん"],"comment":"(n,vs) deposit/bank account"},
	{"question":"頑丈","answers":["がんじょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) solid/firm/stout/burly/strong/sturdy"},
	{"question":"頑固","answers":["がんこ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) stubbornness/obstinacy"},
	{"question":"頑張る","answers":["がんばる"],"comment":"(v5r) to persist/to insist on/to stand firm/to try one's best"},
	{"question":"領事","answers":["りょうじ"],"comment":"(n) consul"},
	{"question":"領収","answers":["りょうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) receipt/voucher"},
	{"question":"領土","answers":["りょうど"],"comment":"(n) dominion/territory/possession"},
	{"question":"領地","answers":["りょうち"],"comment":"(n) territory/dominion"},
	{"question":"領域","answers":["りょういき"],"comment":"(n) area/domain/territory/field/region/regime"},
	{"question":"領海","answers":["りょうかい"],"comment":"(n) territorial waters"},
	{"question":"頬","answers":["ほお","ほほ"],"comment":"(n) cheek (of face)"},
	{"question":"頭","answers":["あたま","かしら"],"comment":"counter for large animals"},
	{"question":"頭痛","answers":["ずつう"],"comment":"(n) headache"},
	{"question":"頭脳","answers":["ずのう"],"comment":"(n) head/brains/intellect"},
	{"question":"頻繁","answers":["ひんぱん"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) frequency"},
	{"question":"頼む","answers":["たのむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to request/to beg/to ask"},
	{"question":"頼もしい","answers":["たのもしい"],"comment":"(adj) reliable/trustworthy/hopeful/promising"},
	{"question":"頼る","answers":["たよる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rely on/to have recourse to/to depend on"},
	{"question":"題","answers":["だい"],"comment":"(n,vs) title/subject/theme/topic"},
	{"question":"題名","answers":["だいめい"],"comment":"(n) title"},
	{"question":"額","answers":["がく","ひたい"],"comment":"(n) forehead/brow"},
	{"question":"顎","answers":["あご"],"comment":"(n) chin"},
	{"question":"顔","answers":["かお"],"comment":"(n) face (person)"},
	{"question":"顔付き","answers":["かおつき"],"comment":"(n) (outward) looks/features/face/countenance/expression"},
	{"question":"顕微鏡","answers":["けんびきょう"],"comment":"(n) microscope"},
	{"question":"願い","answers":["ねがい"],"comment":"(n) desire/wish/request/prayer/petition/application"},
	{"question":"願う","answers":["ねがう"],"comment":"(v5u) to desire/to wish/to request/to beg/to hope/to implore"},
	{"question":"願書","answers":["がんしょ"],"comment":"(n) written application or petition"},
	{"question":"類","answers":["るい"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) kind/sort/class/family/genus"},
	{"question":"類似","answers":["るいじ"],"comment":"(n) analogous"},
	{"question":"類推","answers":["るいすい"],"comment":"(n) analogy"},
	{"question":"顧みる","answers":["かえりみる"],"comment":"(v1) to look back/to turn around/to review"},
	{"question":"風","answers":["かぜ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n,n-suf) method/manner/way"},
	{"question":"風俗","answers":["ふうぞく"],"comment":"(n) (1) manners/customs/(2) sex service/sex industry"},
	{"question":"風呂","answers":["ふろ"],"comment":"(n) bath"},
	{"question":"風呂敷","answers":["ふろしき"],"comment":"(n) wrapping cloth/cloth wrapper"},
	{"question":"風土","answers":["ふうど"],"comment":"(n) natural features/topography/climate/spiritual features"},
	{"question":"風景","answers":["ふうけい"],"comment":"(n) scenery"},
	{"question":"風習","answers":["ふうしゅう"],"comment":"(n) custom"},
	{"question":"風船","answers":["ふうせん"],"comment":"(n) balloon"},
	{"question":"風車","answers":["ふうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) (1) windmill"},
	{"question":"風邪","answers":["かぜ"],"comment":"(n) cold (illness)/common cold"},
	{"question":"飛ばす","answers":["とばす"],"comment":"(v5s) to skip over/to omit"},
	{"question":"飛び出す","answers":["とびだす"],"comment":"(v5s) to jump out/to rush out/to fly out/to appear suddenly/to protrude/to project"},
	{"question":"飛び込む","answers":["とびこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to jump in/to leap in/to plunge into/to dive"},
	{"question":"飛ぶ","answers":["とぶ"],"comment":"(v5b) to jump/to fly/to leap/to spring/to bound/to hop"},
	{"question":"飛行","answers":["ひこう"],"comment":"(n) aviation"},
	{"question":"飛行場","answers":["ひこうじょう"],"comment":"(n) airport"},
	{"question":"飛行機","answers":["ひこうき"],"comment":"(n) aeroplane"},
	{"question":"食い違う","answers":["くいちがう"],"comment":"(v5u) to cross each other/to run counter to/to differ/to clash/to go awry"},
	{"question":"食う","answers":["くう"],"comment":"(v5u) (male) (vulg) to eat"},
	{"question":"食べる","answers":["たべる"],"comment":"(v1) to eat"},
	{"question":"食べ物","answers":["たべもの"],"comment":"(n) food"},
	{"question":"食事","answers":["しょくじ"],"comment":"(n,vs) meal"},
	{"question":"食卓","answers":["しょくたく"],"comment":"(n) dining table"},
	{"question":"食品","answers":["しょくひん"],"comment":"(n) commodity/foodstuff"},
	{"question":"食器","answers":["しょっき"],"comment":"(n) tableware"},
	{"question":"食堂","answers":["しょくどう"],"comment":"(n) cafeteria/dining hall"},
	{"question":"食塩","answers":["しょくえん"],"comment":"(n) table salt"},
	{"question":"食料","answers":["しょくりょう"],"comment":"(n) food"},
	{"question":"食料品","answers":["しょくりょうひん"],"comment":"(n) foodstuff/groceries"},
	{"question":"食欲","answers":["しょくよく"],"comment":"(n) appetite (for food)"},
	{"question":"食物","answers":["しょくもつ"],"comment":"(n) food/foodstuff"},
	{"question":"食糧","answers":["しょくりょう"],"comment":"(n) provisions/rations"},
	{"question":"飢える","answers":["うえる"],"comment":"(v1) to starve"},
	{"question":"飢饉","answers":["ききん"],"comment":"(n) famine"},
	{"question":"飯","answers":["めし"],"comment":"(n) (sl) meals/food"},
	{"question":"飲み物","answers":["のみもの"],"comment":"(n) drink/beverage"},
	{"question":"飲み込む","answers":["のみこむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to gulp down/to swallow deeply/to understand/to take in/to catch on to/to learn/to digest"},
	{"question":"飲む","answers":["のむ"],"comment":"(v5m) to drink"},
	{"question":"飴","answers":["あめ"],"comment":"(n) (hard) candy"},
	{"question":"飼う","answers":["かう"],"comment":"(v5u) to keep/to raise/to feed"},
	{"question":"飼育","answers":["しいく"],"comment":"(n,vs) breeding/raising/rearing"},
	{"question":"飽きる","answers":["あきる"],"comment":"(v1) to get tired of/to lose interest in/to have enough"},
	{"question":"飽くまで","answers":["あくまで"],"comment":"(adv) to the end/to the last/stubbornly/persistently"},
	{"question":"飽和","answers":["ほうわ"],"comment":"(n) saturation"},
	{"question":"飾り","answers":["かざり"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) decoration"},
	{"question":"飾る","answers":["かざる"],"comment":"(v5r) to decorate/to ornament/to adorn"},
	{"question":"餅","answers":["もち"],"comment":"(n) (uk) sticky rice cake"},
	{"question":"養う","answers":["やしなう"],"comment":"(v5u) to rear/to maintain/to cultivate"},
	{"question":"養分","answers":["ようぶん"],"comment":"(n) nourishment/nutrient"},
	{"question":"養護","answers":["ようご"],"comment":"(n,vs) protection/nursing/protective care"},
	{"question":"餌","answers":["えさ"],"comment":"(n) feed/bait"},
	{"question":"首","answers":["くび"],"comment":"(n) neck"},
	{"question":"首相","answers":["しゅしょう"],"comment":"(n) Prime Minister"},
	{"question":"首脳","answers":["しゅのう"],"comment":"(n) head/brains"},
	{"question":"首輪","answers":["くびわ"],"comment":"(n) necklace/choker"},
	{"question":"首都","answers":["しゅと"],"comment":"(n) capital city"},
	{"question":"首飾り","answers":["くびかざり"],"comment":"(n) necklace"},
	{"question":"香り","answers":["かおり"],"comment":"(n) aroma/fragrance/scent/smell"},
	{"question":"香水","answers":["こうすい"],"comment":"(n) perfume"},
	{"question":"香辛料","answers":["こうしんりょう"],"comment":"(n) spices"},
	{"question":"馬","answers":["うま"],"comment":"(n) (1) horse/(2) promoted bishop (shogi)"},
	{"question":"馬鹿","answers":["ばか"],"comment":"(adj-na,exp,n) fool/idiot/trivial matter/folly"},
	{"question":"馴らす","answers":["ならす"],"comment":"(v5s) to domesticate/to tame"},
	{"question":"馴れる","answers":["なれる"],"comment":"(v1) to become domesticated/to become tame/to get too familiar with"},
	{"question":"駄作","answers":["ださく"],"comment":"(n) poor work/rubbish"},
	{"question":"駄目","answers":["だめ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) useless/no good/hopeless"},
	{"question":"駅","answers":["えき"],"comment":"(n) station"},
	{"question":"駆ける","answers":["かける"],"comment":"(v1) to run (race, esp. horse)/to gallop/to canter"},
	{"question":"駆け足","answers":["かけあし"],"comment":"(n) running fast/double time"},
	{"question":"駐車","answers":["ちゅうしゃ"],"comment":"(n) parking (e.g. car)"},
	{"question":"駐車場","answers":["ちゅうしゃじょう"],"comment":"(n) parking lot/parking place"},
	{"question":"騒々しい","answers":["そうぞうしい"],"comment":"(adj) noisy/boisterous"},
	{"question":"騒がしい","answers":["さわがしい"],"comment":"(adj) noisy"},
	{"question":"騒ぎ","answers":["さわぎ"],"comment":"(n,n-suf) uproar/disturbance"},
	{"question":"騒ぐ","answers":["さわぐ"],"comment":"(v5g) to make noise/to clamor/to be excited/to be alarmed/to kick up a fuss/to make merry/to be annoying/to be troublesome/to make a noise"},
	{"question":"騒動","answers":["そうどう"],"comment":"(n) strife/riot/rebellion"},
	{"question":"騒音","answers":["そうおん"],"comment":"(n) noise"},
	{"question":"驚かす","answers":["おどろかす"],"comment":"(v5s) to surprise/to frighten/to create a stir"},
	{"question":"驚き","answers":["おどろき"],"comment":"(n) surprise/astonishment/wonder"},
	{"question":"驚く","answers":["おどろく"],"comment":"(v5k) to be surprised/to be astonished"},
	{"question":"驚異","answers":["きょうい"],"comment":"(n) wonder/miracle"},
	{"question":"骨","answers":["ほね"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) bone"},
	{"question":"骨折","answers":["こっせつ"],"comment":"(n) bone fracture"},
	{"question":"骨董品","answers":["こっとうひん"],"comment":"(n) curio"},
	{"question":"高い","answers":["たかい"],"comment":"(adj) tall/high/expensive"},
	{"question":"高まる","answers":["たかまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to rise/to swell/to be promoted"},
	{"question":"高める","answers":["たかめる"],"comment":"(v1) to raise/to lift/to boost"},
	{"question":"高価","answers":["こうか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) high price"},
	{"question":"高原","answers":["こうげん"],"comment":"(n) tableland/plateau"},
	{"question":"高尚","answers":["こうしょう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) high/noble/refined/advanced"},
	{"question":"高層","answers":["こうそう"],"comment":"(n) upper"},
	{"question":"高度","answers":["こうど"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) altitude/height/advanced"},
	{"question":"高校","answers":["こうこう"],"comment":"(n) senior high school"},
	{"question":"高校生","answers":["こうこうせい"],"comment":"(n) senior high school student"},
	{"question":"高等","answers":["こうとう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) high class/high grade"},
	{"question":"高等学校","answers":["こうとうがっこう"],"comment":"senior high school"},
	{"question":"高級","answers":["こうきゅう"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) high class/high grade"},
	{"question":"高速","answers":["こうそく"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) high speed/high gear"},
	{"question":"髪","answers":["かみ"],"comment":"(n) hair"},
	{"question":"髪の毛","answers":["かみのけ"],"comment":"(n) hair (head)"},
	{"question":"髭","answers":["ひげ"],"comment":"(n) moustache/beard/whiskers"},
	{"question":"鬼","answers":["おに"],"comment":"(n) ogre/demon/'it' (i.e., in a game of tag)"},
	{"question":"魂","answers":["たましい"],"comment":"(n) soul/spirit"},
	{"question":"魅力","answers":["みりょく"],"comment":"(n) charm/fascination/glamour"},
	{"question":"魚","answers":["うお","さかな"],"comment":"(n) fish"},
	{"question":"鮮やか","answers":["あざやか"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) vivid/clear/brilliant"},
	{"question":"鳥","answers":["とり"],"comment":"(n) bird/fowl/poultry"},
	{"question":"鳥居","answers":["とりい"],"comment":"(n) torii (Shinto shrine archway)"},
	{"question":"鳥肉","answers":["とりにく"],"comment":"(n) chicken meat"},
	{"question":"鳴く","answers":["なく"],"comment":"(v5k) to bark/to purr/to make sound (animal)"},
	{"question":"鳴らす","answers":["ならす"],"comment":"(v5s,vt) to ring/to sound/to chime/to beat/to snort (nose)"},
	{"question":"鳴る","answers":["なる"],"comment":"(v5r) to sound/to ring/to resound/to echo/to roar/to rumble"},
	{"question":"麓","answers":["ふもと"],"comment":"(n) the foot/the bottom/the base (of a mountain)"},
	{"question":"麻","answers":["あさ"],"comment":"(n) flax/linen/hemp"},
	{"question":"麻痺","answers":["まひ"],"comment":"(n) paralysis/palsy/numbness/stupor"},
	{"question":"麻酔","answers":["ますい"],"comment":"(n) anaesthesia"},
	{"question":"黄色","answers":["きいろ"],"comment":"(adj-na,n) yellow"},
	{"question":"黄色い","answers":["きいろい"],"comment":"(adj) yellow"},
	{"question":"黄金","answers":["おうごん"],"comment":"(adj-no,n) gold"},
	{"question":"黒","answers":["くろ"],"comment":"(n) (1) black/(2) dark"},
	{"question":"黒い","answers":["くろい"],"comment":"(adj) (1) black/(2) dark"},
	{"question":"黒字","answers":["くろじ"],"comment":"(n) balance (figure) in the black"},
	{"question":"黒板","answers":["こくばん"],"comment":"(n) blackboard"},
	{"question":"黙る","answers":["だまる"],"comment":"(v5r) to be silent"},
	{"question":"黴菌","answers":["ばいきん"],"comment":"(n) bacteria/germ(s)"},
	{"question":"鼠","answers":["ねずみ"],"comment":"(n) (1) mouse/rat/(2) dark gray/slate color"},
	{"question":"鼻","answers":["はな"],"comment":"(n) nose"}
]
}
